<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Walt Disney World</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Walt+Disney+World</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Walt Disney World</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Walt+Disney+World</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Walt Disney World - WDWMAGIC</title><link>https://forums.wdwmagic.com/categories/walt-disney-world.3/</link><description>Walt Disney World WDW Parks News, Rumors and Current Events Latest news, rumors, and events at Walt Disney World, including new attractions, park changes, and upcoming projects.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 19:48:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WDW Parks News, Rumors and Current Events | WDWMAGIC - Unofficial Walt ...</title><link>https://forums.wdwmagic.com/forums/wdw-parks-news-rumors-and-current-events.4/</link><description>Latest news, rumors, and events at Walt Disney World, including new attractions, park changes, and upcoming projects.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 16:06:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WDW Parks General Discussion | WDWMAGIC - Unofficial Walt Disney World ...</title><link>https://forums.wdwmagic.com/forums/wdw-parks-general-discussion.5/</link><description>Stay up to date with the latest Disney news, photos, and discussions right from your iPhone. The app is free to download and gives you quick access to news articles, forums, photo galleries, park hours, weather and Lightning Lane pricing.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 02:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Walt Disney World 2026: All New Attractions, Festivals, and Events in ...</title><link>https://forums.wdwmagic.com/threads/walt-disney-world-2026-all-new-attractions-festivals-and-events-in-one-guide.987284/</link><description>Free Disney Water Park admission on arrival day returns for Disney Resort hotel guests. Disney H2O Glow After Hours returns to Typhoon Lagoon. Banana Ball at ESPN Wide World of Sports: May 29-30. Bluey and Bingo meet-and-play experience opens at Conservation Station in Disney's Animal Kingdom.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 00:42:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>NEWS HUB - Walt Disney World Ride Wait Times – Morning, Afternoon ...</title><link>https://forums.wdwmagic.com/threads/walt-disney-world-ride-wait-times-%E2%80%93-morning-afternoon-evening-stats.985625/</link><description>Stay up to date with the latest wait times across Walt Disney World. This thread will be updated five times daily with reports on wait times from park open.. 10 am Update: Wait times from park open to 10am 1 pm Update: Wait times from 10am to 1pm 5 pm Update: Wait times from 1pm to 5pm 10 pm...</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WDWMAGIC - Unofficial Walt Disney World discussion forums</title><link>https://forums.wdwmagic.com/</link><description>Walt Disney World WDW Parks News, Rumors and Current Events Latest news, rumors, and events at Walt Disney World, including new attractions, park changes, and upcoming projects.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 01:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>DIS Disney Discussion Forums - DISboards.com</title><link>https://www.disboards.com/</link><description>Disney Discussion Forums and Message Boards - DISboards is the ultimate Disney planning community and resource for Disney World, Disney Cruise Line and Disney Vacations, including news, rumors, park hours, theme park descriptions and strategies.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Unofficial Walt Disney World discussion forums - WDWMAGIC</title><link>https://forums.wdwmagic.com/whats-new/</link><description>Stay up to date with the latest Disney news, photos, and discussions right from your iPhone. The app is free to download and gives you quick access to news articles, forums, photo galleries, park hours, weather and Lightning Lane pricing.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>News - ABC's 2025 Disney Parks Holiday Specials at Walt Disney World</title><link>https://forums.wdwmagic.com/threads/abcs-2025-disney-parks-holiday-specials-at-walt-disney-world.986957/</link><description>Disney’s Emmy Award-winning annual celebration returns Christmas morning with magical star-studded performances from Walt Disney World Resort in Florida; Disneyland Resort in California and Aulani, a Disney Resort &amp; Spa in Ko Olina, Hawaiʻi.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:48:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mirror Walt Disney World 3.0 – The Definitive Version</title><link>https://forums.wdwmagic.com/threads/mirror-walt-disney-world-3-0-%E2%80%93-the-definitive-version.979095/</link><description>Mirror Walt Disney World 3.0 The Definitive Version Last year, I started a project that I think is the favorite of all the projects I’ve done across ten years of being part of the online Armchair Imagineering community: Mirror Walt Disney World.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
