<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: JD Miller</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=JD+Miller</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>JD Miller</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=JD+Miller</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>JD Sports: Sneakers, Shoes &amp; Apparel</title><link>https://www.jdsports.com/</link><description>JD Sports is your destination for must-have sneakers, sportswear and apparel from top brands like Nike, Jordan, adidas, New Balance, ASICS and more.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:27:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>京东 (JD.COM)-正品低价、品质保障、配送及时、轻松购物！</title><link>https://www.jd.com/?country=USA</link><description>京东JD.COM-专业的综合网上购物商城，为您提供正品低价的购物选择、优质便捷的服务体验。 商品来自全球数十万品牌商家，囊括家电、手机、电脑、服装、居家、母婴、美妆、个护、食品、生鲜等丰富品类，满足各种购物需求。</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 11:24:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>John Deere US | Products &amp; Services Information</title><link>https://www.deere.com/en/index.html</link><description>Explore agricultural, construction, forestry machinery, technology, services and more on the official John Deere website. Find a dealer in your area or purchase online.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>JD.com, Inc. (JD) Stock Price, News, Quote &amp; History - Yahoo Finance</title><link>https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/JD/</link><description>Find the latest JD.com, Inc. (JD) stock quote, history, news and other vital information to help you with your stock trading and investing.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:58:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>JD.com, Inc.</title><link>https://corporate.jd.com/ourBusiness</link><description>JD.com is the largest retailer in China, a member of the NASDAQ100 and a Fortune Global 500 company.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>JD Sports Fashion - Our brands - JD</title><link>https://www.jdplc.com/our-brands/jd/default.aspx</link><description>JD is a sports fashion, multibrand, multichannel retailer of sports and casual wear, combining globally recognised and emerging brands with strong private labels to provide an elevated consumer experience.</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:48:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Explore John Deere</title><link>https://about.deere.com/en-us/explore-john-deere/</link><description>Explore the John Deere Historic Site, where it all began, enjoy interactive and immersive experiences at the John Deere Pavilion, or get a look at classic machines and rare John Deere artifacts at the John Deere Tractor &amp; Engine Museum.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 22:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Men's Sneakers, Sportswear &amp; Accessories | JD Sports</title><link>https://www.jdsports.com/mens</link><description>Shop JD Sports for men's sneakers, sportswear and accessories from today's hottest brands like Nike, Jordan, adidas, New Balance, ASICS and more.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 22:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>JD Sports Global</title><link>https://www.global.jdsports.com/</link><description>JD Sports is the leading sneaker and sport fashion retailer. With many limited edition and exclusive design from adidas Originals and Nike.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Shop.Deere.com - John Deere</title><link>https://shop.deere.com/us/</link><description>Save 10% off on all StrongBox™ batteries and select battery accessories. Offer Valid: February 1, 2026 through March 31, 2026. Get the right tools for the right job.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 19:51:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
