<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Blarney Castle</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Blarney+Castle</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Blarney Castle</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Blarney+Castle</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Blarney - Aran Gifts from Ireland | Irish Crystal</title><link>https://www.blarney.com/</link><description>Blarney Woollen Mills is more than just a destination—it’s a legacy stitched into the very fabric of Ireland. Established in 1823 as a working woollen mill, it once echoed with the rhythm of spinning wheels and the soft rustle of woven dreams.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BLARNEY Definition &amp; Meaning - Merriam-Webster</title><link>https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/blarney</link><description>The meaning of BLARNEY is skillful flattery : blandishment. How to use blarney in a sentence.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blarney - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blarney</link><description>By kissing the Blarney Stone at Blarney Castle, it is claimed that one can receive the "Gift of the Gab" (eloquence, or skill at flattery or persuasion). The legend has several suggested roots, involving members of the MacCarthy dynasty – builders and original owners of Blarney Castle.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 07:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Visit Blarney Castle – home of the famous Blarney Stone ...</title><link>https://www.ireland.com/en-us/things-to-do/attractions/blarney-castle-blarney-stone/</link><description>One of the most famous castles on the island, Blarney is a romantic partial ruin set in glorious countryside. Built on the site of a 10th century wooden structure, the castle grounds are filled with wooded hollows, strange rock formations and a glistening flowing river.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:53:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Family Friendly Holiday | World-Famous | Blarney Castle</title><link>https://blarneycastle.ie/</link><description>Built nearly six hundred years ago by one of Ireland’s greatest chieftans, Cormac MacCarthy, and has been attracting attention ever since. Over the last few hundred years, millions have flocked to Blarney making it a world landmark and one of Ireland’s greatest treasures.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:27:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BLARNEY Definition &amp; Meaning | Dictionary.com</title><link>https://www.dictionary.com/browse/blarney</link><description>BLARNEY definition: flattering or wheedling talk; cajolery. See examples of blarney used in a sentence.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 03:56:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>15 Fun Things To Do In Blarney, Ireland (For 2025)</title><link>https://irelandtravelguides.com/things-to-do-in-blarney-ireland/</link><description>Blarney is a beautiful small town located 8-km north west of Cork which is a good side trip from the city and 260-km southwest of Dublin. Due to its historic past, Blarney is a popular Irish tourist destination.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blarney Stone, Shamrock, Texas - Roadside America</title><link>https://www.roadsideamerica.com/story/2228</link><description>This genuine chunk from the ruins of Blarney Castle was accidentally knocked off of the original Stone -- at least according to the Shamrock official who brought it here in 1959.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 09:19:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blarney | Irish Village, Castle &amp; Legend | Britannica</title><link>https://www.britannica.com/place/Blarney-Ireland</link><description>Blarney, village, County Cork, Ireland, 5 miles (8 km) northwest of Cork city, famous for Blarney Castle (c. 1446). Below the battlements on the southern wall of the castle is the Blarney Stone, reputed to confer eloquence on those who kiss it; this feat can be achieved only by hanging head downward.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 03:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blarney Stone - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blarney_Stone</link><description>The word blarney has come to mean "clever, flattering, or coaxing talk". Irish politician John O'Connor Power defined it this way: "Blarney is something more than mere flattery.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
