<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Six Flags Over Georgia</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Six+Flags+Over+Georgia</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Six Flags Over Georgia</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Six+Flags+Over+Georgia</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Six Flags Over Georgia | Six Flags Over Georgia</title><link>https://www.sixflags.com/overgeorgia</link><description>If you’re looking for things to do near Atlanta, Six Flags Over Georgia, located in Austell, Georgia, is the must-do destination. It's home to over 45 rides, from the family-friendly Rockin' Tug to the adrenaline-pumping roller coasters like Dare Devil Dive and The Great American Scream Machine.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Flags Over Georgia - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Six_Flags_Over_Georgia</link><description>Six Flags Over Georgia is a 290-acre (1.2 km 2) amusement park in Mableton, Georgia, United States. Opened in 1967, it is the second park in the Six Flags chain following the original Six Flags Over Texas, which opened in 1961.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 07:36:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Flags Over Georgia (2026) - Tripadvisor</title><link>https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attraction_Review-g29213-d103497-Reviews-Six_Flags_Over_Georgia-Austell_Georgia.html</link><description>Six Flags Over Georgia is Atlanta’s largest, most exciting theme park! If your family is looking for things to do in Atlanta, Georgia, you’ve come to the right place.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 22:38:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Flags Over Georgia | Tickets, Rides, Hours &amp; Water Park ...</title><link>https://topthemeparks.com/park/six-flags-over-georgia/</link><description>Located just west of Atlanta in Austell, Georgia, Six Flags Over Georgia combines intense roller coasters, kid-friendly rides, and a full Hurricane Harbor water park — all in a scenic setting surrounded by trees and Southern charm.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 21:19:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Flags Over Georgia - Discover Atlanta</title><link>https://discoveratlanta.com/things-to-do/six-flags/</link><description>As the largest regional theme park in the Southeast, Six Flags Over Georgia is home to more than 40 rides including 12 roller coasters, three water rides and thrill rides.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Flags Over Georgia opening 2026 dates, tickets, job opportunities</title><link>https://www.onlineathens.com/story/news/2026/02/10/six-flags-over-georgia-opening-2026-dates-tickets-job-opportunities/88606191007/</link><description>Six Flags Over Georgia is the largest regional theme park in the southeast with more than 40 rides including 12 roller coasters, according to Discover Atlanta.</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:46:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Flags Over Georgia: Everything You Need To Know Before You Go</title><link>https://atlantafi.com/six-flags-georgia-reopening/</link><description>Six Flags Over Georgia has reopened for 2021! Here's everything you need to know from ticket costs to cool rides to try at the Austell park.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 06:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Flags Over Georgia</title><link>https://exploregeorgia.org/austell/entertainment/theme-parks/six-flags-over-georgia</link><description>The largest regional theme park in the Southeast, featuring 11 heart-pounding coasters, the all-new Hurricane Harbor water park included with park admission, interactive children's sections and water rides to beat the summer heat. Take on the 20-story Goliath hyper coaster, SkyScreame - a 24-story extreme swing ride - or the world's first hybrid zero gravity slide at Hurricane Harbor, opening ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 23:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Flags Over Georgia</title><link>https://www.sixflags.com/overgeorgia/tickets?pass=Daily-Tickets</link><description>Find the best deals on amusement park tickets to Six Flags Over Georgia. Buy tickets online and save on daily admission to the park!</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 21:27:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Our Events | Six Flags Over Georgia</title><link>https://www.sixflags.com/overgeorgia/events</link><description>Park Info Calendar &amp; Hours Explore Cobb &amp; Lodging Frequently Asked Questions Lost &amp; Found Accessibility Code of Conduct Jobs Blogs Contact Us Community Media Center Get The App Privacy Policy | Do Not Sell or Share My Information | Terms of Use | Accessibility | Jobs © 2026 Six Flags Entertainment Corporation</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 13:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
