<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Budapest</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Budapest</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Budapest</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Budapest</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Living in Budapest guide: Everything you need to know to move and ...</title><link>https://www.expat.com/en/guide/europe/hungary/budapest/</link><description>The living in Budapest guide, written by expats for expatriates, will help you to settle down in Budapest. By expatriates, for expatriates. Find all the info you need to settle overseas.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:39:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Guide de l'expatrié à Budapest : l'essentiel à savoir pour votre ...</title><link>https://www.expat.com/fr/guide/europe/hongrie/budapest/</link><description>Le guide de l'expatrié à Budapest, écrit par des expatriés pour des expatriés, vous aidera à vous installer à Budapest. Retrouvez toutes les informations nécessaires pour vous installer à l'international.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BUDAPEST | Tervek és építkezések / Projects and...</title><link>https://www.skyscrapercity.com/threads/budapest-tervek-%C3%A9s-%C3%A9p%C3%ADtkez%C3%A9sek-projects-and-construction-updates.414682/</link><description>Budapest, 1138 Népfürdő utca 27. The Company expects to construct three office towers just off of Váci út, 100 metres from the Danube River and near the NewAge Business Center. The property is situated on approximately 11,250 square metres of land and is expected to have 36,298 square metres of lettable office space and underground parking.</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:56:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BUDAPEST | Tervek és építkezések / Projects and...</title><link>https://www.skyscrapercity.com/threads/budapest-tervek-%C3%A9s-%C3%A9p%C3%ADtkez%C3%A9sek-projects-and-construction-updates.414682/page-1227</link><description>A truly global community dedicated to skyscrapers, cities, urban development, and the metropolitan environment. Join us to share news, views and fun about architecture, construction, transport, skylines, and much more! Home Forums European Forums Euroscrapers Hungary Budapest</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 07:35:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Budapest] Budai Várnegyed | Buda Castle District Developments</title><link>https://www.skyscrapercity.com/threads/budapest-budai-v%C3%A1rnegyed-buda-castle-district-developments.704310/page-2186</link><description>Rákerestem Bojár Ivánra, csak egy 2016-os beszélgetést találtam, ahol ott volt Csomay is. Ennek alapján az új beszélgetés jegyzőkönyve nagyjából előre megírható: borzalom az egész, modern építészetet a Várba, meg tessék megbecsülni a cuclizmus épített hagyatékát is, az is a történelem része. Mindezt 3990-ért, támogatóknak 9990.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 09:41:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Budapest - SkyscraperCity Forum</title><link>https://www.skyscrapercity.com/forums/budapest.2154/</link><description>Budapest úthálózata, fővárosi és kerületi fejlesztések / Road network, City and District developments elbong Feb 26, 2017 42 43 44 2K 740K Jan 20, 2026 by zsimi80</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 12:43:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Budapest] Budai Várnegyed | Buda Castle District Developments</title><link>https://www.skyscrapercity.com/threads/budapest-budai-v%C3%A1rnegyed-buda-castle-district-developments.704310/</link><description>[Budapest] Budai Várnegyed | Buda Castle District Developments budapest 31 reading Jump to Latest 12M views 44K replies 421 participants last post by csikisanyi 51m ago</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 07:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Appartements à louer à Budapest - Expat.com</title><link>https://www.expat.com/fr/immobilier/europe/hongrie/budapest/appartement-a-louer.html</link><description>Trouvez un appartement à louer à Budapest. Parcourez les petites annonces de location d'appartements à Budapest et publiez la vôtre gratuitement.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 20:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>[Budapest] Budai Várnegyed | Buda Castle District Developments</title><link>https://www.skyscrapercity.com/threads/budapest-budai-v%C3%A1rnegyed-buda-castle-district-developments.704310/page-2196</link><description>A Budapest és Magyarország rekonstrukciós ötlettára fb oldalamon írtam is erről. Amíg Lázár a miniszter, addig nem lesz Közlekedési Múzeum újjáépítés a ligetben. Sajnos! De figyelve a mai híreket, hajszálnyira vagyunk a nagy közel keleti háborútól,amiből könnyen világháború lehet.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 10:44:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Flats for rent in Budapest - Expat.com</title><link>https://www.expat.com/en/housing/europe/hungary/budapest/flats-for-rent.html</link><description>Flats for rent in Budapest, apartment rentals in Budapest. Post your free ad here if you are offering flats for rent.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 16:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
