<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Brazil</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Brazil</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Brazil</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Brazil</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Brazil - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brazil</link><description>Brazil encompasses a wide range of tropical and subtropical landscapes, as well as wetlands, savannas, plateaus, and low mountains. It contains most of the Amazon basin, including the world's largest river system and most extensive virgin tropical forest.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 09:58:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazil | History, Map, Culture, Population, &amp; Facts | Britannica</title><link>https://www.britannica.com/place/Brazil</link><description>Brazil, country of South America that occupies half the continent’s landmass. It is the fifth largest and fifth most-populous country in the world. Brazil contains most of the Amazon River basin, which has the world’s largest river system and the world’s most-extensive virgin rainforest.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 09:13:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazil Maps &amp; Facts - World Atlas</title><link>https://www.worldatlas.com/maps/brazil</link><description>Brazil is a large country located in the central-eastern part of South America, bordering the Atlantic Ocean. It occupies almost half of the continent's landmass and is dissected by both the Equator and the Tropic of Capricorn.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 23:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazil | Culture, Facts &amp; Travel | - CountryReports</title><link>https://www.countryreports.org/country/Brazil.htm</link><description>Brazil in depth country profile. Unique hard to find content on Brazil. Includes customs, culture, history, geography, economy current events, photos, video, and more.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 03:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazil - Country Profile - South America - Nations Online Project</title><link>https://www.nationsonline.org/oneworld/brazil.htm</link><description>Brazil has a population of more than 212 million people (in 2024), making it the seventh most populous country in the world and the most populous nation in South America. The national capital is Brasília, a planned city atop the Brazilian highlands.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 03:39:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazil - New World Encyclopedia</title><link>https://www.newworldencyclopedia.org/entry/Brazil</link><description>Brazil, officially the Federative Republic of Brazil, is the largest country in South America. It is the world's fifth-largest country by area, the fifth most populous, and the fourth most populous democracy in the world.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The essential guide to visiting Brazil | National Geographic</title><link>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/travel/article/brazil-essential-travel-guide</link><description>From Rio de Janeiro’s iconic Ipanema Beach to the jaguar-filled Pantanal to the Amazon rainforest, there’s no shortage of thrilling places to visit in Brazil. Here’s an essential guide to explore...</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 11:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>About Brazil – Visit Brasil</title><link>https://visitbrasil.com/en/home/about-brazil/</link><description>Haven’t decided yet? Let us inspire you even more. © 2026 All Rights Reserved Developed by in.Pacto Comunicação.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:44:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazil - Wikitravel</title><link>https://wikitravel.org/en/Brazil</link><description>Brazil [1] (Portuguese: Brasil) is the largest country in South America and fifth largest in the world. Famous for its football tradition and its annual Carnaval in Rio de Janeiro, Salvador, Recife and Olinda.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 09:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazil's first Winter Olympics gold is about much more than the medal</title><link>https://www.nbcnewyork.com/olympics/2026-milan-cortina/brazil-first-winter-olympics-gold-meaning/6462133/</link><description>Brazil's first Winter Olympics gold is about much more than the medal It was the first-ever medal at the Winter Games for any country in South America.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 01:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
