<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Peak District</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Peak+District</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Peak District</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Peak+District</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Rocky Mountain Region USFS Numbering - RadioReference.com Forums</title><link>https://forums.radioreference.com/threads/rocky-mountain-region-usfs-numbering.441304/</link><description>I promised this a long time ago and then didn't follow through. I just found a 2022 document showing all the forest and ranger district numbering. I was only asked to provide Colorado, but will include Wyoming, South Dakota, Nebraska and Kansas also. This will show the National Forest (NF) and...</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 10:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mesa PD Districts - RadioReference.com Forums</title><link>https://forums.radioreference.com/threads/mesa-pd-districts.308418/</link><description>I wasn't home yesterday to monitor any of the incident in Mesa, but I do log what channels I hear and on which sites, and Mesa FD 2 was being heard off the Thompson Peak site, and I'm in Southwest Tempe.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:35:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Echo Fox | Page 2 | RadioReference.com Forums</title><link>https://forums.radioreference.com/threads/echo-fox.494715/page-2</link><description>I was an engineer with GE during the peak of EF. Most in the office knew of name EF but not much more. Generally one technical individual (District Service Manager) had the need to know and the calls referred to him. EF repeaters were generally at AT&amp;T Long Lines microwave towers. Found out later that many Federal techs carried GE credentials and they had access into the high levels of the ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 02:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Yellowstone Frequencies - RadioReference.com Forums</title><link>https://forums.radioreference.com/threads/yellowstone-frequencies.104165/</link><description>165.5875 164.800 110.9 South areas repeater 172.500 172.500 103.5 Fire Cache 166.375 166.375 192.8 Lamar District There was a fair amount of P-25 activity. I did not have a capable scanner, but since I did not hear very much law enforcement in the analog mode, I assume they were the primary user. Click to expand...</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 18:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BLM Master List Of Station Locations - RadioReference.com Forums</title><link>https://forums.radioreference.com/threads/blm-master-list-of-station-locations.268603/</link><description>•Chimney Peak Fire Station (Interagency w/ USFS) Unnamed Type 4 engine •Kernville Fire Station (Interagency w/ USFS) DZ3183 •Midway Fire Station E3134 E3147 WT3191 •Metro Fire Station E3130 E3140 E3144 •South Fork Fire Station E3133 E3146 WT3192 DZ3182 ---California Desert District---</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 17:41:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>J codes for cities in Utah County - RadioReference.com Forums</title><link>https://forums.radioreference.com/threads/j-codes-for-cities-in-utah-county.206862/</link><description>The only glitches are Station 35 which is in Lindon as Orem (Station 31/3J) has the contract for Fire/EMS/Dispatch services to Lindon and Lone Peak Fire District (Station 181) which serves Alpine (18J), Highland (20J) and Cedar Hills (24J) but all use the Station 180/181 numeric.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 01:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Forest Service and Repeaters - RadioReference.com Forums</title><link>https://forums.radioreference.com/threads/forest-service-and-repeaters.413639/</link><description>The California Desert District of the BLM could have Rogers Peak in Death Valley National Park and Lyons Peak southeast of San Diego transmitting on the district net at the same time and only aircraft at a high elevation could hear both, so no repeater wars for nearly everyone.</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Washington Radio Discussion Forum - RadioReference.com Forums</title><link>https://forums.radioreference.com/forums/washington-radio-discussion-forum.62/</link><description>Forum for discussing Radio Information in the State of Washington.</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:44:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Inyo County Moving to Mobile Relay Associates NEXEDGE System?</title><link>https://forums.radioreference.com/threads/inyo-county-moving-to-mobile-relay-associates-nexedge-system.430370/</link><description>I came across an Inyo County Board of Supervisors agenda packet from the July 20, 2021 meeting. There is an agenda item that seems to suggest the Sheriff's Office is moving their primary operations over to the NXDN wide-area system owned/operated by Mobile Relay Associates. They will keep their...</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 14:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Wildland Dispatch Center - RadioReference.com Forums</title><link>https://forums.radioreference.com/threads/new-wildland-dispatch-center.408051/</link><description>14 Picket Peak * Service Net Repeater, all others have both Forest and Admin Nets. Ranger District Number/Unit Identifiers: 1 Smith River NRA/Gasquet RD (pronounced "gas key") 2 Orleans RD 3 Lower Trinity RD 4 Mad River 5 Redwood NP Units 9500 Hoopa BIA Humboldt-Toiyabe NF Carson #D1, Austin #D3 and Tonopah #D4 RD's Net 173.7750/165.7500 Carson ...</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 05:46:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
