<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Edinburgh</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Edinburgh</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Edinburgh</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Edinburgh</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Edinburgh - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edinburgh</link><description>Edinburgh[a] is the capital city of Scotland and one of its 32 council areas. It is located in southeast Scotland and is bounded to the north by the Firth of Forth and to the south by the Pentland Hills.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>11 Fascinating Things to Do in Edinburgh | VisitScotland</title><link>https://www.visitscotland.com/places-to-go/edinburgh/things-to-do</link><description>With hundreds of things to do in Edinburgh, find a range of fascinating sights and attractions. Including Edinburgh Castle, Lost Shore Surf Resort, and more!</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Official Guide to Edinburgh - Forever Edinburgh</title><link>https://edinburgh.org/</link><description>One of Edinburgh’s hidden gems, filled with colourful, stylish boutiques and much-loved pubs and bars. Discover lush parks, delightful shops and family-friendly markets in this charming neighbourhood. Home to Edinburgh’s oldest university, fascinating museums, cosy coffee shops and leafy spaces.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>18 things to know before traveling to Edinburgh - Lonely Planet</title><link>https://www.lonelyplanet.com/articles/things-to-know-before-traveling-to-edinburgh</link><description>Before you visit Edinburgh, find out when to go, what to pack, what kind of currency you'll need and more.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:13:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>25 Best Things to Do in Edinburgh, Scotland - U.S. News Travel</title><link>https://travel.usnews.com/Edinburgh_Scotland/Things_To_Do/</link><description>Whether you're in search of "Harry Potter" sites, Scotch whiskey, historic landmarks, or all of the above, these are the best things to do in Edinburgh, Scotland.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 23:56:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Edinburgh | Geography, History, Map, &amp; Points of Interest | Britannica</title><link>https://www.britannica.com/place/Edinburgh-Scotland</link><description>Edinburgh, capital city of Scotland, located in southeastern Scotland with its center near the southern shore of the Firth of Forth. A city of somber theatricality, it is a major center for finance, law, tourism, education, and cultural affairs.</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 09:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Edinburgh, Scotland: All You Must Know Before You Go (2026 ...</title><link>https://www.tripadvisor.com/Tourism-g186525-Edinburgh_Scotland-Vacations.html</link><description>Edinburgh is a phenomenally popular destination, with around 3.5 million people visiting every year. Even so, thanks to the city's complex history, topography, and layout, much of it stays well off the beaten path.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>20 Things to Do in EDINBURGH, Scotland | 1st timers guide!</title><link>https://visitscotland.travel/edinburgh-1st-timers-guide/</link><description>Edinburgh’s blend of history, culture, and natural beauty makes it unforgettable. Plan ahead for key attractions, wear comfortable shoes, and immerse yourself in the city’s unique spirit.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Edinburgh Attractions &amp; Places to Visit | VisitBritain</title><link>https://www.visitbritain.com/en/destinations/scotland/edinburgh</link><description>Planning a trip to Edinburgh? Explore Edinburgh's top attractions, things to do &amp; places to visit with VisitBritain. Discover why we love Edinburgh.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 07:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Edinburgh - Wikitravel</title><link>https://wikitravel.org/en/Edinburgh</link><description>Edinburgh (Gaelic: Dùn Èideann; [1]) is the capital of Scotland located in the Central Belt region of the country. With a population of approximately 450,000 (1 million in the city region), "Auld Reekie" (Edinburgh) manages to combine both ancient and modern in a uniquely Scottish atmosphere.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 21:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
