<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Rock of Cashel</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Rock+of+Cashel</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Rock of Cashel</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Rock+of+Cashel</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Rock of Cashel - Cashel</title><link>https://www.cashel.ie/rock-of-cashel/</link><description>Set on a dramatic outcrop of limestone in the Golden Vale, the Rock of Cashel, iconic in its historic significance, possesses the most impressive cluster of medieval buildings in Ireland.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cashel | Rock of Cashel &amp; Cashel Heritage Centre &amp; Tourist Information</title><link>https://www.cashel.ie/</link><description>The Rock of Cashel is one of Ireland’s most spectacular archaeological sites, a prominent green hill, banded with limestone outcrops, rising from a grassy plain and bristling with ancient fortifications.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 22:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Explore Archives - Cashel</title><link>https://www.cashel.ie/category/explore/</link><description>Set on a dramatic outcrop of limestone in the Golden Vale, the Rock of Cashel, iconic in its historic significance, possesses the most impressive cluster of medieval buildings in Ireland.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 09:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Map - Cashel</title><link>https://www.cashel.ie/fun-map/</link><description>Our mission is to promote and publicize the many wonders that exist in Cashel beyond the iconic Rock of Cashel. This website is part of our efforts to ensure that people learn about the history, attractions and hidden gems of this wonderful world-famous location.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 14:48:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cashel Walking Trails</title><link>https://www.cashel.ie/cashel-walking-trails/</link><description>From historic Ardmore in Co Waterford to the celebrated Rock of Cashel in Co. Tipperary. The route uses roads, tracks and paths, passing the ruins of many remarkable ecclesiastical sites, as well as holy wells and assorted prehistoric remains.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 09:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cashel Town Trail</title><link>https://www.cashel.ie/cashel-town-trail/</link><description>The Rock of Cashel (Carraig Phádraig), more formally St. Patrick’s Rock, it is also known as Cashel of the Kings. Reputedly the site of the conversion of Aenghus the King of Munster by St. Patrick in the 5th century AD.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 11:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Brú Ború - Cashel</title><link>https://www.cashel.ie/bru-boru/</link><description>The subterranean chambers, seven metres underground at the base of the famous Rock of Cashel, echo to the story of Ireland from ancient times to the present day. Through the passage of time, the visitor’s journey is marked by milestones of achievement, conflict and renewal.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tourism and History Archives - Cashel</title><link>https://www.cashel.ie/category/explore/tourism-and-history/</link><description>Set on a dramatic outcrop of limestone in the Golden Vale, the Rock of Cashel, iconic in its historic significance, possesses the most impressive cluster of medieval buildings in Ireland.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 19:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Video Tour - Cashel</title><link>https://www.cashel.ie/video-tour/</link><description>Video Tour This video takes you on a journey of Cashel. Cashel is home to the iconic Rock of Cashel. One of the most spectacular tourist attractions in Ireland and one of the most visited.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hore Abbey - Cashel</title><link>https://www.cashel.ie/hore-abbey/</link><description>Hore Abbey (also Hoare Abbey, sometimes known as St.Mary’s) is a ruined Cistercian monastery near the Rock of Cashel. ‘Hore’ is thought to derive from ‘iubhair’ – yew tree.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 08:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
