<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Caldicot Castle</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Caldicot+Castle</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Caldicot Castle</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Caldicot+Castle</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Caldicot - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caldicot</link><description>Caldicot (Welsh: Cil-y-coed) is a market town and community in Monmouthshire, Wales. The town is located between Chepstow and the city of Newport. The site adjoins the Caldicot Levels, on the north side of the Severn Estuary. The population of the built-up area was around 11,000.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Caldicot Castle and Country Park | VisitWales</title><link>https://www.visitwales.com/attraction/castle/caldicot-castle-and-country-park-532221</link><description>Visit Caldicot Castle in its beautiful setting of tranquil gardens and a wooded country park. Founded by the Normans, developed in royal hands as a stronghold in the Middle Ages and restored as a Victorian family home, the castle has a romantic and colourful history.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Caldicot Castle And Country Park (2026) - Tripadvisor</title><link>https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attraction_Review-g1514172-d218583-Reviews-Caldicot_Castle_And_Country_Park-Caldicot_Monmouthshire_South_Wales_Wales.html</link><description>Caldicot Castle’s impressive structure is surrounded by an idyllic 55 acre Country Park. You will be able to travel through time and discover the home of Welsh castle life, from medieval times to the twentieth century.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 16:26:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Caldicot – Travel guide at Wikivoyage</title><link>https://en.wikivoyage.org/wiki/Caldicot</link><description>Caldicot (Welsh: Cil-y-coed) is a small town in Monmouthshire. It is a pleasant small town with several local historic attractions. This Welsh border town is home to a significant, complete castle and country park with free access to the public, a large Roman villa with remains of municipal buildings and a temple in Caerwent.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 23:52:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Caldicot Travel Guide: Top 10 Must-Visit Tourist Places</title><link>https://touristplaces.guide/caldicot-travel-guide-top-10-must-visit-tourist-places/</link><description>Caldicot is especially famous for its well-preserved historic castle, which dates back to the 11th century. The castle not only showcases remarkable medieval architecture but also hosts various events throughout the year, attracting history buffs and families alike.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:53:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Caldicot Castle: A Hidden Gem in the Monmouthshire Countryside</title><link>https://www.medievalchronicles.com/medieval-europe/medieval-wales/top-10-castles-in-wales/caldicot-castle-a-hidden-gem-in-the-monmouthshire-countryside/</link><description>Caldicot Castle is located in the town of Caldicot, Monmouthshire, Wales. Its idyllic setting provides a serene escape for history enthusiasts and nature lovers alike.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Caldicot - Visit Monmouthshire</title><link>https://www.visitmonmouthshire.com/explore/caldicot</link><description>Caldicot is one of four main towns in Monmouthshire. Located near the coast between the two bridges over the river Severn, its name is derived from the Old English calde meaning 'cold' and cot meaning 'cottage / shelter'. Caldicot has always been an important transport point.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 20:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>About Caldicot - Caldicot Town Council</title><link>http://www.caldicottc.org.uk/About_Caldicot_6953.aspx</link><description>The village was fast becoming a town. The growth of the community was furthered by the opening of the Severn Bridge in 1966, strengthening the ties between Caldicot and the Bristol region which have always been so important to the wellbeing of the area.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Caldicot Castle</title><link>http://www.castlewales.com/caldicot.html</link><description>But however you travel around Caldicot Castle, you will find yourself transported back to the Middle Ages, and tracing the development of castle-building in Southeastern Wales. C aldicot Castle was built on a site that had long been recognized for its strategic value.</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 06:32:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Caldicot Map - Monmouthshire, Wales, UK - Mapcarta</title><link>https://mapcarta.com/Caldicot</link><description>Caldicot Castle is an extensive stone medieval castle in the town of Caldicot, Monmouthshire, in southeast Wales, built near the site of Harold Godwinson's former Saxon castle by the Norman earls of Hereford from about 1100.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 12:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
