<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Split Croatia Travel</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Split+Croatia+Travel</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Split Croatia Travel</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Split+Croatia+Travel</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>verbs - The past participle of "split": "split" or "splitted ...</title><link>https://english.stackexchange.com/questions/467873/the-past-participle-of-split-split-or-splitted</link><description>The past tense, and past participle of "split" is "split". I don't think that "splitted" is grammatical, though I dare say it gets used.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 20:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>"Split in" vs "split into" - English Language &amp; Usage Stack Exchange</title><link>https://english.stackexchange.com/questions/75153/split-in-vs-split-into</link><description>In the sentence I have a bibliography page which I'd like to split in/into sections which would you rather use: split in or split into? Why?</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 15:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What are the differences between "crack", "slit", "crevice", "split ...</title><link>https://english.stackexchange.com/questions/31116/what-are-the-differences-between-crack-slit-crevice-split-and-cleft</link><description>For the most part, the words are interchangeable. Distinguishing between multiple examples of such things can be aided by their individual connotations: crack a line on the surface of something along which it has split without breaking into separate parts A crack tends to be a visible flaw that can splinter or spider into larger cracks with many smaller, attached cracks. The defining point of ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 15:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ITEM 1: 202512020037 – Pinnacle Land Holdings - Lot Split</title><link>https://www.grovecityohio.gov/DocumentCenter/View/3539/202512020037_StaffReport_Pinnacle-Lands-Holding_Lot-Split</link><description>The applicant is requesting approval to split +/- 0.289 acres from a +/- 8.889 acre tract within the Pinnacle development located approximately 500 feet east of the intersection of Pinnacle Club Drive and Pinnacle Woods Drive.</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:33:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>"The splits" vs "a split" - English Language &amp; Usage Stack Exchange</title><link>https://english.stackexchange.com/questions/9856/the-splits-vs-a-split</link><description>The problem with this is that unlike the runs or scissors or the heebie-jeebies or any other example I can think of, The Splits has multiple forms of use that necessitate a singular form. No one is ever concerned about having "a run" in regard to making it to the toilet. The Splits starts out sounding wrong but then quickly devolves into being un-useable when you have to describe a particular ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 23:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>"Split in half" vs. "split in two" — which one is correct?</title><link>https://english.stackexchange.com/questions/108335/split-in-half-vs-split-in-two-which-one-is-correct</link><description>Does the "in" imply multiplication, in which case split in half is correct, or is it division? It sounds like the latter to me, but I've heard it used both ways.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 01:32:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Courtyards at Harris Farm Lot Split 22.946ac - Lot Split</title><link>https://www.grovecityohio.gov/594/Courtyards-at-Harris-Farm-Lot-Split-2294</link><description>LOT SPLIT Project ID: 202504280018 This proposal is a Lot Split to split +/- 22.946-acres from a +/-99.478-acre tract on London Groveport Road. Supplemental Materials (PDF) Staff Report (PDF) Planner in Charge: Terry Barr, AICP or 614-277-3022</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Are split infinitives grammatically incorrect, or are they valid ...</title><link>https://english.stackexchange.com/questions/2117/are-split-infinitives-grammatically-incorrect-or-are-they-valid-constructs</link><description>Split infinitives involve the to-infinitive specifically. The "to" not a "preposition"; it is a infinitive marker. Lastly, I found your arguments about "wanna" &amp; "gonna" unconvincing and irrelevant because these words are informal and the argument about split infinitives is most certainly about prescriptivism.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 21:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>www.grovecityohio.gov</title><link>https://www.grovecityohio.gov/DocumentCenter/View/3477/202512020037_SupplementalMaterial_Pinnacle-Lands-Holding_Lot-Split</link><description>Pinnacle Land Holdings This application proposed to split out a 60.00’ x 209.93’ out of Franklin County Parcel Identification Number 040015392 - - 00. This property will then be combined with Franklin County Parcel Identification Number 040 - 013754- 00 per the requirements outlined by Brian Younkin in a letter addressed to Steve and Elizabeth</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:19:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>PROJECT / PROPERTY INFORMATION</title><link>https://www.grovecityohio.gov/DocumentCenter/View/184/Lot-Split-Application-PDF</link><description>Lot Split applications are approved by Planning Commission and do not require City Council approval. Certificate of Appropriateness, Development Plan, and Preliminary Development Plan applications are approved by Resolution and require one reading by City Council. two readings by City Council. A 30 day effective per</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 20:35:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
