<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Krakow</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Krakow</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Krakow</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Krakow</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Kraków - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Krak%C3%B3w</link><description>Kraków was the official capital of Poland until 1596 [13] and has traditionally been one of the leading centres of Polish academic, cultural, and artistic life. Its Old Town was declared a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 1978, one of the world's first sites granted the status.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 14:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>25+ Best Things To Do In Kraków, Poland (2026 Guide)</title><link>https://visitkrakow.com/things-to-do-in-krakow/</link><description>From Auschwitz tours to the medieval Old Town, salt mines, and hidden gems – your complete 2026 travel guide with insider tips. Wawel Hill Royal Apartments. This page is full of suggestions for some of the most essential things to see and do in Kraków.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The 14 best things to do in Kraków - Lonely Planet</title><link>https://www.lonelyplanet.com/articles/top-things-to-do-in-krakow</link><description>Ready to plan your visit? These are the top things to do in Kraków, whether you're heading here for one day, a long weekend or for longer. Wawel Cathedral. S-F/Shutterstock. 1. Revel in the glory of the Wawel Royal Castle and Wawel Cathedral.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Krakow Bucket List: 25 Memorable Things to Do in Krakow</title><link>https://www.earthtrekkers.com/best-things-to-do-in-krakow-poland/</link><description>With its large market square, colorful streets, historic sites, and abundance of amazing, budget friendly restaurants, Krakow is a favorite stop for many people on their tour through Poland. We spent five days exploring Krakow and its surrounds, and here is our list of the best things to do in Krakow. 1. Main Market Square (Rynek Glówny)</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Krakow, Poland: All You Must Know Before You Go (2026 ...</title><link>https://www.tripadvisor.com/Tourism-g274772-Krakow_Lesser_Poland_Province_Southern_Poland-Vacations.html</link><description>For its stature, Krakow certainly packs a sightseeing punch, with landmark architecture, medieval palaces and hard-hitting museums. It’s also blessed with a well-priced shopping scene, a buzzing nightlife and the best of world cuisines.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 21:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Krakow | Former Polish Capital, Cultural Heritage, UNESCO ...</title><link>https://www.britannica.com/place/Krakow</link><description>Krakow is a city and the capital of Malopolskie province, southern Poland, lying on both sides of the upper Vistula River. One of the largest cities in Poland, it is known primarily for its grand historic architecture and cultural leadership; UNESCO designated its old town area a World Heritage site.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 09:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kraków - Things to do and travel guide</title><link>https://www.visitpolska.info/en/places-to-visit-poland/krakow/</link><description>Krakow, the former capital of Poland, is one of the oldest and most beautiful cities in the country. Its historical centre has been declared a UNESCO World Heritage Site and is Poland’s main cultural, artistic, university and tourist centre.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 02:51:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
