<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Goodrich Castle</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Goodrich+Castle</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Goodrich Castle</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Goodrich+Castle</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Goodrich Castle - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goodrich_Castle</link><description>Goodrich Castle is a Norman medieval castle ruin north of the village of Goodrich in Herefordshire, England, controlling a key location between Monmouth and Ross-on-Wye.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:33:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Goodrich Castle | English Heritage</title><link>https://www.english-heritage.org.uk/visit/places/goodrich-castle/</link><description>Enjoy this dreamy drone footage of Goodrich Castle and the beautiful surrounding countryside before you visit.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Goodrich Castle - History and Facts | History Hit</title><link>https://www.historyhit.com/locations/goodrich-castle/</link><description>Goodrich Castle in Herefordshire is one of the most picturesque medieval ruins in the UK. Standing at the peak of a scenic woodland hilltop, this Norman fortification has attracted tourists to view its ethereal remains since the 18th century.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 21:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Goodrich Castle (English Heritage) - Visit Herefordshire</title><link>https://www.visitherefordshire.co.uk/discover/goodrich-castle-english-heritage</link><description>Standing in open countryside above the River Wye, Goodrich is one of the finest and best-preserved of all English medieval fortresses. Discover the castle's fascinating history, climb the battlements for breathtaking views, see the famous 'Roaring Meg', and enjoy an action-packed day out for all ages.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Goodrich Castle: A Storied Fortress of the Welsh Marches</title><link>https://www.historytools.org/stories/goodrich-castle-a-storied-fortress-of-the-welsh-marches</link><description>Goodrich Castle, with its towering walls and turrets rising above the surrounding woodland, is a quintessential medieval fortress that has watched over the River Wye for nearly a millennium.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 23:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Goodrich Castle - Castle in Ross-On-Wye, Monmouth</title><link>https://www.visitmonmouthshire.com/things-to-do/goodrich-castle-p1504081</link><description>This magnificent red sandstone castle, with a 12th century keep standing three stories high and extensive remains from the 13th and 14th centuries, looks across the beautiful Wye Valley to Symonds Yat.</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 05:56:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Goodrich Castle | Get Tickets, Visitor Info | Castles History</title><link>https://crazyaboutcastles.com/english-castles/goodrich-castle/</link><description>Goodrich Castle is a Norman fortress in Herefordshire, England. The stone keep, which still stands, was erected around the 12th century. By the 13th century, the castle included luxury accommodations and numerous defences. Today, the ruins can be explored by booking a ticket through English Heritage. Parking.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:41:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Goodrich Castle | Historic Herefordshire Guide - Britain Express</title><link>https://www.britainexpress.com/counties/hereford/castles/goodrich.htm</link><description>Goodrich Castle is one of the finest examples of military architecture in England, located on a spur of land overlooking the River Wye, on the border with Wales. The castle is almost certainly named for Godric Mappestone (or Mappeson), who is mentioned in the Domesday Book as owning land in the area.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 20:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Goodrich Castle (2026) - All You MUST Know Before You Go (with Reviews)</title><link>https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attraction_Review-g2409515-d1008036-Reviews-Goodrich_Castle-Walford_Ross_on_Wye_Herefordshire_England.html</link><description>Goodrich Castle offers multiple stunning views of the Welsh-English Border and some of the best rural land in Britain. A must visit. What a surprise to find a memorial to airborne radar developed during ww2.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Goodrich Castle - Defence Heritage</title><link>https://defenceheritage.com/listings/goodrich-castle/</link><description>Goodrich Castle is one of the finest and best-preserved of all English medieval fortresses, majestically positioned in open countryside above the River Wye on the Herefordshire-Gloucestershire border.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
