<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Moscow State Circus</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Moscow+State+Circus</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Moscow State Circus</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Moscow+State+Circus</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Moscow - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moscow</link><description>In 1992, the Moscow government began planning a projected new part of central Moscow, the Moscow International Business Center, with the goal of creating a zone, the first in Russia, and in all of Eastern Europe, [254] that will combine business activity, living space and entertainment.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Moscow | History, Geography, Population, &amp; Map | Britannica</title><link>https://www.britannica.com/place/Moscow</link><description>Moscow, city, capital of Russia since the late 13th century. It is not only the political center of Russia but also the country’s most populous city and its industrial, cultural, scientific, and educational capital.</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 06:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>THE 15 BEST Things to Do in Moscow (2026) - Tripadvisor</title><link>https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attractions-g298484-Activities-Moscow_Central_Russia.html</link><description>See what other travelers like to do, based on ratings and number of bookings. These rankings are informed by Tripadvisor data—we consider traveler reviews, ratings, number of page views, and user location. 1. Red Square is a city square in Moscow, Russia.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>30 Best Things to do in Moscow Russia 2026 | Holidify</title><link>https://www.holidify.com/places/moscow/sightseeing-and-things-to-do.html</link><description>See most popular tourist places to visit in Moscow, top things to do, shopping and nightlife in Moscow, find entry timings, fees about various attractions in Moscow, Russia</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Moscow - New World Encyclopedia</title><link>https://www.newworldencyclopedia.org/entry/Moscow</link><description>Historically, it was the capital of the former Soviet Union and the Grand Duchy of Moscow, the pre-Imperial Russian state. It is the site of the Kremlin, which now serves as the ceremonial residence of the President of Russia. Moscow is world-renowned for its architecture and its performing arts.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Moscow – Travel guide at Wikivoyage</title><link>https://en.wikivoyage.org/wiki/Moscow</link><description>Moscow is the second most populous city in Europe, after Istanbul, and has the most populous metropolitan area in Europe, with some 21 million residents, comprising roughly one-seventh of the population of Russia. Moscow is in the UTC+3 time zone; there is no daylight saving time.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:34:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Moscow Travel Guide - National Geographic</title><link>https://www.nationalgeographic.com/travel/destination/moscow</link><description>Its Cold War history and massive size might give it an intimidating image, but at its core Moscow is every bit the European city offering wealth of history and culture coupled with modernity and...</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 17:48:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Moscow - Wikiwand</title><link>https://www.wikiwand.com/en/articles/Moscow</link><description>Moscow is the capital and largest city of Russia, standing on the Moskva River in Central Russia. It has a population estimated at over 13 million residents wit...</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 07:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Visit Moscow, sightseeing guide - VisitRussia</title><link>https://visitrussia.com/citiesguide/moscow/moscow.htm</link><description>The most comprehensive information on travel to Moscow. Top Moscow attractions, things to do, unique tours.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 03:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Moscow - Wikitravel</title><link>https://wikitravel.org/en/Moscow</link><description>Moscow has several world-class theatres (Bolshoi, Maly, Moscow Art Theatre, to name a few), and it is definitely worth planning a visit to one of them, although it is neither easy, nor cheap.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 21:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
