<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Sedgwick County Zoo</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Sedgwick+County+Zoo</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Sedgwick County Zoo</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Sedgwick+County+Zoo</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Sedgwick County Zoo – Wichita, Kansas</title><link>https://scz.org/</link><description>An award-winning wildlife park and attraction, Sedgwick County Zoo is fun for the whole family. Home to over 3,000 animals, the zoo is the most popular Kansas attraction.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Plan Your Visit – Sedgwick County Zoo</title><link>https://scz.org/visit</link><description>Whether you’re a first-timer or a frequent guest,u0003fun always awaits at the Zoo. Get the most out of your visit with an interactive map, daily event schedule…</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 06:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>About SCZ – Sedgwick County Zoo</title><link>https://scz.org/about</link><description>Sedgwick County Zoo has been recognized with national and international awards for its support of field conservation programs and successful breeding of rare and endangered species.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 18:06:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Attractions - Sedgwick County Zoo</title><link>https://scz.org/visit/attractions</link><description>Attraction Tickets Use your tickets at any of the Zoo’s attractions. Purchase single tickets, or save when you buy a Go Wild Attraction Pass.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sedgwick County Zoo Web Store :: Ticket Selection</title><link>https://tickets.scz.org/webstore/shop/viewItems.aspx?CG=scz&amp;C=adm</link><description>Skip the line and purchase Zoo admission tickets in advance. Onsite ticket sales end at 4:00 p.m. Gates close at 5:00 p.m. Sedgwick County Zoo donates $.50 of every ticket sold to worldwide conservation initiatives.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 17:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Zoo Calendar – Sedgwick County Zoo</title><link>https://scz.org/calendar</link><description>Zoo Calendar Explore the Zoo’s daily activity and one-of-a-kind events.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 21:13:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Learn - Sedgwick County Zoo</title><link>https://scz.org/learn</link><description>Learn About the Zoo There’s so much to explore. At Sedgwick County Zoo, the natural world comes to life with each step you take. From colossal elephants to majestic lions to playful otters and everything in between, we’re home to more than 3,000 animals across nearly 400 different species.</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 14:24:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Contact – Sedgwick County Zoo</title><link>https://scz.org/contact</link><description>Field trips at the Zoo bring nature to life! Please fill out the information requested below. Please bring the completed Field Trip Form found on the Field Trips page with you on the day of your visit. Please include all of the following information in the Message section of the form.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 18:06:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions – Sedgwick County Zoo</title><link>https://scz.org/faq</link><description>How much are tickets? Admission to Sedgwick County Zoo is $33 for adults and $28 for children under 12 and seniors over 62 (including tax). Children 2 and under…</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 18:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Wild Lights - Sedgwick County Zoo</title><link>https://scz.org/event/wild-lights</link><description>Returning Fall 2025! One-of-a-kind Asian Lantern sculptures will light up the Zoo during the WILDEST nights in town.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
