<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Theme Parks</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Theme+Parks</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Theme Parks</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Theme+Parks</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>The 19 Best Amusement Parks in the U.S. - U.S. News Travel</title><link>https://travel.usnews.com/features/top-amusement-parks-in-the-us</link><description>Ready for some fun at the best U.S. amusement parks? From Dollywood to Universal Studios Hollywood and Cedar Point to Hersheypark, plan some time for fun.</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 22:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>THE 15 BEST Florida Theme Parks (2026) - Tripadvisor</title><link>https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attractions-g28930-Activities-c52-t98-Florida.html</link><description>Every park is spotless, beautifully designed, and thoughtfully laid out, making it feel like you’ve stepped into mult... 7. Walt Disney World Resort. ... gracious cast members, excellent shows, beautiful parades, amazing new fireworks and even improved attractions. 8. Disney's Animal Kingdom Theme Park.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>THE BEST 10 AMUSEMENT PARKS in ST. CLOUD, FL - Yelp</title><link>https://www.yelp.com/search?cflt=amusementparks&amp;find_loc=St.+Cloud%2C+FL</link><description>Best Amusement Parks in St. Cloud, FL - Nona Adventure Park, Kissimmee Go-Karts, Wild Florida Airboats, White Glove Orlando Tours, Congo River Golf &amp; Exploration, Wand Master, Villas near Disney, Royal Family Tours, Tourist Info Store, Power Play Arcade</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 10:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>List of U.S. Amusement Parks and Theme Parks</title><link>https://themeparkarchitect.com/list-of-us-amusement-parks/</link><description>From amusement parks in Wyoming to theme parks in Central Florida, we’ve compiled an extensive list of all theme parks, water parks, and amusement parks in the United States. This guide will help you find the closest amusement park near you and will help you plan your next adventurous vacation!</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Florida Theme Parks - Discover the Best Amusement Parks in ...</title><link>https://www.visitflorida.com/things-to-do/attractions/theme-parks/</link><description>Discover all the theme parks and amusement parks in Florida. From Disney World and Universal Studios to SeaWorld and Busch Gardens, Florida has the best amusement parks in the world.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>10 best theme parks in the United States for 2025</title><link>https://10best.usatoday.com/awards/best-theme-park/</link><description>Not sure which theme park to visit? Here are our readers' 10 favorite theme parks across the United States.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:06:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>20 Best Amusement Parks in the World - Travel</title><link>https://www.travelandleisure.com/attractions/amusement-parks/best-amusement-parks-in-the-world</link><description>As Travel + Leisure' s resident theme park expert, I've curated this list of the world's best amusement parks, highlighting some of the most beautiful, thrilling, and downright fun spots to...</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 23:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
