<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Kenilworth Castle</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Kenilworth+Castle</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Kenilworth Castle</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Kenilworth+Castle</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Kenilworth Castle - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kenilworth_Castle</link><description>Kenilworth Castle is a castle in the town of Kenilworth in Warwickshire, England, managed by English Heritage; much of it is in ruins. The castle was founded after the Norman Conquest of 1066; with development through to the Tudor period.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 03:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kenilworth Castle and Elizabethan Garden | English Heritage</title><link>https://www.english-heritage.org.uk/visit/places/kenilworth-castle/</link><description>Watch this gorgeous drone footage of Kenilworth Castle and Elizabethan Garden before you plan your visit. Listen to properties historian Dr William Wyeth explain the story of the siege of Kenilworth Castle that took place in 1266, the people who took part and its legacy today.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Visiting Kenilworth Castle: History, Ruins &amp; Romance</title><link>https://www.thegeographicalcure.com/post/guide-kenilworth-castle</link><description>Explore Kenilworth Castle’s ruins: get hours and tickets, and learn how it evolved from royal fortress in the Barons’ War to Dudley’s 1575 festivities for Elizabeth I.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 01:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kenilworth Castle: A Historic English Fortress and Palace</title><link>https://www.ancient-history-sites.com/sites/kenilworth-castle/</link><description>Kenilworth Castle is built almost entirely from local New Red Sandstone and showcases five centuries of English military and domestic architecture. The castle’s layout includes an outer bailey, inner court, and several distinct courts and gardens, reflecting its evolution from fortress to palace.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 15:13:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kenilworth Castle &amp; Elizabethan Garden</title><link>https://visit.kenilworthweb.co.uk/listings/kenilworth-castle-elizabethan-garden/</link><description>Kenilworth Castle and its Elizabethan Gardens is the star of Kenilworth’s show and has been described as “the finest surviving example of a semi-royal palace of the later middle ages…”.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kenilworth Castle - Royal Palaces</title><link>https://www.royalpalaces.com/palaces/kenilworth/</link><description>Kenilworth Castle was one of the greatest castles in the land – and still is despite being ruined. The first castle was built in the early 1120s on land granted by Henry I to Geoffrey de Clinton.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kenilworth Castle - Historic UK</title><link>https://www.historic-uk.com/HistoryMagazine/DestinationsUK/Kenilworth-Castle/</link><description>Kenilworth Castle was an important royalist stronghold during the English Civil War. It was eventually partially dismantled and the mere drained by parliamentary troops. The castle was presented to Kenilworth in 1958, on the 400th anniversary of the accession of Elizabeth I to the throne.</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 13:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kenilworth Castle: Medieval Castle and Elizabethan Showpiece</title><link>https://artsandculture.google.com/story/hgXhBZw_mZE3IA</link><description>First built in the 1120s and a royal castle for most of its history, Kenilworth Castle was expanded by King John, John of Gaunt and Henry V. In 1563 Elizabeth I granted it to Robert Dudley,...</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 06:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kenilworth Castle (2026) - All You MUST Know Before You ... - Tripadvisor</title><link>https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attraction_Review-g186398-d213843-Reviews-Kenilworth_Castle-Kenilworth_Warwickshire_England.html</link><description>Kenilworth Castle earns praise for its evocative ruins, beautiful gardens, and family-friendly activities, though some reviewers note high entrance fees and café queues. Many visitors highlight the historical ambiance and stunning views. While most spend around two hours there, experiences vary.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 04:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kenilworth Castle, Warwickshire | History &amp; Photos - Britain Express</title><link>https://www.britainexpress.com/articles/Castles/kenilworth.htm</link><description>Kenilworth Castle, Warwickshire, is one of England's most impressive medieval castles. Discover the history and visitor information of Kenilworth.</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 09:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
