<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Chartres</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Chartres</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Chartres</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Chartres</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Chartres - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chartres</link><description>Chartres is best known for its cathedral, the Cathédrale Notre-Dame de Chartres, which is considered one of the finest and best preserved Gothic cathedrals in France and in Europe. Its historical and cultural importance has been recognized by its inclusion on the UNESCO list of World Heritage Sites.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 09:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chartres, France: travel guide, attractions and places to visit</title><link>https://www.francethisway.com/places/chartres-france.php</link><description>Visit Chartres - travel guide, places to visit and Chartres information and reviews</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 06:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>THE 15 BEST Things to Do in Chartres (2026) - Tripadvisor</title><link>https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attractions-g187122-Activities-Chartres_Eure_et_Loir_Centre_Val_de_Loire.html</link><description>Book these experiences for a closer look at the region. These rankings are informed by Tripadvisor data—we consider traveler reviews, ratings, number of page views, and user location. 1. Cathédrale de Chartres. This UNESCO World Heritage Site is known for its high-Gothic art and architectural style. 2. La Maison Picassiette.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 06:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chartres | France, Map, History, &amp; Facts | Britannica</title><link>https://www.britannica.com/place/Chartres-France</link><description>Chartres, town, capital of Eure-et-Loir département, Centre région, northwestern France, southwest of Paris. The town is built on the left bank of the Eure River, and the spires of its famous cathedral are a landmark on the plain of Beauce.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:48:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>25 Best &amp; Fun Things to Do in Chartres - The Tourist Checklist</title><link>https://thetouristchecklist.com/things-to-do-in-chartres/</link><description>Chartres, a charming town in France, is known for its stunning cathedral and beautiful countryside. This historic place is rich in culture, art, and natural beauty. Whether you are wandering through its narrow streets or enjoying the scenery by the river, Chartres offers something for everyone.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:48:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tourist Office of Chartres Urban Area | C'Chartres Tourism</title><link>https://www.chartres-tourisme.com/en</link><description>Experience a whole new experience! Beyond Chartres en lumières, our destination is unusual, greedy and full of energy. How about a good dose of oxygen at 1 hour from Paris?</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 06:52:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The 15 best things to do in Chartres - FranceRent</title><link>https://francerent.com/discover-france/chartres/the-15-best-things-to-do-in-chartres</link><description>Chartres, a historic French city near Paris, is explored through its top 15 attractions. Medieval streets, stunning architecture, and cultural treasures are discovered.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 03:13:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>9 Best things to do in Chartres, France, in 1 day or more</title><link>https://thedailypackers.com/chartres-travel-guide/</link><description>Discover Chartres, a medieval gem just 1 hour from Paris, known for its charming old town, majestic cathedral, and peaceful riverside walks.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 08:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Chartres Travel Guide Resources &amp; Trip Planning Info by Rick Steves</title><link>https://www.ricksteves.com/europe/france/chartres</link><description>Chartres, about 50 miles southwest of Paris, gives travelers a pleasant break in a lively, midsize town with a thriving, pedestrian-friendly old center. But the big reason to come to Chartres is to see its famous cathedral — arguably Europe's best example of pure Gothic architecture.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 07:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Picturesque Medieval Town in France ⚔️ Chartres ... - YouTube</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PvUOIU1kJys</link><description>🏰 Step into one of the most beautiful medieval towns in France — welcome to Chartres 🇫🇷🎥 In this immersive 4K 60fps walking tour, we explore the charming...</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 04:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
