<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Ring of Dingle</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Ring+of+Dingle</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Ring of Dingle</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Ring+of+Dingle</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Home Security Systems - Cameras, Alarms, Doorbells | Ring</title><link>https://ring.com/</link><description>Ultra-clear, Retinal 4K doorbells and cameras to help protect your spaces. A powerful multi-lens 4K camera with 140° to 360° coverage. Protect hard-to-see spaces with LED lights and siren. Secure large, open areas with ultra-bright LEDs and siren. Cover every corner with countless placement options.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 10:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ring - Always Home - Apps on Google Play</title><link>https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ringapp&amp;hl=en-US</link><description>Ring Doorbells and Cameras can send you instant alerts when someone’s at your door or motion is detected. Keep an eye on what matters with live HD video and greet visitors with Two-Way Talk.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:13:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon.com: Ring Security System</title><link>https://www.amazon.com/ring-security-system/s?k=ring+security+system</link><description>Shop Ring security products for your home or business. Find alarm systems, doorbells, and surveillance cameras.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 21:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Amazon's Ring cancels Flock partnership amid Super Bowl ad ...</title><link>https://www.cnbc.com/2026/02/12/amazons-ring-cancels-flock-partnership-amid-super-bowl-ad-backlash.html</link><description>Ring's decision to cancel its partnership with Flock comes as tech companies face growing pressure to reexamine their work with federal agencies.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:58:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ring Smart Home Security - Best Buy</title><link>https://www.bestbuy.com/site/ring/all-ring-devices/pcmcat1583189521778.c?id=pcmcat1583189521778</link><description>Keep an eye on your home and make it more secure. Shop Best Buy for Ring smart doorbells, security cameras, alarm systems and more.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 06:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ring Whole Home Camera Kit | Costco</title><link>https://www.costco.com/p/-/ring-whole-home-camera-kit/4000360541</link><description>Ring Whole Home Camera Kit, Battery Doorbell w/Head-to-Toe HD Video, Outdoor Cam Plus with 2K Visual Clarity and Color, Low Light Sight Delivers Clear Color in Near-dark, Pan-Tilt Indoor Cam with 360° Horizontal Pan Coverage, Add Ring Subscription Not Included, Sold Seperately,</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:13:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ring ends partnership with Flock, company that gives info to ...</title><link>https://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/smart-home/2026/02/13/ring-camera-ad-flock-partnership-super-bowl/88657750007/</link><description>Ring canceled its partnership with Flock, a tech company that works with police to help solve crime, days after a controversial Super Bowl ad.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 00:43:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
