<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: England Flower</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=England+Flower</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>England Flower</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=England+Flower</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>England - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/England</link><description>England is a country that is part of the United Kingdom. It is located on the island of Great Britain, of which it covers about 62%, and more than 100 smaller adjacent islands.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>England | History, Map, Flag, Population, Cities, &amp; Facts ...</title><link>https://www.britannica.com/place/England</link><description>England, predominant constituent unit of the United Kingdom, occupying more than half of the island of Great Britain. Outside the British Isles, England is often erroneously considered synonymous with the island of Great Britain (England, Scotland, and Wales) and even with the entire United Kingdom.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 07:58:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>England Maps &amp; Facts - World Atlas</title><link>https://www.worldatlas.com/maps/united-kingdom/england</link><description>England, a country that constitutes the central and southern parts of the United Kingdom, shares its northern border with Scotland and its western border with Wales.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>England - VisitBritain.org</title><link>https://www.visitbritain.org/destinations/england</link><description>England is renowned for its iconic landmarks, as well as historic castles, world-leading museums, diverse festivals and top-notch sport. Go fossils hunting along the Jurassic Coast, climb England’s highest peaks in the Lake District, or marvel at the iconic Stonehenge and White Cliffs of Dover.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 22:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>England – Travel guide at Wikivoyage</title><link>https://en.wikivoyage.org/wiki/England</link><description>England is the largest and, with 55 million inhabitants, by far the most populous of the United Kingdom 's constituent countries. A 'green and pleasant land', England is known for its dramatic scenery of countryside, rolling hills, green fields, ancient woodland, and rugged coastline.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>About England Overview</title><link>https://england.edu/international-students/about-england-overview/</link><description>Vastly diverse and populated with a fascinating blend of international cultures from around the globe, the United Kingdom, situated in Western Europe, is recognized as a thriving nation that offers all the elements of balanced modern day living.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:12:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>England - New World Encyclopedia</title><link>https://www.newworldencyclopedia.org/entry/England</link><description>England became a unified state during the tenth century and takes its name from the Angles, one of a number of Germanic tribes who settled in the territory during the fifth and sixth centuries. England ranks among the world's most influential centers of cultural development.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
