<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Betws-y-Coed Wales</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Betws-y-Coed+Wales</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Betws-y-Coed Wales</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Betws-y-Coed+Wales</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Spider-Man: Far from Home (2019) - Full cast &amp; crew - IMDb</title><link>https://m.imdb.com/title/tt6320628/fullcredits/</link><description>Spider-Man: Far from Home (2019) - Cast and crew credits, including actors, actresses, directors, writers and more.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 06:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Far From Home - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spider-Man:_Far_From_Home</link><description>The film was directed by Jon Watts, written by Chris McKenna and Erik Sommers, and stars Tom Holland as Peter Parker / Spider-Man, alongside Samuel L. Jackson, Zendaya, Cobie Smulders, Jon Favreau, J. B. Smoove, Jacob Batalon, Martin Starr, Tony Revolori, Marisa Tomei, and Jake Gyllenhaal.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Far From Home - Cast &amp; Crew — The Movie Database (TMDB)</title><link>https://www.themoviedb.org/movie/429617-spider-man-far-from-home/cast</link><description>Peter Parker and his friends go on a summer trip to Europe. However, they will hardly be able to rest - Peter will have to agree to help Nick Fury uncover the mystery of creatures that cause natural disasters and destruction throughout the continent.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 14:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Far from Home - Full Cast &amp; Crew - TV Guide</title><link>https://www.tvguide.com/movies/spider-man-far-from-home/cast/2000166815/</link><description>Learn more about the full cast of Spider-Man: Far from Home with news, photos, videos and more at TV Guide</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 04:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Far From Home - Marvel Cinematic Universe Wiki</title><link>https://marvelcinematicuniverse.fandom.com/wiki/Spider-Man:_Far_From_Home</link><description>Peter Parker returns in Spider-Man: Far From Home, the next chapter of the Spider-Man: Homecoming series! Our friendly neighborhood Super Hero decides to join his best friends Ned, MJ, and the rest of the gang on a European vacation.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 07:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Far From Home (2019) Cast and Crew - Fandango</title><link>https://www.fandango.com/spider-man-far-from-home-2019-216033/cast-and-crew</link><description>Following the events of Avengers: Endgame, Spider-Man must step up to take on new threats in a world that has changed forever.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Far From Home (2019) Cast Popularity</title><link>https://televisionstats.com/m/spider-man:-far-from-home/cast</link><description>Cast members details for Spider-Man: Far From Home. Get actor roles, casting info, images and more. Explore the cast of characters, their bios and filmography.</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 02:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Far from Home (2019) - IMDb</title><link>https://m.imdb.com/title/tt6320628/</link><description>Reviewers say 'Spider-Man: Far From Home' garners mixed reviews, highlighting impressive visual effects, thrilling action sequences, and standout performances by Tom Holland and Jake Gyllenhaal.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 23:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Far From Home | Cast and Crew | Rotten Tomatoes</title><link>https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/spider_man_far_from_home/cast-and-crew</link><description>Discover the cast and crew of Spider-Man: Far From Home on Rotten Tomatoes. See actors, directors, and more behind the scenes. Explore now!</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 05:48:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Far From Home (2019) - Full Cast &amp; Crew</title><link>https://bingebase.com/movies/spider-man-far-from-home-2019/cast</link><description>Spider-Man: Far From Home cast: Tom Holland, Jake Gyllenhaal, Samuel L. Jackson, and 137 more actors. Full cast &amp; crew list with photos.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
