<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Dover, Calais</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Dover%2c+Calais</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Dover, Calais</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Dover%2c+Calais</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Dover Saddlery English Tack &amp; Riding Apparel</title><link>https://www.doversaddlery.com/</link><description>Dover Saddlery is your source for English riding apparel, equestrian wear, bridles, saddles, and other tack. Outfit your horse and yourself in complete comfort and classic style at Dover Saddlery.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 06:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dover - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dover</link><description>Dover (/ ˈdoʊvər / DOH-vər) is a town and major ferry port in Kent, England. It faces France across the Strait of Dover, the narrowest part of the English Channel at 33 kilometres (21 mi) from Cap Gris Nez in France. It lies southeast of Canterbury and east of Maidstone.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Overview - Dover Corporation</title><link>https://www.dovercorporation.com/about-us/overview</link><description>Dover is a diversified global manufacturer and solutions provider with annual revenue of over $8 billion.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Redefining what's possible | Dover Corporation</title><link>https://www.dovercorporation.com/</link><description>Dover is a diversified global manufacturer that delivers innovative equipment and components, consumable supplies, aftermarket parts, software and digital solutions and support services.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dover Publications | Dover Books</title><link>https://store.doverpublications.com/</link><description>Dover Publications and Dover Books – Classic literature, coloring books, children’s books, music books, art books and more.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Top Things to Do in Dover</title><link>https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attractions-g186313-Activities-Dover_Kent_England.html</link><description>Towering white, silent guardians of Great Britain, drawing a protective curtain on England’s shore, the White Cliffs of Dover are an evocative, enduring, iconic and world-renowned symbol of Great …</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dover | England, Map, History, &amp; Facts | Britannica</title><link>https://www.britannica.com/place/Dover-England</link><description>Dover, town (parish) and seaport on the Strait of Dover, Dover district, administrative and historic county of Kent, southeastern England. It is situated on the English Channel at the mouth of a valley in the chalk uplands that form the famous white cliffs.</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
