<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Lake District</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Lake+District</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Lake District</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Lake+District</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Lake District - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_District</link><description>The Lake District National Park includes all of the central Lake District, though the town of Kendal, some coastal areas and the Cartmel and Furness peninsulas are located outside the park's boundary.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lake District National Park - Official site for the Lake District ...</title><link>https://www.lakedistrict.gov.uk/</link><description>The Lake District is England's largest National Park and UNESCO World Heritage Site. Discover spectacular landscapes, picturesque villages, a warm welcome and a rich cultural heritage.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Visit Lake District | The Official Guide to Cumbria</title><link>https://www.visitlakedistrict.com/</link><description>Visit the Lake District Cumbria, a place where the beauty of the landscape combines with the best quality accommodation, food and drink and things to do. Search for Lake District hotels, bed and breakfast, cottages campsites and glamping.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 08:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A first-time guide to England's Lake District - Lonely Planet</title><link>https://www.lonelyplanet.com/articles/guide-to-the-lake-district</link><description>From Windermere to Scafell Pike, and the best things to do with your family, this first-time guide will tell you everything you need to know before visiting the Lake District.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 03:26:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lake District Attractions &amp; Places to Visit | VisitBritain</title><link>https://www.visitbritain.com/en/destinations/england/lake-district</link><description>Planning a trip to the Lake District? Discover the best things to do and activities in our official tourism guide and learn why we love the Lake District.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 03:19:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Essential Guide to Lake District National Park - Travel</title><link>https://www.travelandleisure.com/guide-to-lake-district-national-park-11865655</link><description>The Lake District is England's largest national park and is home to its highest mountain, Scafell Pike, as well as its deepest lake, Wast Water.</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 14:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lake District | England, Map, &amp; Facts | Britannica</title><link>https://www.britannica.com/place/Lake-District-region-and-national-park-England</link><description>Lake District, famous scenic region and national park in the administrative county of Cumbria, England. It occupies portions of the historic counties of Cumberland, Lancashire, and Westmorland. The national park covers an area of 866 square miles (2,243 square km). It contains the principal English.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 03:24:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Lake District | UNESCO World Heritage Site | England's Largest ...</title><link>https://www.thelakedistrict.com/</link><description>The Lake District is England's largest National Park, covering 2,362 square kilometres of breathtaking mountains, serene lakes, and charming villages in Cumbria, North West England.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 13:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Lake District: Where to Go, Where to Stay &amp; What to Do ...</title><link>https://www.thelakedistrict.org/</link><description>Divided by area, we describe our top 12 towns in the Lake District with a bit about their history, the shopping, the key attractions, and how to get there.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 09:12:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lake District National Parks // National Trust Lake District</title><link>https://www.nationalparks.uk/park/lake-district/</link><description>Welcome to the Lake District. Step into the National Park and UNESCO World Heritage Site to discover spectacular landscapes, pretty villages, a warm welcome and a rich cultural heritage.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
