<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: EPCOT Walt Disney World</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=EPCOT+Walt+Disney+World</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>EPCOT Walt Disney World</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=EPCOT+Walt+Disney+World</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>EPCOT Theme Park | Walt Disney World Resort</title><link>https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/destinations/epcot/</link><description>Celebrate culture, nature and human progress at EPCOT. Enjoy innovative attractions, savor international flavors, and discover exciting seasonal festivals.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 06:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Disney World Attractions &amp; Rides | Walt Disney World Resort</title><link>https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/attractions/epcot/</link><description>Entertainment at CommuniCore Plaza Stage EPCOT Today's Performance Time: 5:30 PM to 8:30 PM Live Entertainment</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:42:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tickets, Annual Passes &amp; Vacation Packages | Walt Disney World Resort</title><link>https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/admission/</link><description>Disney After Hours at EPCOT Select Nights January 22 to September 24, 2026 Explore a world of possibilities at EPCOT during a limited-capacity event with yummy snacks and lower wait times for select attractions.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World Discovery - EPCOT - Walt Disney World Resort</title><link>https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/attractions/epcot/guardians-of-the-galaxy-cosmic-rewind/</link><description>Travel through space and time with Guardians of the Galaxy: Cosmic Rewind at EPCOT in Walt Disney World Resort, near Orlando, Florida.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Special Events &amp; Tours - Walt Disney World Resort</title><link>https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/events-tours/</link><description>Behind the Seeds EPCOT Today's Hours: 10:30 AM, 11:30 AM, 12:30 PM, 1:30 PM, 2:30 PM, 3:30 PM, 4:30 PM</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EPCOT International Festival of the Holidays - Walt Disney World Resort</title><link>https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/events-tours/epcot/holiday-festival/</link><description>Celebrate holidays around the world during EPCOT International Festival of the Holidays, a spirited seasonal festival at Walt Disney World Resort.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 18:36:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Special Offers, Deals &amp; Discounts | Walt Disney World Resort</title><link>https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/special-offers/</link><description>3-Day, 3-Park Ticket with admission to Disney’s Hollywood Studios, EPCOT and Disney’s Animal Kingdom theme park only; not valid for admission to Magic Kingdom park</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 03:32:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Remy’s Ratatouille Adventure at EPCOT | Walt Disney World Resort</title><link>https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/attractions/epcot/remys-ratatouille-adventure/</link><description>Join Chef Remy on a culinary adventure. Shrink and race through Gusteau’s kitchen on Remy’s Ratatouille Adventure, located in the France Pavilion at EPCOT.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:52:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Journey of Water, Inspired by Moana - Walt Disney World Resort</title><link>https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/attractions/epcot/journey-of-water/</link><description>Experience Journey of Water, Inspired by Moana, and immerse yourself in the exploration of the water cycle with playful, interactive elements.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>EPCOT International Festival of the Arts</title><link>https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/events-tours/epcot/epcot-international-festival-of-the-arts/</link><description>Come celebrate the visual arts, performing arts and culinary arts during EPCOT International Festival of the Arts at Walt Disney World Resort in Florida.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 22:24:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
