<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: United Kingdom</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=United+Kingdom</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>United Kingdom</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=United+Kingdom</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>United Kingdom - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom</link><description>The United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, commonly known as the United Kingdom (UK) or Britain, [m] is a country in northwestern Europe, off the coast of the continental mainland.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>United Kingdom | History, Population, Map, Flag, Capital ...</title><link>https://www.britannica.com/place/United-Kingdom</link><description>United Kingdom, island country located off the northwestern coast of mainland Europe. It comprises the whole of the island of Great Britain—which contains England, Wales, and Scotland—as well as the northern portion of the island of Ireland. Its capital is London.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The United Kingdom Maps &amp; Facts - World Atlas</title><link>https://www.worldatlas.com/maps/united-kingdom</link><description>The United Kingdom comprises of a union of the individual countries of England, Scotland and Wales (collectively, Great Britain) and the constitutionally distinct region of Northern Ireland.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 06:52:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>United Kingdom | Culture, Facts &amp; Travel | - CountryReports</title><link>https://www.countryreports.org/country/unitedkingdom.htm</link><description>The United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland is a highly developed constitutional monarchy composed of Great Britain (England, Scotland, and Wales) and Northern Ireland.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 09:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>United Kingdom - A Country Profile - Nations Online Project</title><link>https://www.nationsonline.org/oneworld/united_kingdom.htm</link><description>Now four constituent nations form the United Kingdom (England, Scotland, Wales, and Northern Ireland). Great Britain, the dominant industrial and maritime power of the 19th century, played a leading role in developing parliamentary democracy, in advancing literature, science, and later pop music.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>United Kingdom - New World Encyclopedia</title><link>https://www.newworldencyclopedia.org/entry/United_Kingdom</link><description>The United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland (commonly known as the United Kingdom, the UK, or Britain) is a state located off the northwestern coast of mainland Europe.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>United Kingdom country profile - BBC News</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-18023389</link><description>The United Kingdom is a state made up of the historic countries of England, Wales and Scotland, as well as Northern Ireland. It is known as the home of both modern parliamentary democracy and...</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 15:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
