<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Montenegro</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Montenegro</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Montenegro</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Montenegro</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>The 18 best things to do in Montenegro - Lonely Planet</title><link>https://www.lonelyplanet.com/articles/top-things-to-do-in-montenegro</link><description>Discover the best things to do in the Balkan nation of Montenegro, from untouched natural beauty to rich culture and fascinating ancient history.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 05:27:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>18 things you need to know before traveling to Montenegro</title><link>https://www.lonelyplanet.com/articles/things-to-know-before-traveling-to-montenegro</link><description>Planning, etiquette and safety tips for Montenegro will ease your visit to this underrated Balkan gem.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Montenegro travel - Lonely Planet | Europe</title><link>https://www.lonelyplanet.com/destinations/montenegro</link><description>Discover majestic mountains, breathtaking beaches, stunning national parks and more in our Montenegro guide. Find top attractions, local spots and expert tips.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 15:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A first-time guide to Montenegro - Lonely Planet</title><link>https://www.lonelyplanet.com/articles/guide-to-montenegro</link><description>From the atmospheric streets of UNESCO-listed Kotor to hiking trails through Durmitor National Park, here's how to plan your time and budget in Montenegro.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:34:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Best places to visit in Montenegro - Lonely Planet</title><link>https://www.lonelyplanet.com/articles/best-places-to-visit-in-montenegro</link><description>Discover the best places to visit in Montenegro, from UNESCO-listed walled towns and Adriatic beaches to the glacial lakes of Durmitor National Park.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Montenegro’s most unforgettable experiences – Lonely Planet</title><link>https://www.lonelyplanet.com/articles/best-of-montenegro</link><description>While it may be the beach that lures you to Montenegro, look up from your towel and you will discover a land full of culture, history and natural wonders, not to mention delicious food.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 06:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The top things to do Kotor - Lonely Planet</title><link>https://www.lonelyplanet.com/articles/top-things-to-do-in-kotor</link><description>Headed to Kotor, Montenegro? Here are the 11 best things to do, from exploring Kotor’s historic old town to boat trips and hikes around the Bay of Kotor.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>When is the best time to visit Montenegro? - Lonely Planet</title><link>https://www.lonelyplanet.com/articles/when-to-visit-montenegro</link><description>Whether you’re seeking summer beach days, mild weather for exploring historic towns or snow for skiing, here are the best times to visit Montenegro.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 21:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Niagara Falls | Podgorica, Montenegro - Lonely Planet</title><link>https://www.lonelyplanet.com/points-of-interest/niagara-falls/1543410</link><description>Sign in to save, get inspo &amp; more Attraction in Montenegro Ostrog Monastery Discover Save</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 08:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Podgorica travel - Lonely Planet | Montenegro, Europe</title><link>https://www.lonelyplanet.com/destinations/montenegro/podgorica</link><description>Discover Podgorica's blend of Ottoman relics, modern cafés and riverside parks in our Montenegro travel guide. Top sights, local eats and expert tips.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 02:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
