<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Canterbury</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Canterbury</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Canterbury</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Canterbury</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Canterbury - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canterbury</link><description>Canterbury (/ ˈkæntərb (ə) ri / ⓘ, /- bɛri /) [2] is a city and UNESCO World Heritage Site, in the Canterbury district, in the county of Kent, England; it was a county borough until 1974. It lies on the River Stour. The city has a mild oceanic climate.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 18:06:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Commons At Canterbury – Broken Arrow Townhomes</title><link>http://www.thecommonsatcanterbury.org/</link><description>The Commons at Canterbury is a townhome community comprised of 94 privately owned homes. The Commons address is 2408 W Quantico St., Broken Arrow, OK 74011. The Commons does not have a business office nor does it have paid employees. Board members are homeowners who volunteer their time.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 08:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Visit Canterbury</title><link>https://www.canterbury.co.uk/</link><description>Experience winter in one of the most beautiful parts of England. In the heart of Kent and just under one hour's train drive from London, Canterbury is a medieval walled city that has been hosting visitors for more than 1,000 years - so a warm welcome for any 'pilgrim' is guaranteed!</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 20:22:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The 12 best things to do in Canterbury, England - Lonely Planet</title><link>https://www.lonelyplanet.com/articles/top-things-to-do-in-canterbury</link><description>Discover the best things to do in Canterbury, from historic cathedrals and museums to scenic river tours and charming pubs.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 23:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Canterbury | Location, Cathedral, History, &amp; Facts | Britannica</title><link>https://www.britannica.com/place/Canterbury-England</link><description>Canterbury is a historic town and surrounding city (local authority) in the administrative and historic county of Kent, southeastern England. Its cathedral has been the primary ecclesiastical center of England since the early 7th century CE.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 03:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>10 Best Things To Do In Canterbury That Make A Visit Worth It (+ map)</title><link>https://abroadpurpose.com/best-things-to-do-in-canterbury-england/</link><description>But I can attest that if you love York and enjoy top historical cities in England, then you’ll absolutely love Canterbury. Even if you only have an afternoon to explore, here are the 10 best things to do in Canterbury and why you really must go!</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:36:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>THE 15 BEST Things to Do in Canterbury (2026) - Tripadvisor</title><link>https://www.tripadvisor.com/Attractions-g186311-Activities-Canterbury_Kent_England.html</link><description>Explore its unique history and take in some of the most iconic views in the county of Kent.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>12 Unique Things to do in Canterbury - Travel Magazine</title><link>https://www.travelmag.com/articles/things-to-do-in-canterbury/</link><description>Made famous by its impressive cathedral, imposing castle and the country´s oldest church, there’s no shortage of great things to see and do in Canterbury, with thousands flocking to the magnificent medieval city every year.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 03:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Canterbury - Simple English Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</title><link>https://simple.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canterbury</link><description>Canterbury was once the main settlement of the Celtic tribe of the Cantiaci, which lived in most of modern-day Kent. In the 1st century AD, the Romans captured the settlement and named it Durovernum Cantiacorum. [4]</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 03:26:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Canterbury, England: All You Must Know Before You Go (2026 ...</title><link>https://www.tripadvisor.com/Tourism-g186311-Canterbury_Kent_England-Vacations.html</link><description>In the Middle Ages, Canterbury’s pilgrimage-site status made it the setting of Chaucer’s seminal "Canterbury Tales," while today, cobbled streets and the 6th-century Canterbury Cathedral secure this city as one of England’s must-visit destinations.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 23:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
