<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Raglan Castle</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Raglan+Castle</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Raglan Castle</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Raglan+Castle</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Raglan Castle - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raglan_Castle</link><description>Raglan Castle (Welsh: Castell Rhaglan) is a late medieval castle located just north of the village of Raglan in the county of Monmouthshire in south east Wales.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Raglan Castle - Cadw</title><link>https://cadw.gov.wales/visit/places-to-visit/raglan-castle</link><description>The unmistakable silhouette of Raglan crowning a ridge amid glorious countryside is the grandest castle ever built by Welshmen. We can thank Sir William ap Thomas, the ‘blue knight of Gwent’, for the moated Great Tower of 1435 that still dominates this mighty fortress-palace.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 01:44:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Raglan Castle: Grand Welsh Ruins And Forgotten Majesty</title><link>https://www.exploring-castles.com/uk/wales/raglan_castle/</link><description>Raglan has a rather checkered history – it started life, in late Medieval times, as a real fortified castle. However, being built during a peaceful period in the English/Welsh border wars, it didn’t see much military action. As a result, it evolved into a breathtakingly beautiful Tudor manor-house.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 08:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Raglan Castle: A Historic Welsh Fortress and Noble Residence</title><link>https://www.ancient-history-sites.com/sites/raglan-castle/</link><description>Raglan Castle, near the village of Raglan in southeast Wales, offers a glimpse into medieval and Renaissance noble life through its layered history and well-preserved ruins. It reflects centuries of architectural evolution, regional power shifts, and the blend of defense with residential grandeur.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Raglan Castle - Castles and Legends</title><link>https://castlesandlegends.com/castles/raglan-castle/</link><description>Explore Raglan Castle in Monmouthshire - a 15th-century fortress built by Sir William ap Thomas. Discover its moated Great Tower, rich history, and scenic views.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 21:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Raglan Castle - Great Castles</title><link>https://great-castles.com/raglan.php</link><description>Raglan Castle is one of the last true castles to be built in Wales. Its construction began in the 1430s by Sir William ap Thomas, the Blue Knight of Gwent, who fought at the Battle of Agincourt with King Henry V in 1415.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 23:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Raglan Castle (Cadw) - Castle in Raglan, Raglan - Visit ...</title><link>https://www.visitmonmouthshire.com/things-to-do/raglan-castle-cadw-p1502721</link><description>About Raglan Castle has an unmistakable silhouette crowning a ridge amid glorious Monmouthshire countryside, and is the grandest castle ever built by Welshmen. We can thank Sir William ap Thomas, the ‘blue knight of Gwent’, for the moated Great Tower of 1435 that still dominates this mighty fortress-palace.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 22:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
