<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Six Flags Magic Mountain</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Six+Flags+Magic+Mountain</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Six Flags Magic Mountain</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Six+Flags+Magic+Mountain</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Six Flags Magic Mountain | Six Flags Magic Mountain</title><link>https://www.sixflags.com/magicmountain</link><description>Six Flags Magic Mountain, the Thrill Capital of the World, is home to the best collection of world-class roller coasters and is packed with rides, games and attractions for the entire family!</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:42:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Flags Magic Mountain - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Six_Flags_Magic_Mountain</link><description>Six Flags Magic Mountain, formerly known and colloquially referred to as simply Magic Mountain, is a 209-acre (85 ha) amusement park located in Valencia, California, 35 miles (56 km) northwest of downtown Los Angeles.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 18:06:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>California Theme Park Closing After 49 Years in 2027 - Farewell to Fun ...</title><link>https://theamericannews.net/america/usa/california/farewell-to-fun-iconic-california-theme-park-set-to-close-after-49-years-in-2027/</link><description>In a significant development for amusement park enthusiasts and local residents, Six Flags Entertainment Corporation has announced plans to close one of its flagship parks, Six Flags Magic Mountain, located in Valencia, California.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 15:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Flags Shares Unexpected Announcement of Entire Theme Park Closure</title><link>https://www.disneydining.com/six-flags-magic-mountain-closure-cj1/</link><description>Six Flags Magic Mountain closed early today due to rain, capping a turbulent year marked by debt, park closures, and operational uncertainty.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:12:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Flags Magic Mountain Shuts Down, Update Given Amid Sale Rumors</title><link>https://insidethemagic.net/2025/03/six-flags-magic-mountain-theme-park-ceases-operations-cj1/</link><description>As stormy weather moves across the area, Six Flags Magic Mountain has closed its gates to all guests today. The Southern California theme park confirmed the closure on X, formerly known as...</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:43:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Flags Magic Mountain | Tickets, Hours, Rides &amp; Coasters ...</title><link>https://topthemeparks.com/park/six-flags-magic-mountain/</link><description>Six Flags Magic Mountain, located in Valencia, California (just north of Los Angeles), is a paradise for roller coaster fans. With more coasters than any other theme park in the world, it’s famous for delivering high-speed thrills, record-breaking drops, and nonstop adrenaline.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 14:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Magic Mountain closes as another storm hits Southern California</title><link>https://ktla.com/news/theme-parks/magic-mountain-closes-as-another-storm-hits-southern-california/</link><description>Six Flags Magic Mountain didn’t open its gates on Monday due to “inclement weather” as another round of rain moved into Southern California. The theme park announced on Instagram that ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:32:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rides | Six Flags Magic Mountain</title><link>https://www.sixflags.com/magicmountain/attractions</link><description>As the “Undisputed Thrill Capital of the World,” everyone can go all out and experience the ultimate adventure at Six Flags Magic Mountain.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 02:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Flags Magic Mountain - Visit California</title><link>https://www.visitcalifornia.com/experience/six-flags-magic-mountain/</link><description>Living up to the nickname “Thrill Capital of the World” with more world-class roller coasters than any other destination, the Six Flags Magic Mountain theme park, roughly an hour’s drive northeast of Los Angeles in Valencia, is a daredevil’s paradise.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Flags Magic Mountain closes due to forecast of heavy rain and high ...</title><link>https://www.ocregister.com/2026/02/16/six-flags-magic-mountain-closes-due-to-forecast-of-heavy-rain-and-high-winds/</link><description>A rainy end to the Presidents Day weekend has forced Six Flags Magic Mountain to close its gates due to a forecast of heavy downpours and a threat of high winds in the Santa Clarita area. Six ...</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 20:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
