<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Ireland</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Ireland</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Ireland</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Ireland</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Ireland's inspiring idea to go greener - The World Economic Forum</title><link>https://www.weforum.org/stories/2019/09/ireland-reforestation-environment-trees/</link><description>Ireland has ambitious plans to harness the power of trees, combating climate change and making the Emerald Isle even greener.</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 14:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Everything you need to know about Ireland’s economy</title><link>https://www.weforum.org/stories/2019/03/everything-you-need-to-know-about-ireland-s-economy/</link><description>Although it was among the nations hardest hit by the 2007/8 economic crisis, Ireland’s economy has bounced back.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 09:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Duncan Crabtree-Ireland - Agenda Contributor | World Economic Forum</title><link>https://www.weforum.org/stories/authors/duncan-crabtree-ireland/</link><description>Duncan Crabtree-Ireland is the National Executive Director and Chief Negotiator of SAG-AFTRA. In this capacity, he oversees the world’s most influential entertainment union, comprised of more than 160,000 members worldwide who work in film, television, broadcast news, commercials, music, video games and more. Crabtree-Ireland has played a critical role in many of SAG-AFTRA’s signature ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 22:06:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>These countries are paying people to move to the countryside</title><link>https://www.weforum.org/stories/2022/04/countries-paying-you-to-move-to-countryside/</link><description>From Japan and Portugal to Ireland and Australia, some countries will fund your escape to the countryside. Here are some examples of rural relocation grants.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:49:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Britain and the EU reach Northern Ireland trade deal | World Economic Forum</title><link>https://www.weforum.org/stories/2023/03/brexit-trade-deal-northern-ireland-windsor-framework/</link><description>The Windsor Framework, a new deal struck between the UK and the EU, is designed to resolve the issue of border checks for goods arriving in Northern Ireland.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:13:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Davos 2025: What to expect and who's coming? - The World Economic Forum</title><link>https://www.weforum.org/stories/2024/12/davos-2025-whos-coming-and-what-to-expect/</link><description>Davos 2025, the Annual Meeting of the World Economic Forum, takes place from 20-24 January under the theme, Collaboration for the Intelligent Age.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Davos 2026: What to expect, who's coming and how to follow</title><link>https://www.weforum.org/stories/2026/01/davos-2026-annual-meeting-what-to-expect/</link><description>Davos 2026 provides an impartial platform to connect leaders to confront shared challenges and drive innovations defining the future.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why the Phillips curve still works for Ireland</title><link>https://www.weforum.org/stories/2015/07/why-the-phillips-curve-still-works-for-ireland/</link><description>7 Ireland experienced three monetary regimes, two of them fixed (a parity link with sterling until 1979, and the euro period since 1999) and one period of floating during EMU. 8 For instance, Geary (1976) studies annual data for the period 1953-1974, and Geary and Jones (1975) study annual data for the period 1953-1972.</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 08:06:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The US-EU trade deal, explained | World Economic Forum</title><link>https://www.weforum.org/stories/2025/07/the-eu-us-trade-deal-explained-eu-competitiveness/</link><description>Germany is Europe's largest exporter of goods to the US followed by Ireland, Italy and France. French Prime Minister François Bayrou said the deal was "a dark day" for the EU. Concerns about rising inflation and its impact on economic growth in Europe have been raised, too.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 06:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How AI can empower, not replace, human creativity</title><link>https://www.weforum.org/stories/2025/01/artificial-intelligence-must-serve-human-creativity-not-replace-it/</link><description>Ethical standards, collective action and responsible innovation will ensure AI elevates human creativity rather than sidelining it.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
