<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Germany</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Germany</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Germany</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Germany</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Germany - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Germany</link><description>Germany is a developed country with a strong economy; it has the largest economy in Europe by nominal GDP. As a major force in several industrial, scientific and technological sectors, Germany is both the world's third-largest exporter and third-largest importer.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Germany | Facts, Geography, Maps, &amp; History | Britannica</title><link>https://www.britannica.com/place/Germany</link><description>Although Germany existed as a loose polity of Germanic-speaking peoples for millennia, a united German nation in roughly its present form dates only to 1871. Modern Germany is a liberal democracy that has become ever more integrated with and central to a united Europe.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 04:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Germany | Culture, Facts &amp; Travel | - CountryReports</title><link>https://www.countryreports.org/country/Germany.htm</link><description>Germany in depth country profile. Unique hard to find content on Germany. Includes customs, culture, history, geography, economy current events, photos, video, and more.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Facts about Germany - deutschland.de</title><link>https://www.deutschland.de/en/germany-facts-information-figures-worth-knowing</link><description>Germany is a parliamentary democracy with its Basic Law serving as the constitutional foundation. Germany is a federation comprising 16 federal states. Who governs in Germany? The federal president is the head of state, an office that has been held by Frank-Walter Steinmeier since 2017.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 22:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Information on Germany - Germany Travel</title><link>https://www.germany.travel/en/information-on-germany.html</link><description>You will find everything you ever wanted to know about Germany in our summary of key facts and figures, from form of government to size, landscapes, population, lifestyle and cultural scene.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 03:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Facts about Germany - Federal Foreign Office</title><link>https://www.germany.info/us-en/welcome/resources-for-you/2067360-2067360</link><description>It provides facts and figures about Germany's people, system of government, social life, politics, economy and culture. The website breaks down information into topics, with details such as charts, statistics and other related facts located in each section.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 17:17:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Germany Maps &amp; Facts - World Atlas</title><link>https://www.worldatlas.com/maps/germany</link><description>Physical map of Germany showing major cities, terrain, national parks, rivers, and surrounding countries with international borders and outline maps. Key facts about Germany.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 14:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Germany - New World Encyclopedia</title><link>https://www.newworldencyclopedia.org/entry/Germany</link><description>Germany, officially the Federal Republic of Germany, a country in Central Europe, is a modern great power, the world's third largest economy, and the world's largest exporter of goods.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 08:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Seite-Topic-Auf einen Blick | Facts about Germany</title><link>https://www.tatsachen-ueber-deutschland.de/en/germany-glance</link><description>Germany at a glance The Federal Republic of Germany is situated in the heart of Europe. It is a cosmopolitan, democratic country with a rich heritage and a thriving present-day. Facts and figures at a glance.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Welcome to Germany</title><link>https://www.welcome-center-germany.com/post/welcome-to-germany</link><description>Explore Germany's rich history, diverse geography, vibrant culture, and dynamic economy in this comprehensive guide.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:57:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
