<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Canada</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Canada</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Canada</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Canada</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Canada - Wikipedia</title><link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canada</link><description>It is one of the world's most ethnically diverse and multicultural nations, the product of large-scale immigration. Canada's long and complex relationship with the United States has had a significant impact on its history, economy, and culture.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 09:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Home - Canada.ca</title><link>https://www.canada.ca/en.html</link><description>Get quick, easy access to all Government of Canada services and information.</description><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 17:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada | History, Population, Immigration, Capital ...</title><link>https://www.britannica.com/place/Canada</link><description>Canada, the second largest country in the world in area, occupying roughly the northern two-fifths of the continent of North America. Despite Canada’s great size, it is one of the world’s most sparsely populated countries. It has crafted what many consider to be a model multicultural society.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 04:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada Maps &amp; Facts - World Atlas</title><link>https://www.worldatlas.com/maps/canada</link><description>Canada is the largest country in North America. Canada is bordered by non-contiguous US state of Alaska in the northwest and by 12 other US states in the south. The border of Canada with the US is the longest bi-national land border in the world.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 19:38:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada | Culture, Facts &amp; Travel | - CountryReports</title><link>https://www.countryreports.org/country/Canada.htm</link><description>Canada is the second largest country in the world in land area and has large mountain ranges and extensive coastlines. Tourist facilities are widely available in much of the country, but the northern and wilderness areas are less developed and facilities there can be vast distances apart.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 14:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada in Brief | Destination Canada - Media Centre</title><link>https://media.canada.travel/en-US/resources/canada-in-brief</link><description>Canada has 10 provinces and 3 territories: Alberta, British Columbia, Manitoba, New Brunswick, Newfoundland and Labrador, Nova Scotia, Nunavut, Ontario, Prince Edward Island, Quebec, Saskatchewan, The Northwest Territories and Yukon Territory.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 19:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Visit Canada | Official Travel Guide &amp; Information ...</title><link>https://travel.destinationcanada.com/en-us</link><description>Home of the True North strong and free, Canada is a wild wonderland of inspiring scenery, incredible experiences, and a vibrant cultural mosaic that spreads from coast to coast to coast.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:13:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
