<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Houston</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Houston</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Houston</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Houston</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Visit Houston Texas | Travel Guide for Tourist Attractions</title><link>https://www.visithoustontexas.com/</link><description>Discover top places to visit in Houston! Find amazing tourist spots and plan your perfect Texas getaway. Uncover HTX today!</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Things To Do in Houston, TX | Events, Shopping &amp; Nightlife</title><link>https://www.visithoustontexas.com/things-to-do/</link><description>Discover the best things to do in Houston, TX, from exciting events and shopping to vibrant nightlife and entertainment.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 02:56:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Houston TX Trip Planner | Your Guide to Travel &amp; Vacations</title><link>https://www.visithoustontexas.com/travel-planning/</link><description>Start planning your Houston getaway! Discover essential travel info, maps, itineraries, and tips for an unforgettable Texas experience.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 21:53:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Houston History &amp; Timeline - Houston Visitors Bureau</title><link>https://www.visithoustontexas.com/about-houston/history/</link><description>Discover Houston's history from its founders to present times. Find facts, timeline, community and culture from the official Houston visitors bureau.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 17:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Houston Attractions | Top Tourist Spots &amp; Local Activities</title><link>https://www.visithoustontexas.com/things-to-do/attractions/</link><description>Uncover the best places to visit in Houston! Explore parks, landmarks, unique sights, and museums. Plan your HTX adventure now!</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>About Houston, Texas | Community, Culture &amp; Neighborhoods</title><link>https://www.visithoustontexas.com/about-houston/</link><description>See for yourself, here in Houston, where much of daily life happens outdoors, thanks to mild, year-round temperatures. Take time to explore the eclectic, culture-filled neighborhoods, gallery spaces and attractions, which offer diverse flavors that can only be found here.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Houston Facts &amp; Figures | Find Population, Culture &amp; Industry Data</title><link>https://www.visithoustontexas.com/meetings/convention-kit/facts-and-figures/</link><description>Hollywood directors frequently film in Houston because of the vastly diverse terrain and unique locations found in the Greater Houston area, from the urban landscape seen in Jason’s Lyric and Reality Bites to the NASA favorites Apollo 13, Armageddon and Space Cowboys.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 19:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Houston Digital Visitor Guide | Request Travel Tips &amp; Info</title><link>https://www.visithoustontexas.com/travel-planning/visitor-guide-info/</link><description>Get Houston, Texas’ Digital Tourist Guide! Submit your info to access itineraries, travel tips, deals, &amp; everything you need for your trip.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 13:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Houston, Texas Trip Ideas | Travel &amp; Vacation Itineraries</title><link>https://www.visithoustontexas.com/travel-planning/trip-ideas/</link><description>Plan your Houston escape! Discover top experiences, itineraries, and hidden gems for couples, families, solo travelers, and first-timers.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 18:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Houston Restaurant Weeks 2025</title><link>https://www.visithoustontexas.com/taste-houston/trending/post/houston-restaurant-weeks/</link><description>As the fourth-largest city in the country, Houston is home to more than 70 countries and regions represented in its restaurants. During this month-long event, diners can experience a curated taste of that diversity while also supporting a great cause.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 18:12:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
