<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Kotor Montenegro</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Kotor+Montenegro</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Kotor Montenegro</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Kotor+Montenegro</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Kotor | Visit Montenegro</title><link>https://www.visit-montenegro.com/destinations/kotor/</link><description>A UNESCO world heritage site, the well preserved medieval walled town of Kotor sits at the foot of Mt. Lovćen at the southern end of the Boka Bay</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 07:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Old Town of Kotor - Visit Montenegro</title><link>https://www.visit-montenegro.com/destinations/kotor/attractions/old-town-kotor/</link><description>The old town of Kotor has a great number of monuments of the medieval architecture: churches, cathedrals, palaces, and museums. Its beauty is complemented with the multitude of narrow streets, squares, and markets.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 05:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kotor Attractions - Visit Montenegro</title><link>https://www.visit-montenegro.com/destinations/kotor/attractions/</link><description>The old town – that is the most famous part of Kotor, where the Kotor history, culture, and tradition are being preserved. The old town of Kotor has a great number of monuments of the medieval architecture: churches, cathedrals, palaces, and museums....</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:32:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The History of Kotor - Visit Montenegro</title><link>https://www.visit-montenegro.com/destinations/kotor/info/history/</link><description>The dynasty Nemanjic, names the town Kotor, and they make Kotor a seaport, through which they have maintained connections with the west. During the reign of the Serbian dynasty Nemanjic, Kotor experiences a significant economical as well as cultural boom.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Our Lady of the Rocks - Visit Montenegro</title><link>https://www.visit-montenegro.com/destinations/kotor/attractions/our-lady-of-the-rocks/</link><description>The Island Gospa od Skrpjela (Our Lady of the Rocks) is one of two gorgeous islands in the bay of Boka Kotorska, which are situated in the sea across Perast in the Kotor municipality. The other island, which also should be visited, is the Island Sveti Djordje.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>TOP 5 questions about KOTOR Montenegro | Visit Montenegro</title><link>https://www.visit-montenegro.com/news/kotor-montenegro/</link><description>Published on May 19, 2018 The Bay of Kotor is one of the unique natural attractions of the Mediterranean. Kotor is located at the end of Boka Bay; surrounded by mountains, notably Lovćen National Park, and the sea, it is no wonder it is officially one of the 25 most beautiful bays in the world.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 07:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Perast - Visit Montenegro</title><link>https://www.visit-montenegro.com/destinations/kotor/attractions/perast/</link><description>Its narrow streets and numerous, mostly abandoned renaissance, and baroque palaces, testify about the former richness of the Kotor bay, and about the days when there used to be led a luxurious life of its inhabitants.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:13:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Saint Tryphon Cathedral - Visit Montenegro</title><link>https://www.visit-montenegro.com/destinations/kotor/attractions/saint-tryphon-cathedral/</link><description>What is important for tourists to know is that the relics of Sveti Tripun (St. Tripun), who otherwise is the protector of Kotor, at the beginning of IX century, more precisely in 809, were brought from Carigrad (Istanbul), and until the cathedral was built they were placed in a small Kotor church.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 11:12:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Montenegro Travel Portal | Visit Montenegro</title><link>https://www.visit-montenegro.com/</link><description>If you are looking for a new destination that combines a variety of experiences, visit Montenegro and be amazed with its stunning nature, people and culture.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 15:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Events and Festivals - Visit Montenegro</title><link>https://www.visit-montenegro.com/montenegro/events-and-festivals/</link><description>Long prepared, boats cruise along the Kotor harbor to fascinate spectators and infect everyone with the contagiously festive atmosphere. Cheerful music makes everybody jig, fun inhabits Kotor and festive fireworks make this event dreamlike.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 17:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
