<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Scottish Borders</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Scottish+Borders</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Scottish Borders</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Scottish+Borders</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Scottish Fitba 2025-26: North of Heaven | Sons of Sam Horn</title><link>https://sonsofsamhorn.net/index.php?threads/scottish-fitba-2025-26-north-of-heaven.46556/</link><description>Celtic are already 2 points up on Rangers after the opening weekend. Meanwhile, Scotland's NT girds itself for WC qualifying beginning September 5th. Discuss all things Scottish fitba here!</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 10:49:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2025 PGA Tour | Sons of Sam Horn</title><link>https://sonsofsamhorn.net/index.php?threads/2025-pga-tour.44713/</link><description>Don't know how much it matters but January weekends are dominated by the NFL. The only signature event is the Pebble pro-am which is the week between the conference championship games and the Super Bowl. The ratings aren't good anyway but putting a signature event where the sponsor has ponied up big bucks up against NFL playoff games I'd imagine doesn't return much on the sponsor's investment.</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 22:13:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Scottish Fitba 2024-25: Many of Horror - Sons of Sam Horn</title><link>https://sonsofsamhorn.net/index.php?threads/scottish-fitba-2024-25-many-of-horror.42926/</link><description>Celtic win the Double but face valid criticisms about their caliber/style of play, as well as questions about talent development and acquisition. Things are murky looking forward, but since it's the SPL, they'll still finish top of the league or in second and compete for the two domestic cups...</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 08:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pats HoF 2025 | Sons of Sam Horn</title><link>https://sonsofsamhorn.net/index.php?threads/pats-hof-2025.45608/</link><description>I agree that Vinatieri and Edelman (and others) should get in ahead of him, but ignoring the circumstances Mankins faced in The Scottish Game is pretty insensitive, imo.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:21:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Super Bowl LIX Game Thread | Sons of Sam Horn</title><link>https://sonsofsamhorn.net/index.php?threads/super-bowl-lix-game-thread.44923/page-23</link><description>In fairness, TB12 never had blocking this poor in a Super Bowl. This is shades of Seahawks-Broncos. Maybe not this bad but my admittedly blocked out memories of the Scottish Game include the OL getting demolished.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 01:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2025 SoSH golf | Sons of Sam Horn</title><link>https://sonsofsamhorn.net/index.php?threads/2025-sosh-golf.45662/</link><description>On 17 I thought I hit my drive too far right and into the ocean only to find it on the green 15 feet from the hole. The links course is really good, very reminiscent of Scottish links courses. I'll see if I can add pics this evening.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2024/25 Europa League | Sons of Sam Horn</title><link>https://sonsofsamhorn.net/index.php?threads/2024-25-europa-league.43940/</link><description>I genuinely wonder if Rangers players find it hard to give a shit about non-OF Scottish games. The league's gone, Europe is their time in the shop window for the next move...</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:43:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Week 18 NFL Game Thread | Sons of Sam Horn</title><link>https://sonsofsamhorn.net/index.php?threads/week-18-nfl-game-thread.44710/page-2</link><description>The 70+ yard throw at the end of the Scottish Game that Moss nearly hauled in was one of the greatest cannon shots in the history of football. This would be a fun discussion. Feeling the pressure in the pocket and going down to the ground preemptively rather than getting destroyed and fumbling, or throwing a desperation interception.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 18:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Netflix Untold | Sons of Sam Horn</title><link>https://sonsofsamhorn.net/index.php?threads/netflix-untold.44643/</link><description>Has anyone watched the Untold Netflix documentary on the Michiga/Harbaugh scandal, Sign Stealer? Lerbon is an executive producer of this series. As a film, I thought it was decent, not great. But as a Pats fan there were certainly a lot of callbacks to Spygate and Deflategate– from the nature...</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 10:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Free Agency projections, 2025 | Sons of Sam Horn</title><link>https://sonsofsamhorn.net/index.php?threads/free-agency-projections-2025.47280/</link><description>Most sites that cover baseball will come out with free agency projections for the offseason. Tim Britton at the Athletic came out with his a couple days...</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
