<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Bing: Israel</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Israel</link><description>Search results</description><image><url>http://www.bing.com:80/s/a/rsslogo.gif</url><title>Israel</title><link>http://www.bing.com:80/search?q=Israel</link></image><copyright>Copyright © 2026 Microsoft. All rights reserved. These XML results may not be used, reproduced or transmitted in any manner or for any purpose other than rendering Bing results within an RSS aggregator for your personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of these results requires express written permission from Microsoft Corporation. By accessing this web page or using these results in any manner whatsoever, you agree to be bound by the foregoing restrictions.</copyright><item><title>Israel's neighbors condemn "de facto beginning" of West Bank ...</title><link>https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/world/israels-neighbors-condemn-de-facto-beginning-of-west-bank-annexation/ar-AA1Ws6Ap</link><description>Israel has approved numerous measures on the occupied West Bank seen widely as part of an effort by Netanyahu's government to annex the Palestinian territory.</description></item><item><title>Truth behind viral photo feeding conspiracy theory that ...</title><link>https://www.ladbible.com/news/us-news/jeffrey-epstein-photo-conspiracy-alive-israel-ai-662598-20260209</link><description>An alleged photo of Jeffrey Epstein walking around alive and well has finally been explained. Conspiracy theorists had a field day after the snap surfaced, with many believing that the disgraced ...</description></item><item><title>Trump calls Israel’s president ‘disgraceful’ for not ...</title><link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2026/2/12/trump-calls-israels-president-disgraceful-for-not-pardoning-netanyahu</link><description>Donald Trump has upped his pressure against Israel’s President Isaac Herzog as he seeks a pardon for his ally, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who is facing bribery charges. The United States ...</description></item><item><title>Iran’s military degraded by 12-day war with Israel, but still ...</title><link>https://www.timesofisrael.com/irans-military-degraded-by-12-day-war-with-israel-but-still-has-significant-capabilities/</link><description>Despite its losses to Israel and US, Tehran retains missiles, manpower and regional reach</description></item><item><title>Israel-Iran conflict</title><link>https://www.aljazeera.com/tag/israel-iran-conflict/</link><description>Stay on top of Israel-Iran conflict latest developments on the ground with Al Jazeera’s fact-based news, exclusive video footage, photos and updated maps.</description></item><item><title>Israel has joined Trump's 'Board of Peace,' Netanyahu says</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israel-join-trumps-board-peace-netanyahu-says-2026-02-12/</link><description>Israel has joined U.S. President Donald Trump's "Board of Peace" initiative, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Wednesday during his visit to Washington where he met Trump and Secretary of ...</description></item><item><title>Israel tightens grip on West Bank ahead of Netanyahu’s visit ...</title><link>https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/world/israel-tightens-grip-on-west-bank-ahead-of-netanyahu-s-visit-to-us/ar-AA1VVWd3</link><description>Ahead of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu’s visit to Washington, DC, this week, Israel has taken a series of sweeping steps to tighten its grip on the occupied West Bank.</description></item></channel></rss>
