<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FactCheck.org</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.factcheck.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.factcheck.org/</link>
	<description>A Project of The Annenberg Public Policy Center</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:14:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.8.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Trump and Musk Amplify Long-Ago Debunked  Mail-In Vote Fraud Claim</title>
		<link>https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/trump-and-musk-amplify-long-ago-debunked-mail-in-vote-fraud-claim/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert Farley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 16:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[FactCheck Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2020 Election]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.factcheck.org/?p=280246</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Mail-ballot.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Mail-ballot.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Mail-ballot-340x145.png 340w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />A social media post cited by Elon Musk to bolster his argument that mail-in voting should be curtailed, and which was subsequently amplified by President Donald Trump, makes the false and long-ago debunked claim that in the 2020 election, "Pennsylvania sent out 1,823,148 mail-in ballots but received back around 2.5 MILLION mail-in ballots."</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/trump-and-musk-amplify-long-ago-debunked-mail-in-vote-fraud-claim/">Trump and Musk Amplify Long-Ago Debunked  Mail-In Vote Fraud Claim</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Mail-ballot.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Mail-ballot.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Mail-ballot-340x145.png 340w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />
<p>A social media post cited by Elon Musk to bolster his argument that mail-in voting should be curtailed, and which was subsequently amplified by President Donald Trump, makes the false and long-ago debunked claim that in the 2020 election, &#8220;Pennsylvania sent out 1,823,148 mail-in ballots but received back around 2.5 MILLION mail-in ballots.&#8221;</p>



<p>As the Pennsylvania Department of State&#8217;s final <a href="https://www.pa.gov/content/dam/copapwp-pagov/en/dos/programs/voting-and-elections/2020-General-Election-Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">report</a> on the 2020 election shows, there were 2,673,272 mail-in ballot applications approved for the 2020 general election, so that&#8217;s how many were sent out. And of those, 2,273,490 votes were cast. (See charts 6.2 and 6.3 in the report.) Another 435,932 absentee ballots were also approved, and 374,659 of them were cast.</p>



<p>&#8220;This claim is based on mixing up statistics from the primary and the general election,&#8221; Charles Stewart III, director of the MIT Election Data and Science Lab, explained to us via email.</p>



<p>As online <a href="https://www.pa.gov/content/dam/copapwp-pagov/en/dos/resources/voting-and-elections/reports/2020-08-01-Act35Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pennsylvania records</a> show, there were roughly 1.8 million absentee and mail-in ballots approved for the <em>primary</em> election in 2020, nearly 1.5 million of which were cast. In other words, the post mixes up the number of mail-in ballots (including absentee ballots) sent out for the 2020 <em>primary</em> election and then cites approximately the number of mail-in ballots cast in the 2020 <em>general</em> election.</p>



<p>&#8220;These are long-ago debunked claims that will not disappear despite the availability of official data,&#8221; Stewart said. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">The Posts</h2>



<p>Trump has been making <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2025/08/factchecking-trumps-claims-about-mail-in-ballots-voting-machines-and-states-role/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">false and unfounded claims</a> related to <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2020/09/trumps-repeated-false-attacks-on-mail-in-ballots/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">mail-in voting</a> for years. And he has long called for <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-interview-larry-kudlow-fox-business-february-9-2023/#26" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ending mail-in voting</a> &#8220;other than if you&#8217;re in the military, or you&#8217;re sick, or you&#8217;re away, or some reasonable but good excuse,&#8221; as he said on Feb. 9.</p>



<p>Tesla and SpaceX CEO Musk, a former Trump adviser, agrees, according to a Feb. 8 <a href="https://x.com/LeadingReport/status/2020500166089089159" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">post</a> from an X account called The Leading Report: &#8220;Elon Musk calls for mail-in voting to be abolished nationwide except for troops overseas or a serious medical condition.&#8221; Musk reposted it and <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/2020521601872048305" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">commented</a>, &#8220;Critical to avoid fraud.&#8221;</p>



<p>The same day, The SCIF &#8212; an X account whose bio identifies the operator as a &#8220;Digital Operator, Creator and Intelligence Researcher&#8221; with the motto, &#8220;Truth is the most effective weapon in a war of information filled with lies&#8221; &#8212; weighed in with <a href="https://x.com/TheSCIF/status/2020570499743445054" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">an X post</a> that read: &#8220;Elon is right, banning mail-in voting is critical to avoiding fraud in our elections. During the 2020 election, Pennsylvania sent out 1,823,148 mail-in ballots but received back around 2.5 MILLION mail-in ballots. This accounts for Biden&#8217;s fraudulent and impossible 682,000+ vote spike, which were counted with NO observers and were all for Biden, which magically just happened to be enough to steal Trump&#8217;s almost 700,000 vote lead in PA before swing states shut down counting locations at the same time, to steal the 2020 election. PA&#8217;s own Secretary of State website then wiped the 2.5 MILLION mail-in ballot number after the total number was questioned. Trump won the 2020 election in a landslide.&#8221;</p>



<p>Musk <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/2020838047495995886" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reposted</a> that, and commented, &#8220;Essential to stop fraud in elections.&#8221; On Feb. 10, Trump reposted the claim and Musk&#8217;s response on <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/116046118344224496" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Truth Social</a>, without comment.</p>



<p>This latest criticism of mail-in voting comes as Congress considers the <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/119th-congress/house-bill/7296/text" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">SAVE America Act</a>, which would require voters to provide documentary proof of U.S. citizenship when registering to vote, and also photo identification to vote in federal elections. It would not abolish mail-in voting, but it would require a copy of identification to both request and submit a mail-in ballot.</p>



<p>Mail-in voting is widely used around the country. Eight states and Washington, D.C., conduct their elections mostly by mail, according to the <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/elections-and-campaigns/table-18-states-with-all-mail-elections" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">National Conference of State Legislatures</a>. Another 28 states &#8212; including Pennsylvania &#8212; offer <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/elections-and-campaigns/table-1-states-with-no-excuse-absentee-voting" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">&#8220;no excuse&#8221;</a> mail-in voting, meaning that any voter can request a mail-in ballot without needing to provide a reason. (Pennsylvania has both no-excuse mail-in ballots as well as absentee ballots for those who can&#8217;t make it to a polling place due to illness, disability, work or travel.)</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">The Origins</h2>



<p>The post claiming there were hundreds of thousands more mail-in ballots received than were actually sent out in Pennsylvania &#8212; a swing state that <a href="https://www.cnn.com/election/2020/results/president" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">broke for Biden</a> in 2020 &#8212; originated in a Nov. 25, 2020, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/ohe2dQbNJwM?si=f6jghzWFKIs5ZWXP&amp;t=4127" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hearing</a> held by Pennsylvania Senate Republicans (a video of which is attached to the post). During that hearing, then-Trump attorney Rudy Giuliani referred to Pennsylvania voting data and said, &#8220;Now this is the part that is a mystery. Mailed ballots sent out: 1,823,148. But when you go to the count of the final count of the vote, there are 2,589,242 mail-in ballots.&#8221; Giuliani asked witness Phil Waldron, a retired Army colonel, &#8220;How do you account for the 700,000 mail-in ballots that appeared from nowhere?&#8221;</p>



<p>Waldron, who has <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/phil-waldron-powerpoint-incited-jan-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">promoted</a> many unfounded theories about manipulated voting machines, speculated the voting machines may have been tampered with and called for a &#8220;detailed forensic analysis&#8221; of the voting machines used in Pennsylvania.</p>



<p>(Waldron later circulated a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/10/us/politics/capitol-attack-meadows-powerpoint.html?smid=tw-share" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PowerPoint</a> document to Trump allies that drew the attention of the House committee investigating the Jan. 6, 2021, attack on the Capitol. At the time, Democratic Rep. Bennie Thompson, chair of the panel, <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/phil-waldron-powerpoint-incited-jan-6/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">called</a> the document &#8220;an alarming blueprint for overturning a nationwide election.&#8221; According to the Jan. 6 <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/GPO-J6-REPORT/pdf/GPO-J6-REPORT.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">committee report</a>, Waldron was among those who &#8220;invoked their Fifth Amendment privilege against self-incrimination when asked by the Select Committee what supposed proof they uncovered that the election was stolen.&#8221;)</p>



<p>But again, the premise of Giuliani&#8217;s question was flawed. There were not more ballots returned in Pennsylvania than had been sent out. </p>



<p>&#8220;This is completely false,&#8221; Kathy Boockvar, who was the Pennsylvania secretary of the commonwealth at the time of the 2020 election, said in an email to us about the online claim. She explained the same thing at the time in a Dec. 16, 2020, <a href="https://www.pa.gov/content/dam/copapwp-pagov/en/dos/alerts-and-notices/statements/2020-12-16-Senator-Johnson-and-Peters.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">letter</a> to U.S. Sens. Ron Johnson and Gary Peters about similar claims.</p>



<p>All of the election data are, and were, in public records available online, and they contradict Giuliani&#8217;s claim.</p>



<p>The claim is also contradicted by the <a href="https://electproject.github.io/Early-Vote-2020G/PA.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">contemporaneous reporting</a> made to the U.S. Elections Project, a clearinghouse for voting data maintained by Mike McDonald, a professor at the University of Florida.</p>



<p>&#8220;The individual-level Pennsylvania 2020 mail ballot data I received on a daily basis from the Secretary of State’s office does not substantiate these allegations,&#8221; McDonald told us via email. &#8220;Pennsylvania election officials reported issuing a little over 3 million mail ballots during the COVID crisis, of which election officials accepted a little more than 2.6 million returned ballots.&#8221; Those figures include both mail-in and absentee ballots. </p>



<p>And the claim is further contradicted by news accounts <a href="https://www.nbcphiladelphia.com/news/politics/decision-2020/pennsylvania-mail-in-ballot-requests-hit-2-8-million-including-700000-gop-voters/2567670/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">before</a> the election that cited the correct number of ballot requests for the general election.</p>



<p>Indeed, the bogus claim was <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/factcheck/2020/11/28/fact-check-pennsylvania-ballot-claim-mixes-primary-general-election-data/6450032002/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">widely</a> <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/world/fact-check-post-mixes-pennsylvania-primary-and-general-election-data-to-suggest-idUSKBN28B5NM/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">debunked</a> at the time.</p>



<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s pretty unbelievable this is still being used,&#8221; <a href="https://seventy.org/staff-board">Eric Kraeutler</a>, a member of the board of directors and former chair of the Committee of Seventy, a Philadelphia-based election watchdog, told us in a phone interview. &#8220;They mixed up data for these two separate elections (the 2020 primary and general elections). &#8230; As far as we&#8217;re concerned, this was disposed of five or six years ago.&#8221;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><em>Editor’s note:&nbsp;FactCheck.org does not accept advertising. We rely on grants and individual donations from people like you. Please consider a donation. Credit card donations may be made through&nbsp;<a href="https://giving.aws.cloud.upenn.edu/?fastStart=simpleForm&amp;program=ANS&amp;fund=602014" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our “Donate” page</a>. If you prefer to give by check, send to: FactCheck.org, Annenberg Public Policy Center, P.O. Box 58100, Philadelphia, PA 19102.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/trump-and-musk-amplify-long-ago-debunked-mail-in-vote-fraud-claim/">Trump and Musk Amplify Long-Ago Debunked  Mail-In Vote Fraud Claim</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump Oversells Recent U.S. Economic Growth</title>
		<link>https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/trump-oversells-recent-u-s-economic-growth/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[D'Angelo Gore]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 22:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[FactCheck Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured Posts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.factcheck.org/?p=280190</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shopping-720-x-307.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shopping-720-x-307.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shopping-720-x-307-340x145.png 340w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />In the second and third quarters of 2025, the U.S. economy grew at its fastest pace in two years. Those growth rates were not "numbers unheard of," or figures the U.S. "never had" before, as President Donald Trump has claimed.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/trump-oversells-recent-u-s-economic-growth/">Trump Oversells Recent U.S. Economic Growth</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shopping-720-x-307.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shopping-720-x-307.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shopping-720-x-307-340x145.png 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />
<p>In the second and third quarters of 2025, the U.S. economy grew at its fastest pace in two years. Those growth rates were not &#8220;numbers unheard of,&#8221; or figures the U.S. &#8220;never had&#8221; before, as President Donald Trump has claimed.</p>



<p>In addition, economic experts told us that federal data do not support Trump&#8217;s claim that there was economic &#8220;stagflation&#8221; during the Biden administration and “the complete opposite” during Trump’s first year back in office. Inflation was high during much of Joe Biden&#8217;s presidency, but economic growth was not stagnant, another key indicator of stagflation, the experts said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They also said that Trump’s tariff policies likely hindered economic growth, rather than helped spur it, as the president has suggested.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Trump made those claims while touting the U.S. economy in recent speeches and remarks, as well as in a late January opinion piece written for the Wall Street Journal.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">Economic Growth</h2>



<p>During a Jan. 27 <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-speech-economy-energy-clive-iowa-january-27-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">speech</a> in Iowa, Trump said, “So, under my leadership, economic growth is exploding to numbers unheard of. They&#8217;ve never had them before.”</p>



<p>He later said in <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-interview-tom-llamas-nbc-news-february-4-2026/#365" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">an interview</a> with NBC News on <a href="https://youtu.be/rT6eucDVmFY?si=ruC7Zho8b2Zj1sKU&amp;t=16" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Feb. 4</a>, “We have low inflation and we have tremendous growth. You haven&#8217;t had these numbers like this.”</p>



<p>And when claiming to have achieved &#8220;unprecedented&#8221; growth numbers in a Jan. 29 Cabinet <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-remarks-cabinet-meeting-january-29-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">meeting</a> at the White House, Trump said that if not for the <a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2025/11/12/congress/trump-signs-bill-ending-longest-government-shutdown-in-us-history-00650189" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">43-day</a> federal government shutdown last fall,<strong> “</strong>we would have picked up about a point and a half more than [the] already high numbers, record setting numbers.”</p>



<p>While the U.S. economy grew significantly in the second and third quarters of 2025, <a href="https://perma.cc/9DQR-APL2" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to</a> the most recent data from the Bureau of Economic Analysis, the numbers did not set records, as Trump claimed.</p>



<p>After declining by an annualized rate of <a href="https://www.bea.gov/sites/default/files/2026-01/gdp3q25-updated.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">0.6%</a> in the first quarter of 2025, which covers the three months from January to March, real gross domestic product (meaning it has been adjusted for inflation) grew at an annualized rate of 3.8% in the second quarter of 2025 and at a rate of 4.4% in the third quarter. Those were the largest quarterly increases since the third quarter of 2023, under Biden, when the economy expanded at an annualized rate of 4.7%, <a href="https://apps.bea.gov/iTable/?reqid=19&amp;step=2&amp;isuri=1&amp;categories=survey&amp;_gl=1*sn2p5o*_ga*MjA0NDMwMzg2OS4xNzY2MTc1OTM5*_ga_J4698JNNFT*czE3NzA4MTMzNjIkbzE2JGcxJHQxNzcwODEzNjI4JGo1NiRsMCRoMA..#eyJhcHBpZCI6MTksInN0ZXBzIjpbMSwyLDNdLCJkYXRhIjpbWyJjYXRlZ29yaWVzIiwiU3VydmV5Il0sWyJOSVBBX1RhYmxlX0xpc3QiLCIxIl1dfQ==" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to</a> BEA estimates.</p>



<p>The record for quarterly growth is 34.9% in the third quarter of 2020, which happened right after the economy shrunk by 28% at the start of the COVID-19 pandemic. The pre-pandemic quarterly growth record is 16.7% in the first quarter of 1950, <a href="https://apps.bea.gov/iTable/?reqid=19&amp;step=2&amp;isuri=1&amp;categories=survey&amp;_gl=1*sn2p5o*_ga*MjA0NDMwMzg2OS4xNzY2MTc1OTM5*_ga_J4698JNNFT*czE3NzA4MTMzNjIkbzE2JGcxJHQxNzcwODEzNjI4JGo1NiRsMCRoMA..#eyJhcHBpZCI6MTksInN0ZXBzIjpbMSwyLDNdLCJkYXRhIjpbWyJjYXRlZ29yaWVzIiwiU3VydmV5Il0sWyJOSVBBX1RhYmxlX0xpc3QiLCIxIl1dfQ==" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to</a> BEA quarterly data going back to 1947.</p>



<div style="position: relative; width: 100%; height: 0px; padding: 105.57% 0px 0px; overflow: hidden; will-change: transform;"><iframe loading="lazy" style="position: absolute; width: 100%; height: 100%; top: 0px; left: 0px; border: medium; padding: 0px; margin: 0px;" src="https://e.infogram.com/_/dQjFCjhCnlmV1AC9YkHd?src=embed&amp;embed_type=responsive_iframe" title="Feb2026: Real GDP Quarterly Growth" allowfullscreen="" allow="fullscreen"></iframe></div>



<p>On <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-interview-larry-kudlow-fox-business-february-9-2023/#121" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">several</a> <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-speech-world-economic-forum-davos-january-21-2026/#4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">occasions</a>, Trump has said that fourth quarter growth is projected to be 5.4%, a figure that he has <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-remarks-cabinet-meeting-january-29-2026/#14">attributed</a> to the Federal Reserve Bank in Atlanta. But that projection is now out of date.</p>



<p>Throughout much of January,&nbsp;the Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta&#8217;s GDPNow model <a href="https://www.atlantafed.org/research-and-data/data/gdpnow/archive-of-past-gdpnow-commentaries" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">was projecting</a> growth of 5.4% for the fourth quarter of 2025. Then, on Jan. 29, the projection lowered to 4.2%, and, as of Feb. 10, it was down again, to 3.7% projected growth.</p>



<p>The BEA is <a href="http://www.bea.gov/news/schedule" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">scheduled</a> to release its advanced estimate of GDP for the fourth quarter, and all of 2025, on Feb. 20.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">Stagflation</h2>



<p>Trump also has claimed that he turned around an economy that had stalled under Biden.</p>



<p>&#8220;Under the Biden administration, America was plagued by the nightmare of stagflation, meaning low growth and high inflation, a recipe for misery, failure and decline. But now, after just one year of my policies, we are witnessing the exact opposite – virtually no inflation and extraordinarily high economic growth,&#8221; Trump <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-speech-world-economic-forum-davos-january-21-2026/#4">said</a> at a World Economic Forum meeting on Jan. 21.</p>



<p>He repeated the &#8220;stagflation&#8221; claim in his Jan. 30 <a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/donald-j-trump-my-tariffs-have-brought-america-back-2248391b?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=AWEtsqdujoYASVpXAKhWH0d8VpV3RR2tTIi7QAPZ6qpGWfoFQhykKbCtEOKJDks8oBw%3D&amp;gaa_ts=698620ab&amp;gaa_sig=Q0bYrtOcyojXwvt8kueM4jmyxBippiMnrV5ItFSvhL7eaJM7JW_yPnIhiII02V46MYjeRy3WB2sN-BQEp75tCA%3D%3D">opinion piece</a> published in the Wall Street Journal.</p>



<p>But economists told us that the U.S. economy under Biden did not experience stagflation, which has a specific economic meaning.</p>



<p>“It refers to a sustained period of high inflation combined with weak or stagnant real economic growth, typically alongside rising unemployment,” <a href="https://gps.ucsd.edu/faculty-directory/kyle-handley.html">Kyle Handley</a>, a professor of economics at the University of California, San Diego, told us in an email. “By that definition, the U.S. economy during the Biden years does not qualify as stagflation.”</p>



<p>Handley said that the <a href="https://www.bls.gov/charts/consumer-price-index/consumer-price-index-by-category-line-chart.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">annual inflation rate</a> did “rise sharply” during Biden’s first two years in office. It peaked in June 2022, at 9.1%, before declining dramatically in Biden’s last two years in office.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“However, real GDP growth during the Biden presidency was positive and often above trend, and unemployment remained historically low,” Handley said. “Real GDP grew strongly in 2021 during the post-pandemic recovery, slowed in 2022 as monetary policy tightened, and then re-accelerated in 2023 and 2024. That is not a period of economic stagnation.”</p>



<p>In an <a href="https://www.clevelandfed.org/collections/infographics/2025/infogr-20251117-stagflation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">infographic</a> from November, the staff of the Federal Reserve Bank of Cleveland wrote that the “last major case” of stagflation in the U.S. “occurred in the mid-1970s, when global crude oil prices surged, triggering widespread rises in other prices and fueling inflation of more than 12 percent and unemployment that peaked at 9 percent.” The infographic said that stagflation &#8212; the combination of rising unemployment and inflation, and slowing economic growth all at the same time &#8212; was &#8220;rare&#8221; and &#8220;an unusual pattern.&#8221;</p>



<p>When we asked about the basis for the president&#8217;s stagflation claim, a White House spokesperson told us that &#8220;[r]eal wages shrank markedly during the Biden presidency, and growth – once you put aside the early bit of Biden admin when Democrat state officials finally started lifting unscientific and draconian lockdowns – was tepid with inflation at 40-year highs.&#8221;</p>



<p>There was a decrease in real wages under Biden, <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2025/10/bidens-final-numbers/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">as we&#8217;ve written</a>. But the economy grew by well over 2% each year during his administration, and the rate of inflation, while still elevated, was not near a 40-year high when he left office. The 9.1% annual rate in June 2022 was the highest since <a href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/archives/cpi_07132022.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">November 1981</a>.<strong> </strong>The rate was 3% in Biden&#8217;s final 12 months.</p>



<div style="position: relative; width: 100%; height: 0px; padding: 108.43% 0px 0px; overflow: hidden; will-change: transform;"><iframe loading="lazy" style="position: absolute; width: 100%; height: 100%; top: 0px; left: 0px; border: medium; padding: 0px; margin: 0px;" src="https://e.infogram.com/_/Ao0rcu0nqIXjzB1reTtD?src=embed&amp;embed_type=responsive_iframe" title="RB: U.S. Inflation" allowfullscreen="" allow="fullscreen"></iframe></div>



<p>The unemployment rate also decreased under Biden, going from 6.4% when he was inaugurated to 4% in his last month, <a href="https://data.bls.gov/timeseries/LNS14000000" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to</a> the Bureau of Labor Statistics. The average monthly rate for Biden’s presidency was 4.1%, below the historical average. </p>



<div style="position: relative; width: 100%; height: 0px; padding: 100% 0px 0px; overflow: hidden; will-change: transform;"><iframe loading="lazy" style="position: absolute; width: 100%; height: 100%; top: 0px; left: 0px; border: medium; padding: 0px; margin: 0px;" src="https://e.infogram.com/_/WjPVYXJcVlMmQmHMy4jd?src=embed&amp;embed_type=responsive_iframe" title="RB: Unemployment Rate 2021 to Present" allowfullscreen="" allow="fullscreen"></iframe></div>



<p>“You had high inflation, yes, but paired with strong growth and a robust labor market,” <a href="https://economics.wfu.edu/faculty-and-staff/aeimit-k-lakdawala/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Aeimit Lakdawala</a>, an associate professor of economics at Wake Forest University, told us in an email. &#8220;That&#8217;s just not stagflation by any standard definition of the term.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>He said that Trump’s claim of engineering a complete turnaround from the Biden economy is an overstatement.</p>



<p>“What we&#8217;re really seeing is a continuation of trends that were already well underway before Trump took office in January 2025,” Lakdawala said.</p>



<p>He noted that the annual inflation rate had cooled to 3% when Trump’s second term started. It had been as low as 2.4% in September 2024.</p>



<p>“That disinflation happened under Biden, driven largely by the resolution of supply chain issues and Fed monetary policy,” he said, referring to the Federal Reserve. “Under Trump&#8217;s second term so far, inflation has averaged about 2.7%. That&#8217;s modestly lower, but it&#8217;s not a dramatic reversal.”</p>



<p>Although Trump considers the 2.7% annual inflation rate, as of December, to be “very low” or “virtually no inflation,” it is still above the <a href="https://www.richmondfed.org/publications/research/econ_focus/2024/q1_q2_federal_reserve" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2% target</a> set by the Federal Reserve. Prices are still increasing, just at a slightly slower pace than before he became president again.</p>



<p>As for economic growth, Lakdawala said that the increase in real GDP has “averaged about 2.5% annualized so far under Trump&#8217;s second term, which is solid but actually a touch lower than the 2.9% we saw” in Biden’s last two years as president.</p>



<p>“So characterizing this as &#8216;extraordinarily high economic growth&#8217; is a stretch,” he said about Trump’s claim. “It&#8217;s good growth, roughly in line with where we&#8217;ve been.”</p>



<p>The unemployment rate, meanwhile, was 4.3% in January, slightly higher than when Trump took office. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">Tariff Effect</h2>



<p>In his Wall Street Journal <a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/donald-j-trump-my-tariffs-have-brought-america-back-2248391b?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=AWEtsqdujoYASVpXAKhWH0d8VpV3RR2tTIi7QAPZ6qpGWfoFQhykKbCtEOKJDks8oBw%3D&amp;gaa_ts=698620ab&amp;gaa_sig=Q0bYrtOcyojXwvt8kueM4jmyxBippiMnrV5ItFSvhL7eaJM7JW_yPnIhiII02V46MYjeRy3WB2sN-BQEp75tCA%3D%3D" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">opinion piece</a>, Trump said that the &#8220;entire Trump economic agenda deserves credit for this explosion of growth&#8221; &#8212; but he specifically gave credit for the country&#8217;s &#8220;economic success&#8221; to his tariff policies.</p>



<p>&#8220;We have proven, decisively, that, properly applied, tariffs do not hurt growth — they promote growth and greatness, just as I said all along,&#8221; the opinion piece said.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="400" height="267" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shopping-400-x-267.png" alt="" class="wp-image-280256" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shopping-400-x-267.png 400w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shopping-400-x-267-217x145.png 217w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Shoppers wait in line at a grocery store on Jan. 23 in Lenexa, Kansas. Photo by Chase Castor/Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>But the experts we consulted told us that the economy likely grew despite the tariffs, not because of them.</p>



<p>&#8220;Year-over-year real GDP growth over the past year looks similar to the years immediately preceding the new tariffs,” Handley said. “Outside of the pandemic period, growth has been relatively stable across administrations, which makes it difficult to attribute recent performance to tariffs rather than economic momentum.”</p>



<p>He noted that the tariffs that Trump placed on imported foreign goods last year were not as high as the rates he originally proposed, and that tariff revenue, which did increase significantly in 2025, is still quite small in relation to GDP (about 1% of GDP as of the third quarter of 2025, <a href="https://fredblog.stlouisfed.org/2025/07/the-evolution-of-import-tariffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to</a> the Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis).</p>



<p>&#8220;By construction, a policy of that size cannot plausibly explain an increase in aggregate economic growth,&#8221; he said.</p>



<p>Lakdawala had a similar take.</p>



<p>&#8220;Crediting tariffs for economic growth gets the causation backwards,” he said. “The economics on this is fairly clear and there is broad consensus among economists: tariffs are essentially a tax on imports that raises costs for domestic consumers and businesses. If anything, they&#8217;ve been a modest drag on growth, not a driver of it.&#8221;</p>



<p>He pointed to an analysis done by the Budget Lab at Yale, a nonpartisan research center, that said that in 2025 tariffs <a href="https://budgetlab.yale.edu/research/state-us-tariffs-november-17-2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">slowed</a> real GDP growth by 0.5 percentage points and increased the unemployment rate by 0.3 percentage points. The Budget Lab <a href="https://budgetlab.yale.edu/research/state-us-tariffs-january-19-2026" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">estimated</a> that tariffs will reduce real GDP growth by 0.4 percentage points in 2026, and said that &#8220;[i]n the long run, the US economy is persistently 0.3% smaller, the equivalent of $100 billion annually in 2025 dollars,&#8221; because of tariffs.</p>



<p>&#8220;These aren&#8217;t catastrophic numbers and the economy is resilient and has absorbed the tariff shock reasonably well,” Lakdawala said. “But they clearly point in the wrong direction for someone trying to credit tariffs with economic success.”</p>



<p>The pro-business Tax Foundation also <a href="https://taxfoundation.org/research/all/federal/trump-tariffs-trade-war/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> that Trump&#8217;s imposed tariffs, if the Supreme Court rules that some of them can remain in effect, &#8220;will raise $2.0 trillion in revenue from 2026-2035 on a conventional basis and reduce US GDP by 0.5 percent, all before foreign retaliation&#8221; from other countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The White House told us that, under Trump, the &#8220;[a]nnualized rate of inflation has been trending in the mid-twos and GDP growth in Q3 surpassed expectations by over a full point, hitting above 4 percent. Largely driven by the investments we are seeing thanks in part to tariffs.&#8221;</p>



<p>But Handley noted that many of the investments <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2025/12/factchecking-trumps-economic-speech/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">touted</a> by Trump are &#8220;announcements rather than realized outcomes.&#8221;</p>



<p>&#8220;Foreign investment commitments do not directly enter GDP, and they often reflect projects planned years in advance,&#8221; he said, adding that some of the pledges made by foreign countries and companies “may never come to fruition.&#8221;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve already <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2025/12/factchecking-trumps-economic-speech/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">written</a> that Trump&#8217;s claim that he has brought in about $18 trillion in investments to the U.S. is exaggerated, according to experts and a White House webpage.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.fordham.edu/academics/departments/economics/faculty/giacomo-santangelo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Giacomo Santangelo</a>, a senior lecturer of economics at Fordham University, told us in an interview that consumption is the &#8220;largest portion&#8221; of GDP, and that people are currently taking on more debt to finance that spending. &#8220;That&#8217;s what&#8217;s driving this economy,&#8221; he said.</p>



<p>Joseph Brusuelas, chief economist at RSM, <a href="https://perma.cc/Y3SZ-YAXA" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote</a> in December that the third-quarter growth was due to “[h]ousehold consumption driven by higher-income consumers and AI-related investment,” which he said “accounted for just under 70% of total growth during the [third] quarter.”</p>



<p>In its <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20260211111251/https://www.bea.gov/news/2026/gross-domestic-product-3rd-quarter-2025-updated-estimate-gdp-industry-and-corporate" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">news release</a> about third-quarter growth in 2025, the BEA said, &#8220;The increase in real GDP in the third quarter reflected increases in consumer spending, exports, government spending, and investment.&#8221; For the second quarter, the BEA <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20260205035612/https://www.bea.gov/news/2025/gross-domestic-product-2nd-quarter-2025-third-estimate-gdp-industry-corporate-profits" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> the increase &#8220;primarily reflected a decrease in imports, which are a subtraction in the calculation of GDP, and an increase in consumer spending.&#8221;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><em>Editor’s note: FactCheck.org does not accept advertising. We rely on grants and individual donations from people like you. Please consider a donation. Credit card donations may be made through <a href="https://giving.aws.cloud.upenn.edu/?fastStart=simpleForm&amp;program=ANS&amp;fund=602014" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our “Donate” page</a>. If you prefer to give by check, send to: FactCheck.org, Annenberg Public Policy Center, P.O. Box 58100, Philadelphia, PA 19102. </em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/trump-oversells-recent-u-s-economic-growth/">Trump Oversells Recent U.S. Economic Growth</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WHO Didn’t Recommend Lockdowns, Contrary to Health Officials&#8217; Suggestions</title>
		<link>https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/who-didnt-recommend-lockdowns-contrary-to-health-officials-suggestions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jessica McDonald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 20:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[FactCheck Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SciCheck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.factcheck.org/?p=280158</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shutdown-720-x-307.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shutdown-720-x-307.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shutdown-720-x-307-340x145.png 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />As the U.S. formally exited from the World Health Organization last month, Trump administration officials misleadingly claimed that the WHO “pushed” or “promoted” lockdowns during the COVID-19 pandemic. The group did not explicitly recommend lockdowns, although it also did not advise countries not to implement them. It said it recognized that the measures might be needed in some cases.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/who-didnt-recommend-lockdowns-contrary-to-health-officials-suggestions/">WHO Didn’t Recommend Lockdowns, Contrary to Health Officials&#8217; Suggestions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shutdown-720-x-307.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shutdown-720-x-307.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shutdown-720-x-307-340x145.png 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />
<p>As the U.S. formally exited from the World Health Organization last month, Trump administration officials misleadingly claimed that the WHO “pushed” or “promoted” lockdowns during the COVID-19 pandemic. The group did not explicitly recommend lockdowns, although it also did not advise countries not to implement them. It said it recognized that the measures might be needed in some cases.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft"><img decoding="async" data-pin-description="RFK Jr. Misleads on Autism Prevalence, Causes - FactCheck.org" data-pin-title="The Facts Behind Claims on Autism, Tylenol and Folate - FactCheck.org" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/SciCHECKsquare_4-161x145.png" alt=""/></figure></div>


<p>More than six years after the start of the COVID-19 pandemic, federal health officials are spinning the facts about the WHO as part of their justification to leave the organization. The U.S.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2025/01/qa-on-trumps-impending-exit-from-the-world-health-organization/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">formally exited</a>&nbsp;the WHO on Jan. 22, a year after giving notice to do so, much to the chagrin of many in public health.</p>



<p>The WHO “ignored rigorous science and promoted lockdowns,” Acting Centers for Disease Control and Prevention Director Jim O’Neill&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://x.com/HHS_Jim/status/2014533604010024980">wrote</a>&nbsp;on the day of the exit in an X post that also made claims about Taiwan.</p>



<p>The same day, National Institutes of Health Director Dr. Jay Bhattacharya similarly said in an&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lnNsfrMXsEo&amp;t=1s">interview</a>&nbsp;on Fox News that the WHO “absolutely failed during the pandemic … pushing, still to this day … lockdown policies that plagued Americans for years.”</p>



<p>Those comments led to contentious exchanges with WHO officials who have taken issue with the statements.</p>



<p>“All untrue,”&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://x.com/mvankerkhove">Maria Van Kerkhove</a>, an infectious disease epidemiologist and the WHO’s technical lead for COVID-19, responded to O’Neill in a Jan. 24&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://x.com/mvankerkhove/status/2015061936820322354">post</a>, adding, “we don&#8217;t ignore science and WHO never recommended lockdowns.”</p>



<p>The WHO also pushed back in a Jan. 24&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.who.int/news/item/24-01-2026-who-statement-on-notification-of-withdrawal-of-the-united-states">statement</a>, writing, “WHO recommended the use of masks, vaccines and physical distancing, but at no stage recommended mask mandates, vaccine mandates or lockdowns. We supported sovereign governments to make decisions they believed were in the best interests of their people, but the decisions were theirs.”</p>



<p>The dispute recalls a similar situation in October 2020 when President Donald Trump, then in his first term, incorrectly said that the WHO had “just admitted” that he was “right” about lockdowns. Trump had criticized lockdowns, saying they were “worse than the problem itself.&#8221; Trump was in office at the height of the pandemic when COVID-19 restrictions in the U.S. were the most stringent.</p>



<p>As we wrote&nbsp;<a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2020/10/trump-distorts-whos-lockdown-comments/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">then</a>, the WHO’s position on lockdowns had always been more nuanced &#8212; the group neither recommended the measures nor advised against them, saying it recognized that lockdowns can harm society but are sometimes necessary.</p>



<p>The organization did at times praise China’s aggressive response, and supported countries in their decisions, which could be interpreted as an implicit endorsement of the measures. But it’s an oversimplification to say that the WHO “pushed” or “promoted” lockdowns. We did not find evidence that the WHO explicitly recommended them, consistent with the organization’s statements.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="400" height="267" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shutdown-400-x-267.png" alt="" class="wp-image-280183" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shutdown-400-x-267.png 400w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Shutdown-400-x-267-217x145.png 217w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A candy store in downtown Patchogue, New York, that was an early casualty of the coronavirus pandemic. Photo by Steve Pfost/Newsday via Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>We reached out to the NIH to ask about Bhattacharya’s comments and to the CDC to ask about O’Neill’s, but did not receive a reply. The WHO pointed us to a Q&amp;A&nbsp;<a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/questions-and-answers/item/herd-immunity-lockdowns-and-covid-19" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">post</a>&nbsp;&#8212; last updated Dec. 31, 2020 &#8212; that we also previously referenced, which notes that so-called “lockdown” measures can work to slow viral transmission but can have “a profound negative impact,” especially for disadvantaged groups.</p>



<p>“WHO recognizes that at certain points, some countries have had no choice but to issue stay-at-home orders and other measures, to buy time,” the post continues, adding that “WHO is hopeful that countries will use targeted interventions where and when needed, based on the local situation.”</p>



<p>Similar language also appears in an April 2020 WHO <a href="https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/coronaviruse/covid-strategy-update-14april2020.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">document</a>, which states there is an &#8220;urgent need&#8221; to transition away from lockdown measures, but also cautions that premature lifting of restrictions without careful planning is likely to lead to an uncontrolled surge in COVID-19 cases.</p>



<p>It’s worth noting that there is&nbsp;<a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2022/03/scicheck-what-weve-learned-about-so-called-lockdowns-and-the-covid-19-pandemic/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">no unified definition</a>&nbsp;of what “lockdowns” are. While they generally refer to what the WHO&nbsp;<a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/questions-and-answers/item/herd-immunity-lockdowns-and-covid-19" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">terms</a>&nbsp;“large scale physical distancing measures and movement restrictions,” they varied greatly in scope and severity in different countries during the COVID-19 pandemic. The U.S. version &#8212; which at its most restrictive involved stay-at-home orders and school and business closures, implemented by states and local governments &#8212; was far lighter than measures imposed in China, for example. </p>



<p>In some parts of China, residents at times could not leave their cities, were <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2020/02/21/806958341/restrictions-and-rewards-how-china-is-locking-down-half-a-billion-citizens" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">not allowed</a> to use their own cars and needed permission to leave their apartments. In the U.S., there was never a federal lockdown, although the Trump administration <a href="https://trumpwhitehouse.archives.gov/articles/15-days-slow-spread/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">issued</a> <a href="https://trumpwhitehouse.archives.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/03.16.20_coronavirus-guidance_8.5x11_315PM.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">guidelines</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/29/us/politics/trump-coronavirus-guidelines.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">that</a> told people to avoid large gatherings and encouraged school and nonessential business closures early in the pandemic. </p>



<p>&#8220;My administration is recommending that all Americans, including the young and healthy, work to engage in schooling from home when possible. Avoid gathering in groups of more than 10 people. Avoid discretionary travel. And avoid eating and drinking at bars, restaurants, and public food courts,&#8221; Trump <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-press-conference-coronavirus-briefing-march-16-2020/#76" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> on March 16, 2020, when announcing the government&#8217;s &#8220;15 Days to Slow the Spread,&#8221; which was later extended. On March 23, 2020, Trump <a href="https://trumpwhitehouse.archives.gov/briefings-statements/remarks-president-trump-vice-president-pence-members-coronavirus-task-force-press-briefing-9/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> that &#8220;America will again, and soon, be open for business — very soon.&#8221;</p>



<p>The word &#8220;lockdown&#8221; has sometimes <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10110335/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">erroneously been applied</a> to any public health measure, even those that don’t limit social interactions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><strong>Contentious Exchanges</strong></h2>



<p>In response to Van Kerkhove’s post about O’Neill, Bhattacharya pointed to some text of the WHO-China Joint Mission&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/coronaviruse/who-china-joint-mission-on-covid-19---final-report-1100hr-28feb2020-11mar-update.pdf">report</a>&nbsp;in February 2020, and&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://x.com/DrJBhattacharya/status/2015071416966631650">wrote</a>, “That is just plain false. The WHO mission to China in 2020 lauded the Chinese lockdown as a success, in effect endorsing the model for the rest of the world.”</p>



<p>The text he cited stated that the measures employed in China &#8212; at their core, proactive surveillance, rapid diagnosis and case isolation and tracking and quarantine of close contacts &#8212; “are the only measures that are currently proven to interrupt or minimize transmission” of the coronavirus. “Given the damage that can be caused by uncontrolled, community-level transmission of this virus, such an approach is warranted to save lives and to gain the weeks and months needed for the testing of therapeutics and vaccine development,” the report added.</p>



<p>Van Kerkhove, however,&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://x.com/mvankerkhove/status/2015076737999077657">replied</a>: “What you’re reading here is that we acknowledged that governments had to take tough decisions to protect their populations, but lockdowns were never recommended, nor were they a policy recommendation by @WHO.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finishing the exchange, Bhattacharya&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://x.com/DrJBhattacharya/status/2015080861050257443">wrote</a>: “What I&#8217;m not reading here is a condemnation of lockdowns at a time where governments worldwide were seriously considering them. If you want the world to trust the WHO, take honest ownership of this failure.”</p>



<p>Bhattacharya has also objected to statements from the WHO’s leader, Director-General Dr.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.who.int/director-general/tedros-adhanom-ghebreyesus" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus</a>, who had responded to an X post from Health and Human Services Secretary Robert F. Kennedy Jr.,&nbsp;<a href="https://x.com/DrTedros/status/2015065682266800417" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">saying</a>&nbsp;that the HHS statement “contains inaccurate information” and that the WHO “never recommended lockdowns.”</p>



<p>“That is just deeply dishonest,” Bhattacharya&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://x.com/DrJBhattacharya/status/2015078563918000598">wrote</a>&nbsp;in a Jan. 24 X post. “If the WHO opposed lockdowns, where was the WHO condemnation of them in 2020 or 2021? Or of China&#8217;s lockdowns in 2022?”</p>



<p>A day later, Bhattacharya posted a&nbsp;<a href="https://x.com/DrJBhattacharya/status/2015461278563598359" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">thread</a>&nbsp;with what he called “receipts” of evidence that the WHO is wrong, which included statements from the WHO about what countries should ideally do before lifting lockdown measures.</p>



<p>The disagreement between U.S. and WHO officials partly comes down to semantics.&nbsp;Bhattacharya is correct that the WHO mission praised China&#8217;s response &#8212; and that the group did not come out against lockdowns. But Van Kerkhove and the WHO have not claimed to have done so. Moreover, not opposing lockdowns is different from recommending them.</p>



<p>“WHO neither recommended nor categorically opposed lockdowns,” Van Kerkhove told us in an email responding to questions about the claims. “We recommended a comprehensive risk-based approach including surveillance, contact tracing, testing, quarantine (for those infected), isolation (for contacts), physical distancing, the use of masks/respirators, personal protective equipment for health workers, improved ventilation, vaccines, therapeutics and more. At the same time, we acknowledged that in some circumstances, countries felt they had no choice but to introduce lockdowns to prevent their health systems being overwhelmed resulting in more lives lost. We respected that choice, as it was their sovereign right, but we said that lockdowns should not be used as the primary or default strategy for controlling COVID-19, and highlighted their serious social and economic consequences.”</p>



<p>“We did say, repeatedly and clearly, that lockdowns came with risks and potential harms, and that they were not a sustainable solution,” she added.</p>



<p>She <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/speeches/item/who-director-general-s-opening-remarks-at-the-media-briefing-on-covid-19---17-july-2020" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pointed</a> <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/speeches/item/who-director-general-s-opening-remarks-at-the-media-briefing-on-covid-19---21-august-2020" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">to</a> <a href="https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/coronaviruse/transcripts/covid-19-virtual-press-conference---21-august.pdf?sfvrsn=ada7ae85_0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">multiple</a> <a href="https://reliefweb.int/report/world/who-director-generals-opening-remarks-member-states-briefing-covid-19-25-february-2021" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">examples</a> <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/speeches/item/who-director-general-s-opening-remarks-at-the-media-briefing-on-covid-19---1-february-2022" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">of</a> <a href="https://pmnch.who.int/docs/librariesprovider9/meeting-reports/lives-in-the-balance-1-tedros-speech.pdf?sfvrsn=9dadbbc0_5" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the</a> WHO expressing this view or warning about the harms or potential harms of lockdown measures, including a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/speeches/item/russian-federation-s-international-legal-forum-the-rule-of-corona" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">speech</a>&nbsp;the director-general gave in April 2020 that reminded nations that “there is a need to respect human rights and dignity” and that the &#8220;restrictive measures governments are implementing are already having a massive impact on livelihoods.&#8221;</p>



<p>&#8220;Lockdowns are a blunt instrument that have taken a heavy toll in many countries,&#8221; the WHO director-general similarly <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/speeches/item/who-director-general-s-opening-remarks-at-the-media-briefing-on-covid-19---4-september-2020" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> in September 2020. &#8220;With the right mix of targeted and tailored measures, further national lockdowns can be avoided.&#8221;</p>



<p>Van Kerkhove also cited a&nbsp;<a href="https://x.com/WHO/status/1317156172353441793" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Q&amp;A video</a>&nbsp;from the WHO that Van Kerkhove appeared in and was shared on social media in October 2020.</p>



<p>Bhattacharya&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://x.com/DrJBhattacharya/status/2015461295244382356">cited</a>&nbsp;the same video in his X thread, saying, “A WHO epidemiologist lauds lockdowns as a way to ‘stop’ covid outbreaks.”</p>



<p>Van Kerkhove said that was a “deliberate misinterpretation of what was said.” In the clip, speaking for the WHO, she said, &#8220;we haven&#8217;t recommended” lockdowns, adding that “we do recognize that some countries and some areas have had to use what is called so-called lockdown measures because they needed to buy themselves some time.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>“This clip cannot be interpreted as me ‘lauding’ lockdowns,” she said.</p>



<p>Other individuals on social media have&nbsp;<a href="https://x.com/aya_velazquez/status/2015354631887466940" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">highlighted</a>&nbsp;statements from February 2020 by Dr.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.worldhealthsummit.org/speaker/edb71f9f-7037-4f6d-9159-9994b01c8f30" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bruce Aylward</a>, a Canadian physician and epidemiologist who was&nbsp;<a href="https://healthpolicy-watch.news/two-who-officials-dropped-in-may-from-senior-leadership-team-move-into-other-roles/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">then</a>&nbsp;a senior adviser to the WHO director-general, that Bhattacharya&nbsp;<a href="https://perma.cc/BF4M-3UZ7" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reshared</a>&nbsp;on X.</p>



<p>During the press conference for the WHO-China joint mission, Aylward emphasized that what China had done did appear to be working. “What China has demonstrated is, you have to do this,” he said at one point. “If you do it, you can save lives and prevent thousands of cases of what is a very difficult disease.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Van Kerkhove said this was also a case of misinterpretation. “Dr Aylward spoke positively about China’s overall response to COVID-19, and recognized that other countries including Italy were now taking ‘extremely aggressive actions,’” she told us in an email. “Dr Aylward’s comment that ‘you have to do this’ was a reference to the overall ‘aggressive’ or ‘rigorous’ approach that was needed to stop transmission and save lives, not specifically to the role of lockdowns.”</p>



<p>Aylward “did not recommend that countries impose lockdowns,” she added, pointing to earlier comments of his that day, in which he said “it’s important that other countries think about” applying “not necessarily the full lockdowns … but that same rigorous approach.”</p>



<p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.law.georgetown.edu/faculty/lawrence-o-gostin/">Lawrence Gostin</a>, a global health law professor at Georgetown University, told us that it is “certainly true that WHO officials praised China&#8217;s COVID-19 [response], and that was irresponsible.”</p>



<p>But, he added, “we forget how frightening the early days of the COVID-19 pandemic were. We had no vaccines or treatments and the virus was spreading exponentially. In that context, a temporary lockdown was clearly justified to buy time for the development and deployment of vaccines. Lockdowns were also intended to protect overwhelmed hospitals and health workers. It is easy to blame WHO for its proactive response in the midst of a global crisis. But it&#8217;s wrong.”</p>



<p>He said Bhattacharya&#8217;s posts “lack any subtlety or context” and emphasized that the WHO “has no power to order lockdowns &amp; it never did.”</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><em>Editor’s note: FactCheck.org does not accept advertising. We rely on grants and individual donations from people like you. Please consider a donation. Credit card donations may be made through <a href="https://giving.aws.cloud.upenn.edu/?fastStart=simpleForm&amp;program=ANS&amp;fund=602014" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our “Donate” page</a>. If you prefer to give by check, send to: FactCheck.org, Annenberg Public Policy Center, P.O. Box 58100, Philadelphia, PA 19102. </em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/who-didnt-recommend-lockdowns-contrary-to-health-officials-suggestions/">WHO Didn’t Recommend Lockdowns, Contrary to Health Officials&#8217; Suggestions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Manufacturing Construction Spending Declines Under Trump</title>
		<link>https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/manufacturing-construction-spending-declines-under-trump/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eugene Kiely]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 22:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[FactCheck Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured Posts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.factcheck.org/?p=280068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Samsung-720-x-307.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Samsung-720-x-307.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Samsung-720-x-307-340x145.png 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />Spending to build, expand and rehabilitate manufacturing sites in the U.S. has declined since President Donald Trump took office, according to U.S. Census Bureau data. Yet, Trump has repeatedly boasted that “factory construction” is up 41%.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/manufacturing-construction-spending-declines-under-trump/">Manufacturing Construction Spending Declines Under Trump</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Samsung-720-x-307.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Samsung-720-x-307.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Samsung-720-x-307-340x145.png 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />
<p>Spending to build, expand and rehabilitate manufacturing sites in the U.S. has declined since President Donald Trump took office, according to U.S. Census Bureau data. Yet, Trump has repeatedly boasted that “factory construction” is up 41%.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="400" height="267" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Samsung-400-x-267.png" alt="" class="wp-image-280141" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Samsung-400-x-267.png 400w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Samsung-400-x-267-217x145.png 217w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A general view of the Samsung Austin Semiconductor plant on April 16, 2024, in Taylor, Texas, which received CHIPS Act funds. Photo by Brandon Bell/Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Trump <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-press-conference-briefing-room-january-20-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cited the 41% statistic</a> in a White House press conference on Jan. 20 – calling it a “record” increase and suggesting that other presidents cannot compare to this “record.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Investment in American factories is up 41%. That&#8217;s a record. Nobody goes 41% up. You go 2% up, 1% up. You go down by 3%. If Kamala [Harris] got elected, the 41% up would be 41% down,” Trump said at the press conference, referring to the former vice president and Democratic presidential nominee who lost to Trump in the 2024 election.</p>



<p>A day later, in a <a href="https://www.weforum.org/stories/2026/01/davos-2026-special-address-donald-trump-president-united-states-america/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Jan. 21 speech</a> at the World Economic Forum Annual Meeting in Davos, Switzerland, Trump repeated the 41% figure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Factory construction is up by 41%, and that number is really going to skyrocket right now, because that&#8217;s during a process that they&#8217;re putting in to get their approvals and we&#8217;ve given very, very quick, fast approvals,” Trump said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This claim is part of a theme the president <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/articles/2025/10/president-trump-continues-to-drive-an-american-manufacturing-boom/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has emphasized</a> of a &#8220;manufacturing boom&#8221; or &#8220;<a href="https://www.weforum.org/stories/2026/01/davos-2026-special-address-donald-trump-president-united-states-america/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">booming</a>&#8221; economy due to his trade policies.</p>



<p>At our request, the White House sent us a link to the Census Bureau&#8217;s <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/TLMFGCONS" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">manufacturing construction spending data</a> via the Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis&#8217; online database <a href="https://fredhelp.stlouisfed.org/fred/about/about-fred/what-is-fred/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">known as FRED</a>. We provide more about the White House response later, but let&#8217;s focus first on what the data show.</p>



<p>Under President Joe Biden &#8212; who served from Jan. 20, 2021, to Jan. 20, 2025 &#8212; there was a significant increase in manufacturing construction spending in all four years, <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/?g=1Rb7p" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to</a> the Census Bureau’s annual average estimates. After declining 6.9% in 2020 – the last year of Trump’s first term – manufacturing construction spending started to rise in 2021, the data show.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(Technical note: The Census Bureau provides average <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/?g=1RgEY" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">quarterly</a> and <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/?g=1Rb7p" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">annual</a> estimates and <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/?g=1RhZw" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">monthly</a> reports for construction spending, including manufacturing construction spending, based on its monthly <a href="https://www.census.gov/construction/c30/about_the_survey.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Value of Construction Put in Place</a> survey. We use all three in this story.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Initially, the increases during the Biden years were in response to the COVID-19 pandemic, <a href="https://webinars.constructionexec.com/speaker/anirban-basu/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Anirban Basu</a>, chief economist for the Associated Builders and Contractors, an industry trade association, told us in an email.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Supply chain disruptions at the start of the COVID-19 pandemic convinced many producers to reshore capacity, while a sudden and sharp increase in construction materials prices—which rose more than 40% during the early years of the pandemic—also boosted nominal construction spending,” Basu said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Manufacturing construction spending <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/blogs/econographics/the-ira-and-chips-act-are-supercharging-us-manufacturing-construction/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">accelerated</a> after Biden signed legislation in August 2022 designed to encourage private investment in U.S. manufacturing for <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/4346" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">semiconductors</a> and <a href="https://seia.org/news/president-bidens-signature-historic-inflation-reduction-act-secures-americas-position-global/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">clean energy</a>. The bipartisan <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/4346" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CHIPS Act</a>, for example, included $39 billion to help fund semiconductor manufacturing facilities in the U.S., as explained in an <a href="https://crsreports.congress.gov/product/pdf/R/R47523" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">April 2023 report</a> by the Congressional Research Service.</p>



<p>During Biden’s four years, the <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/?g=1Rb7p">annual average rate</a> of manufacturing construction spending jumped more than 200%, from $75.5 billion to $235.6 billion, <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/?g=1Rb7p" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to</a> Census Bureau estimates. Spending surged 62% in a single year – 2023, a year after Biden signed the CHIPS Act.&nbsp;</p>



<div class="embed-container"><iframe src="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/graph-landing.php?g=1RhXD&#038;width=670&#038;height=475" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" style="overflow:hidden;" allowTransparency="true" loading="lazy"></iframe></div><script src="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/assets/research/fred-graph-react/build/embed.min.js" type="text/javascript"></script>



<p>But manufacturing construction spending peaked in the third quarter of 2024 and has been trending down slightly ever since. Census Bureau <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/?g=1R8lH" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">quarterly data</a> show that under Trump, measuring from the last quarter in 2024 through the third quarter in 2025, spending declined 6.7%.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That decline is expected to continue in 2026 and 2027, according to the <a href="https://www.aia.org/resource-center/consensus-construction-forecast/january-2026" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">most recent survey</a> of construction economists that is conducted twice a year by the American Institute of Architects.</p>



<p>“Manufacturing construction spending has seen phenomenal growth in recent years, increasing by over 50% in 2022, another 62% in 2023, and then another 16% in 2024,” the AIA consensus construction forecast published Jan. 15 said. “However, growth paused last year as spending in this category fell about 5% and is projected to decline another 4% this year and 1% in 2027.”</p>



<p>Despite the slight declines, the AIA construction forecast noted that the semiconductor fabrication plants continue to fuel manufacturing construction spending and will do so in the long term. </p>



<p>&#8220;The longer-term prospects look much more promising, as construction starts for manufacturing projects have shot up again,&#8221; the AIA forecast said. &#8220;Since many of these starts are for megaprojects, such as large semiconductor fabrication plants that entail a complex construction process, it may take a while before the activity shows up in the construction spending data.&#8221;</p>



<p>In January, Basu analyzed the Census Bureau’s <a href="https://www.census.gov/construction/c30/pdf/release.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">most recent monthly report</a> for nonresidential construction spending, which showed manufacturing construction spending as of October had <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/?g=1RhZw" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">declined for nine straight months</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“With CHIPS Act-enabled megaprojects winding down and the stiff headwind of trade policy, manufacturing construction spending has fallen by nearly 10% over the past 12 months, accounting for more than the entire decline in private nonresidential spending,” Basu said in<a href="https://www.abc.org/News-Media/News-Releases/abc-nonresidential-construction-spending-remains-stagnant-in-october" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> an ABC press release</a> issued Jan. 21. (By “trade policy,” Basu is referring to the <a href="https://www.abc.org/News-Media/News-Releases/abc-tariffs-push-construction-materials-prices-higher-in-november" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">economic impact of Trump’s tariffs</a> on construction materials.)</p>



<p>On a <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/?g=1RhZw" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">monthly basis</a>, the Census Bureau shows a 7.3% decline in manufacturing construction spending last year under Trump from January through October, the most recent data available. </p>



<div class="embed-container"><iframe src="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/graph-landing.php?g=1RhZw&#038;width=670&#038;height=475" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" style="overflow:hidden;" allowTransparency="true" loading="lazy"></iframe></div><script src="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/assets/research/fred-graph-react/build/embed.min.js" type="text/javascript"></script>



<p>Beginning on Jan. 23, we asked the White House on multiple occasions to provide support for the 41% figure used in Trump&#8217;s Jan. 20 and 21 remarks. After not receiving a response, we sent another email on Feb. 2 after the president wrote an <a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/donald-j-trump-my-tariffs-have-brought-america-back-2248391b" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">opinion piece</a> for the Wall Street Journal on Jan. 30 that said, &#8220;Factory construction is up by 42% since 2022.&#8221; We asked how it arrived at a 42% increase “since 2022.” That evening, the White House sent us a link to the Census Bureau&#8217;s <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/TLMFGCONS">manufacturing construction spending data</a>, saying it compared &#8220;averages of Jan – August 2025 vs 2021-2024 average.&#8221;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s true &#8212; as far as it goes. On an annualized basis, monthly manufacturing construction spending averaged $226.1 billion for January through August &#8212; which is 40% higher than the annual average of $161.1 billion in Biden&#8217;s four years. But Trump wrote that the 42% increase was “since 2022,” not 2021. (We’ve asked the White House for a clarification.)</p>



<p>More importantly, the White House methodology fails to take into account the <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/?g=1Rb7p">212% increase</a> in factory construction spending over Biden&#8217;s four years, which peaked in 2024 at an annual average of $235.6 billion, and how the Biden-era CHIPS Act continues to fuel manufacturing construction spending.</p>



<p>As we noted earlier, Basu attributed the recent decline to Trump&#8217;s tariffs and the slowing &#8212; not the halting &#8212; of construction projects spurred by the CHIPS Act. Asked to elaborate on his analysis, Basu told us that the manufacturing construction spending in 2025 is &#8220;largely due&#8221; to the CHIPS Act.</p>



<p>&#8220;While spending in the segment remains elevated from 2022 levels, that&#8217;s partially due to a precipitous increase in materials prices that occurred in 2022 and 2023 &#8212; these data are in nominal terms &#8212; and largely due to the surge in megaproject activity induced by the CHIPS Act,&#8221; Basu said.</p>



<p>He added that Trump&#8217;s tariffs have helped drive up the costs of fabricated metal &#8212; which has increased manufacturing construction costs. </p>



<p>&#8220;[I]t should be noted&nbsp;that spending in the fabricated metal manufacturing subsegment is up 19% over the past year,&#8221; Basu said. &#8220;Some of the increase can be contributed to tariffs and the resulting increase in demand for domestic production.&#8221; </p>



<p>We should note that even with the recent surge in manufacturing construction spending, there has been a decline in the number of manufacturing jobs. As we <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/01/trumps-numbers-second-term/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reported last month</a>, the economy lost 63,000 <a href="https://data.bls.gov/timeseries/CES3000000001" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">manufacturing jobs</a> in Trump’s first 11 months. That followed a loss of 98,000 in the preceding 11 months, according to the Bureau of Labor Statistics.</p>



<p>Shortly before Biden left office, Manufacturing Today, a trade magazine, <a href="https://manufacturing-today.com/news/us-factory-construction-boom-struggles-to-deliver-immediate-jobs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote</a> in <a href="https://manufacturing-today.com/news/us-factory-construction-boom-struggles-to-deliver-immediate-jobs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">December 2024</a> that manufacturing jobs were slow to materialize despite Biden’s incentives to spur manufacturing construction. But the magazine predicted the jobs “will materialize in the future.”</p>



<p>“Unlike traditional industrial projects, today’s semiconductor and clean energy facilities require longer timelines,” the article said. “Factories of this scale can take two to three years to complete, with even longer delays for more complex facilities, such as semiconductor plants. This extended timeline means the full benefits will not be realized for several more years.”</p>



<p>Basu agreed that CHIPS-related spending will result in an overall increase in U.S. manufacturing jobs – but cautioned that the impact of Trump’s tariffs could offset those gains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The massive facilities incentivized by the CHIPS Act will employ thousands of people,” Basu told us. “That said, all else is not equal, and recent trade policy and the effects on manufacturing input prices have put downward pressure on the industry’s employment.” (<a href="https://www.bls.gov/k12/productivity-101/content/what-is-productivity/what-are-inputs.htm">Input prices</a> are costs of materials and other resources manufacturers need to produce goods, with some of those materials being imported.)</p>



<p>Others are bullish that Trump’s trade policies will encourage more manufacturers to expand in the U.S.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In April, when Trump <a href="https://perma.cc/GL6U-5QY3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a> higher tariffs on nearly all foreign imports, Morgan Stanley analyst Chris Snyder <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/04/05/trump-says-tariffs-will-accelerate-reshoring-but-experts-say-its-not-that-easy.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">called</a> tariffs “a positive catalyst&#8221; for relocating manufacturing to the U.S. More recently, Snyder <a href="https://www.morganstanley.com/insights/podcasts/thoughts-on-the-market/us-manufacturing-transformation-2026" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> in a podcast last month that the tariffs have changed the &#8220;supply chain cost calculation&#8221; and will result in new U.S. factories.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&#8220;What we&#8217;re seeing is the cost of imports have gone higher with tariffs, and now it&#8217;s more economically advisable for these companies to make the product in the United States,&#8221; Snyder said. &#8220;And if that&#8217;s the case, that means that when they need a new factory, it&#8217;s going to come to the United States. They might not need a factory now, but when they do, the U.S. is at least incrementally better positioned to get that factory.&#8221;</p>



<p>In a January news article, the Wall Street Journal <a href="https://www.wsj.com/economy/u-s-manufacturing-is-in-retreat-and-trumps-tariffs-arent-helping-d2af4316?st=5tdeYf&amp;reflink=article_copyURL_share" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote</a> that Trump&#8217;s tariffs &#8220;haven&#8217;t worked, so far.&#8221; The article said tariffs have increased manufacturers&#8217; costs for foreign parts, adding that the &#8220;White House’s stop-and-start&#8221; tariff policy announcements have &#8220;also led to what many executives view as a lost year for investment.&#8221;</p>



<p>In a <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/elections/trump-isnt-certain-his-economic-policies-will-translate-to-midterm-wins-455e0d46?st=68swNa&amp;reflink=article_copyURL_share" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">December interview</a> with the Wall Street Journal, Trump cited &#8212; <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2025/05/trumps-growing-exaggeration-of-u-s-investments/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">as he often does</a> &#8212; the value of investments that he says his administration has secured to date. (As <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2025/12/factchecking-trumps-economic-speech/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">we&#8217;ve written</a>, he has exaggerated pledges to invest made by various companies and countries that may or may not materialize, experts say.) But he couldn&#8217;t say if the investments would show results in time for the midterm elections, when the Republican Party is in <a href="https://apnews.com/article/house-control-congress-trump-2026-elections-434e7e16a5d70ce44a3f26e316bf251e" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">jeopardy</a> of losing its slim majority in the House. “I can’t tell you. I don’t know when all of this money is going to kick in,” the president told the Journal, adding that it may happen in the second quarter of this year.</p>



<p>What will happen in the coming months and years remains to be seen. But what we can say is that factory construction so far has declined under Trump and his claim that it has increased 41% depends on a spending surge that occurred under Biden.&nbsp;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><em>Editor’s note: FactCheck.org does not accept advertising. We rely on grants and individual donations from people like you. Please consider a donation. Credit card donations may be made through <a href="https://giving.aws.cloud.upenn.edu/?fastStart=simpleForm&amp;program=ANS&amp;fund=602014" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our “Donate” page</a>. If you prefer to give by check, send to: FactCheck.org, Annenberg Public Policy Center, P.O. Box 58100, Philadelphia, PA 19102. </em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/manufacturing-construction-spending-declines-under-trump/">Manufacturing Construction Spending Declines Under Trump</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ICE Officers and Bonuses</title>
		<link>https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/ice-officers-and-bonuses/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sanjana Juvvadi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ask FactCheck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Debunking Viral Claims]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.factcheck.org/?p=279939</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/ICE-Arrest-720-x-307.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/ICE-Arrest-720-x-307.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/ICE-Arrest-720-x-307-340x145.png 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />Q:&#160;Is it true that ICE agents are financially rewarded for the number of people taken into custody?</p>
<p>A: The Department of Homeland Security has said there is no such policy, and an immigration think tank told us it is unaware of any payments per arrest. The Wall Street Journal reported that agents &#8220;are rewarded for making arrests&#8221; but didn&#8217;t say how they are rewarded. Immigration and Customs Enforcement quickly scrapped a proposed program to pay bonuses to speed up deportations.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/ice-officers-and-bonuses/">ICE Officers and Bonuses</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/ICE-Arrest-720-x-307.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/ICE-Arrest-720-x-307.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/ICE-Arrest-720-x-307-340x145.png 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />
<p><strong>Q:&nbsp;Is it true that ICE agents are financially rewarded for the number of people taken into custody?</strong></p>



<p><strong>A:</strong> <strong>The Department of Homeland Security has said there is no such policy, and an immigration think tank told us it is unaware of any payments per arrest. The Wall Street Journal reported that agents &#8220;are rewarded for making arrests&#8221; but didn&#8217;t say how they are rewarded. Immigration and Customs Enforcement quickly scrapped a proposed program to pay bonuses to speed up deportations. </strong></p>



<span id="more-279939"></span>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>FULL ANSWER</strong></h2>



<p>We&#8217;ve received several questions from readers about whether Immigration and Customs Enforcement agents get a bonus for each person they arrest. One reader asked if agents are paid $1,500 for each immigrant they arrest. Versions of this claim <a href="https://archive.is/5eQY5" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">have circulated</a> on social media, with <a href="https://archive.ph/8dPzI" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">some posts</a> pointing to a Wall Street Journal article that said ICE officers were &#8220;under pressure&#8221; to meet a daily nationwide arrest goal and were &#8220;rewarded for making arrests.&#8221; Some have interpreted this to mean a financial bonus. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="400" height="267" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/ICE-Arrest-400-x-267.png" alt="" class="wp-image-280111" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/ICE-Arrest-400-x-267.png 400w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/ICE-Arrest-400-x-267-217x145.png 217w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Federal agents arrest a man after stopping and questioning him in the street in Minneapolis on Jan. 14. Photo by Mostafa Bassim/Anadolu via Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The Department of Homeland Security and ICE didn&#8217;t respond to our multiple inquiries asking whether agents receive a bonus payment for each arrest. However, a DHS spokesperson <a href="https://www.snopes.com/news/2026/01/25/ice-arrest-bonuses/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">told</a>&nbsp;Snopes, which wrote about these claims, that &#8220;this policy has never and never was in effect.&#8221;</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.migrationpolicy.org/about/about-migration-policy-institute" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Migration Policy Institute</a>, a nonpartisan think tank, also told us it wasn&#8217;t aware of any per-arrest bonus structure. <a href="https://www.migrationpolicy.org/about/staff/michelle-mittelstadt" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Michelle Mittelstadt</a>, MPI&#8217;s director of communications and public affairs, said, &#8220;We do not believe these claims regarding bonuses for arrests are accurate. ICE and its parent agency, DHS, have never indicated that they would set up a bonus payment structure rewarding personnel per arrest.&#8221;</p>



<p>In August, the New York Times reported on an ICE proposal to pay bonuses for quicker deportations — but it was canceled before it started and didn&#8217;t pertain to arrests.<strong>&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/05/us/politics/ice-bonuses-immigrants-deportations.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">According</a>&nbsp;to the Times, an internal ICE email proposed &#8220;cash bonuses to agents for deporting people quickly, an incentive meant to motivate the staff to speed up President Trump’s mass deportation campaign. Less than four hours later, the agency abruptly canceled what was supposed to be a 30-day pilot program.&#8221;</p>



<p>The Times reported that documents it reviewed called for $100 and $200 bonuses for each immigrant deported within one or two weeks of arrest. But a subsequent email to ICE field offices from Liana J. Castano, an ICE field operations official, told staff to &#8220;PLEASE DISREGARD&#8221; the program, the newspaper reported.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we said, some social media posts about arrest bonuses have pointed to a Jan. 17 Wall Street Journal article.&nbsp;The article about immigration enforcement in Minneapolis&nbsp;<a href="https://www.wsj.com/us-news/the-standoff-that-has-turned-minnesota-into-a-tinderbox-a3a7e672" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a>&nbsp;that&nbsp;&#8220;officers here and elsewhere are under pressure from daily arrest quotas that leadership has set at 3,000 a day across the country—the number it would take to reach one million arrests in a year, according to ICE officials familiar with the matter. Though ICE has never come close to meeting that daily goal, officers are rewarded for making arrests, even if the immigrants they take in are later released.&#8221;</p>



<p>The administration has publicly acknowledged the 3,000 arrest goal. In May, senior White House adviser Stephen Miller <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MJNXsOqFSZs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> on Fox News that the administration was &#8220;looking to set a goal of a minimum of 3,000 arrests for ICE every day and President Trump is going to keep pushing to get that number up higher each and every single day.&#8221;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s unclear from the Wall Street Journal article how officers are &#8220;rewarded for making arrests&#8221;; the story says nothing about financial payments and doesn&#8217;t offer any more explanation about these rewards. We reached out to the Journal reporters for clarification, but we did not receive a response.</p>



<p>We also didn&#8217;t get a response from DHS or ICE when we asked for comment on the Journal&#8217;s article. </p>



<p>Some, including Minnesota Democratic Sen. Amy Klobuchar, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/amyklobuchar/posts/rewarding-ice-agents-for-arrests-even-if-the-person-is-released-without-charges-/1447187416763420/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">posted</a> that ICE was &#8220;rewarding&#8221; agents, an accurate summary of that article. Others interpreted this as a &#8220;bonus.&#8221; For instance, David J. Bier, the director of immigration studies at the libertarian Cato Institute, <a href="https://archive.is/Krda3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">posted</a> part of the article on X and said, &#8220;ICE agents get bonuses when they make wrongful arrests of US citizens.&#8221; Democratic Sen. Ruben Gallego, of Arizona, <a href="https://archive.is/ri2X1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shared</a> Bier&#8217;s post and said, &#8220;Mistakenly arrest a US citizen? You get a big fat bonus.&#8221;</p>



<p>Beyond these interpretations of the Journal&#8217;s article, we were unable to find evidence regarding claims about per-arrest bonuses. Bier told us the Journal story was the only information he had. Gallego&#8217;s office hasn&#8217;t responded to our inquiry. </p>



<p>Snopes reported that some of its readers appeared to misconstrue the daily 3,000 arrest goal with a &#8220;$3,000 bonus for each arrest,&#8221; as some readers asked about. </p>



<p>According to DHS&nbsp;<a href="https://www.dhs.gov/news/2025/07/29/dhs-launches-defend-homeland-nationwide-recruit-patriots-join-ice-law-enforcement" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">press</a>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ice.gov/news/releases/ice-announces-most-successful-federal-law-enforcement-agency-recruitment-campaign" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">releases</a>, there is a signing bonus of up to $50,000 for new ICE hires.&nbsp;But that&#8217;s a recruitment and retention incentive, and there&#8217;s no indication it is&nbsp;tied to the number of arrests, or deportations for that matter, that an agent performs.</p>



<p>The Republicans&#8217; 2025 budget bill, called the One Big Beautiful Bill Act, <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/119th-congress/house-bill/1/text/eh" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">provided</a> $858 million for the signing bonuses, which, the legislation says, would be for new agents, officers or attorneys who agree to serve for five years or those already working for ICE who agree to stay with the agency for two more years. </p>



<p>Last year, DHS&nbsp;<a href="https://www.dhs.gov/news/2025/09/02/dhs-announces-new-reimbursement-opportunities-state-and-local-law-enforcement" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced</a>&nbsp;incentive funding&nbsp;to state and local law enforcement agencies that partner with ICE to arrest&nbsp;immigrants living in the country illegally. Beginning Oct.&nbsp;1, DHS said that&nbsp;participating agencies would receive&nbsp;reimbursement for trained officers’ salaries and benefits along with quarterly performance-based bonuses. These monetary awards range from $500 to $1,000 per&nbsp;&#8220;eligible task force officer,&#8221;&nbsp;depending on&nbsp;&#8220;the successful location of illegal aliens provided by ICE and overall assistance to further ICE’s mission to Defend the Homeland.&#8221;</p>



<p>But that quarterly bonus program is for state and local police that cooperate with ICE, not a payment per arrest for ICE officers.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><em>Editor’s note: FactCheck.org does not accept advertising. We rely on grants and individual donations from people like you. Please consider a donation. Credit card donations may be made through <a href="https://giving.aws.cloud.upenn.edu/?fastStart=simpleForm&amp;program=ANS&amp;fund=602014" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our “Donate” page</a>. If you prefer to give by check, send to: FactCheck.org, Annenberg Public Policy Center, P.O. Box 58100, Philadelphia, PA 19102. </em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/ice-officers-and-bonuses/">ICE Officers and Bonuses</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump&#8217;s Immediate Speculation on Shootings Bucks Presidential Norms</title>
		<link>https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/trumps-immediate-speculation-on-shootings-bucks-presidential-norms/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Saranac Hale Spencer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 22:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[FactCheck Posts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.factcheck.org/?p=279854</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/TrumpPrettiThumb.jpg" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/TrumpPrettiThumb.jpg 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/TrumpPrettiThumb-340x145.jpg 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />President Donald Trump wasted no time in responding to the deaths of two U.S. citizens last month during protests against an immigration crackdown in Minneapolis. Trump and other top administration officials made inaccurate or unsupported statements within hours of the incidents, a departure from how previous presidents responded in similar situations, experts told us.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/trumps-immediate-speculation-on-shootings-bucks-presidential-norms/">Trump&#8217;s Immediate Speculation on Shootings Bucks Presidential Norms</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/TrumpPrettiThumb.jpg" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/TrumpPrettiThumb.jpg 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/TrumpPrettiThumb-340x145.jpg 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />
<p>President Donald Trump wasted no time in responding to the deaths of two U.S. citizens last month during protests against an immigration crackdown in Minneapolis. Trump and other top administration officials made inaccurate or unsupported statements within hours of the incidents, a departure from how previous presidents responded in similar situations, experts told us.</p>



<p>Hours after an Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent shot and killed <a href="https://apnews.com/article/ice-shooting-minneapolis-minnesota-9aa822670b705c89906f2c699f1d16c5" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Renee Good</a> on Jan. 7, Trump <a href="https://perma.cc/LLH9-3KCY" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">claimed</a> that Good was &#8220;very disorderly, obstructing and resisting, who then violently, willfully, and viciously ran over the ICE Officer, who seems to have shot her in self defense.&#8221; The president included a video clip of the shooting, captured from a distance, but closer video showed the agent wasn&#8217;t run over.</p>



<p>Then, hours after federal agents shot and killed <a href="https://apnews.com/article/immigration-enforcement-minnesota-protester-alex-pretti-15ade7de6e19cb0291734e85dac763dc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Alex Pretti</a> on Jan. 24, Trump <a href="https://perma.cc/2CJH-85YH" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">posted</a> a picture of a handgun and wrote, &#8220;This is the gunman&#8217;s gun, loaded (with two additional full magazines!), and ready to go – What is that all about? Where are the local Police? Why weren’t they allowed to protect ICE Officers? The Mayor and the Governor called them off? It is stated that many of these Police were not allowed to do their job, that ICE had to protect themselves — Not an easy thing to do!&#8221;</p>



<p>Department of Homeland Security officials also made <a href="https://x.com/DHSgov/status/2015115351797780500" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">statements</a> that Pretti &#8220;approached&#8221; officers with a handgun, &#8220;violently resisted&#8221; an attempt to &#8220;disarm&#8221; him, and &#8220;wanted to do maximum damage and massacre law enforcement.&#8221; As we&#8217;ve <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/01/politicians-reach-different-conclusions-on-minnesota-shooting-video/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">explained</a>, in the immediate aftermath of a shooting, it&#8217;s difficult to know exactly what happened, but bystander videos contradicted DHS&#8217; account. They don&#8217;t show Pretti holding the gun or threatening officers with it.</p>



<p>The president, himself, softened his remarks,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/policy/trump-says-administration-is-reviewing-everything-about-minneapolis-shooting-a501f48e?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=AWEtsqdB6uIi_aTjQ7wInLoGsnJByGNVICEFVVP_5ibNcCmPpx_4Zlyi16HynxBxy3M%3D&amp;gaa_ts=6977e434&amp;gaa_sig=Y-3MrAYWdTU51S30o49JRHzlMwf-942u9VeAYLoDLh9pXwwHih3Ix-kkqWAiF8nhKku7U6g-t1BWPYwVU1eitg%3D%3D">saying</a>&nbsp;the next day, &#8220;We&#8217;re reviewing everything and will come out with a determination&#8221; on whether the federal agent&#8217;s actions were justified. And the civil rights division of the Justice Department is now <a href="https://www.npr.org/2026/01/30/nx-s1-5694313/alex-pretti-shooting-doj-civil-rights-investigation" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">investigating</a> the Pretti killing.</p>



<p>All four of the experts we spoke to &#8212; a group that included political communications researchers and historians &#8212; said that Trump&#8217;s remarks following these deaths marked a shift from previous presidents, and even from some of his own rhetoric during his first term.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="400" height="267" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/TrumpPrettiFull.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-280034" style="width:452px;height:auto" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/TrumpPrettiFull.jpg 400w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/TrumpPrettiFull-217x145.jpg 217w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Trump speaks to reporters on Jan. 27 about the shooting of Alex Pretti in Minneapolis. Photo by Kyle Mazza/Anadolu via Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>&#8220;As with so much else Trump, yes &#8212; he&#8217;s extremely different,&#8221; <a href="https://gspm.gwu.edu/matt-dallek" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Matt Dallek</a>, a political historian and professor at George Washington University&#8217;s Graduate School of Political Management, told us in an interview.</p>



<p>&#8220;He&#8217;s much more extreme and far more untethered from facts and the reality on the ground,&#8221; Dallek said, noting that, importantly, it&#8217;s not just the president, but also his officials who have taken this tack.</p>



<p>Others we spoke to made the same point.</p>



<p>&#8220;Without question,&#8221; there has been a shift, <a href="https://commstudies.utexas.edu/faculty/roderick-hart" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Roderick Hart</a>, a professor emeritus of communication at the University of Texas at Austin with expertise in politics and the mass media, told us. &#8220;And it has very little to do with this particular situation in Minneapolis. He&#8217;s&nbsp;a rhetoric-first guy. &#8230; And he&#8217;s chosen his people who have exactly the same instincts,&#8221; Hart said.</p>



<p>Presidents are normally judicious, particularly when reacting to an event, Hart said. But, &#8220;Trump talks before the event is even finished.&#8221;</p>



<p>The Minnesota fatal shootings, however, involved federal agents, while examples from past presidencies concern state or local officers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, former President Barack Obama &#8212; who was in office at a <a href="https://basslab.usc.edu/bass-and-beyond/witnessing-police-brutality/#:~:text=The%20videos%20of%20Grant's%20shooting%20helped%20galvanize,in%202012%20and%20Michael%20Brown%20in%202014." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">moment</a> when the ubiquity of camera phones and the rise of social media <a href="https://bja.ojp.gov/sites/g/files/xyckuh186/files/media/document/public-perceptions-of-the-justifiability-of-police-shootings.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">converged</a> to shine light on the killings of unarmed Black men and boys &#8212; took more time before publicly expressing his thoughts.</p>



<p>One of the first illustrations of this moment didn&#8217;t actually feature an officer, but rather a neighborhood watch volunteer in central Florida, who shot and killed 17-year-old <a href="https://www.britannica.com/event/shooting-of-Trayvon-Martin" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trayvon Martin</a> on Feb. 26, 2012. About a month after that, in response to a reporter&#8217;s question, Obama <a href="https://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/documents/remarks-the-nomination-jim-yong-kim-be-president-the-world-bank-and-exchange-with" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a>, in part, &#8220;Well, I&#8217;m the head of the executive branch, and the attorney general reports to me, so I&#8217;ve got to be careful about my statements to make sure that we&#8217;re not impairing any investigation that&#8217;s taking place right now. But obviously, this is a tragedy. I can only imagine what these parents are going through. And when I think about this boy, I think about my own kids. And I think every parent in America should be able to understand why it is absolutely imperative that we investigate every aspect of this and that everybody pulls together &#8212; federal, state, and local &#8212; to figure out exactly how this tragedy happened.&#8221; </p>



<p>Obama continued: &#8220;But my main message is to the parents of Trayvon Martin. If I had a son, he&#8217;d look like Trayvon. And I think they are right to expect that all of us as Americans are going to take this with the seriousness it deserves and that we&#8217;re going to get to the bottom of exactly what happened.&#8221;</p>



<p>In 2014, a <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0047272721001936#:~:text=Highly%20publicized%20police%20killings%20during,Michael%20Brown%20in%20Ferguson%2C%20Missouri%2C" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">year</a> that saw several high-profile police killings, Obama waited three days to publicly respond to the Aug. 9 <a href="https://www.justice.gov/sites/default/files/opa/press-releases/attachments/2015/03/04/doj_report_on_shooting_of_michael_brown_1.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">death</a> of 18-year-old <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/08/09/nx-s1-5064675/michael-brown-ferguson-killing-10-years" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Michael Brown</a>, who was shot and killed by a local police officer in Ferguson, Missouri, sparking <a href="https://www.ebsco.com/research-starters/political-science/2014-ferguson-unrest" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">widespread</a> <a href="https://nmaahc.si.edu/explore/stories/remembering-ferguson" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">protests</a>.</p>



<p>Then, Obama said in a <a href="https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/realitycheck/the-press-office/2014/08/12/statement-president-passing-michael-brown" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">statement</a>: &#8220;The death of Michael Brown is heartbreaking, and Michelle and I send our deepest condolences to his family and his community at this very difficult time. As Attorney General Holder has indicated, the Department of Justice is investigating the situation along with local officials, and they will continue to direct resources to the case as needed. I know the events of the past few days have prompted strong passions, but as details unfold, I urge everyone in Ferguson, Missouri, and across the country, to remember this young man through reflection and understanding. We should comfort each other and talk with one another in a way that heals, not in a way that wounds. Along with our prayers, that&#8217;s what Michael and his family, and our broader American community, deserve.&#8221;</p>



<p>The former president waited three weeks &#8212; when he was asked about it in an interview &#8212; to comment on the shooting death that year of 12-year-old <a href="https://www.justice.gov/archives/opa/pr/justice-department-announces-closing-investigation-2014-officer-involved-shooting-cleveland" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tamir Rice</a> in Cleveland. In a lengthy answer to a question about how responsible he felt his administration was for addressing police shootings, Obama <a href="https://www.bet.com/article/cqro4z/transcript-bet-s-exclusive-interview-with-president-obama" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a>, &#8220;Well, I think an enormous amount. Not just because, as president, you&#8217;re always responsible for what happens in this country and you&#8217;ve got to be part of the solution, not part of the problem, but because of my particular experiences that I bring to this office.&#8221;</p>



<p>And Obama took more than four months to make remarks on the July 17, 2014, death of Eric Garner in New York &#8212; the former president had waited until a grand jury <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2014/12/03/chokehold-grand-jury/19804577/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">decided</a> not to indict the police officer who had <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/15/nyregion/eric-garner-death-daniel-pantaleo-chokehold.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">choked</a> Garner. In December 2014, Obama <a href="https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/the-press-office/2014/12/03/remarks-president-tribal-nations-conference" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a>, in part, &#8220;My tradition is not to remark on cases where there may still be an investigation. But I want everybody to understand that this week, in the wake of Ferguson, we initiated a Task Force whose job it is to come back to me with specific recommendations about how we strengthen the relationship between law enforcement and communities of color and minority communities that feel that bias is taking place; that we are going to take specific steps to improve the training and the work with State and local governments when it comes to policing in communities of color; that we are going to be scrupulous in investigating cases where we are concerned about the impartiality and accountability that&#8217;s taking place.&#8221;</p>



<p>Before the era of the camera phone, the <a href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/Rodney-King" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rodney King</a> case in 1991 grabbed national attention when a man in a nearby apartment videotaped Los Angeles police beating King during a traffic stop.</p>



<p>Then-President George H.W. Bush waited almost three weeks before commenting. Then, in a prepared statement on March 21, 1991, he <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/PPP-1991-book1/html/PPP-1991-book1-doc-pg295.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a>, in part, &#8220;We&#8217;ve all seen those shocking videotapes and have seen transcripts of the incident in Los Angeles. And without getting into the specifics of the case, those terrible scenes stir us all to demand an end to gratuitous violence and brutality. Law enforcement officials cannot place themselves above the law that they are sworn to defend. This administration will investigate possible breaches of federal law aggressively and will prosecute violators to the full extent of the law. &#8230; I was shocked by what I saw in that tape&#8211;that violence. And to the degree there&#8217;s a federal role here, I&#8217;m confident we will go the extra mile to see that that is fulfilled.&#8221;</p>



<p>Going back even further, to the 1970s, Dallek said, &#8220;Even Nixon&#8217;s comments in the wake of the Kent State killings were far more restrained and measured than anything Trump has offered the American people.&#8221;</p>



<p>On May 4, 1970, the same day that the National Guard shot and killed four students during a protest of the Vietnam War at Kent State University in Ohio, then-President Richard Nixon issued a <a href="https://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/documents/statement-the-deaths-four-students-kent-state-university-kent-ohio" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">statement</a> that said, &#8220;This should remind us all once again that when dissent turns to violence, it invites tragedy. It is my hope that this tragic and unfortunate incident will strengthen the determination of all the Nation&#8217;s campuses&#8211;administrators, faculty, and students alike&#8211;to stand firmly for the right which exists in this country of peaceful dissent and just as strongly against the resort to violence as a means of such expression.&#8221;</p>



<p>When he was asked about the proper role of the National Guard &#8212; which, in this <a href="https://www.kent.edu/may-4-historical-accuracy" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">case</a>, had been called in by the state&#8217;s governor &#8212; at a press conference four days later, Nixon <a href="https://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/documents/the-presidents-news-conference-144" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a>, &#8220;I want to know what the facts are. I have asked for the facts. When I get them, I will have something to say about it. But I do know when you do have a situation of a crowd throwing rocks and the National Guard is called in, that there is always the chance that it will escalate into the kind of a tragedy that happened at Kent State. If there is one thing I am personally committed to, it is this: I saw the pictures of those four youngsters in the Evening Star the day after that tragedy, and I vowed then that we were going to find methods that would be more effective to deal with these problems of violence, methods that would deal with those who would use force and violence and endanger others, but, at the same time, would not take the lives of innocent people.&#8221;</p>



<p>&#8220;There are some echoes, I think,&#8221; Dallek said, comparing Trump&#8217;s recent statements with Nixon&#8217;s. But Nixon was much more measured in the aftermath, Dallek said, adding that &#8220;he never branded [the students] as traitors or domestic terrorists.&#8221; (After the Good killing, DHS Secretary Kristi Noem <a href="https://www.rev.com/transcripts/noem-speaks-on-mn-ice-shooting" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">called</a> Good&#8217;s actions &#8220;domestic terrorism,&#8221; and Noem <a href="https://www.rev.com/transcripts/dhs-press-brirfing-1-24-25" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">used the same phrase</a> to describe Pretti&#8217;s actions.)</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">Minneapolis Cases Involved Federal Agents</h2>



<p>One distinction between these previous examples and the current situation is that agents deployed in Minneapolis are federal, rather than state or local, <a href="https://millercenter.org/experts/barbara-perry" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Barbara Perry</a>, a professor of governance at the University of Virginia&#8217;s <a href="https://millercenter.org/about/who-we-are" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Miller Center</a>, which focuses on the American presidency, told us in an interview.</p>



<p>Since most previous cases of officer-involved shootings implicated state or local police, presidents could distance themselves, she said, and say that the Justice Department would investigate.</p>



<p>&#8220;So they could keep at arms length the legal process while expressing their sorrow,&#8221; Perry said.</p>



<p>Similarly, Guian A. McKee, a professor of public affairs at the Miller Center, told us in an email, &#8220;Trump administration statements about the recent killings in Minneapolis have been immediate, they have been political, and they have had little regard for facts or willingness to wait until evidence is clear.&#8221;</p>



<p>He went on to explain that one reason for this may be that &#8220;the recent killings have been done by federal agents acting as instruments of the president&#8217;s own policies and the tactics chosen to implement them. This has not been the case in most other law enforcement-involved deaths, where the officers were state or local. So the actions and their consequences fall much closer to the president.&#8221;</p>



<p>Near the end of his first term, Trump made conciliatory remarks about a high-profile case that involved local police officers, not federal agents.</p>



<p>Two days after the May 25, 2020, killing of <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/31/us/george-floyd-investigation.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">George Floyd</a>, whose death under the knee of a Minneapolis police officer led to widespread protests, Trump wrote on <a href="https://x.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1265774767493148672?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1265774767493148672%7Ctwgr%5E78f1ad20895f7eb11203918257df148bab7ad2b4%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thetrumparchive.com%2F%3Fsearchbox%3D22georgefloyd22" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Twitter</a>, &#8220;At my request, the FBI and the Department of Justice are already well into an investigation as to the very sad and tragic death in Minnesota of George Floyd.&#8221;</p>



<p>And, two days after that, on May 29, he <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-remarks-roundtable-reopening-economy-coronavirus-may-29-2020/#266" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> at the start of an event for business leaders, &#8220;I want to express our nation&#8217;s deepest condolences and most heartfelt sympathies to the family of George Floyd. A terrible event. Terrible, terrible thing that happened. I&#8217;ve asked that the Department of Justice expedite the federal investigation into his death and do it immediately, do it as quickly as absolutely possible. &#8230; It should never be allowed to happen, a thing like that.&#8221;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><em>Editor’s note: FactCheck.org does not accept advertising. We rely on grants and individual donations from people like you. Please consider a donation. Credit card donations may be made through <a href="https://giving.aws.cloud.upenn.edu/?fastStart=simpleForm&amp;program=ANS&amp;fund=602014" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our “Donate” page</a>. If you prefer to give by check, send to: FactCheck.org, Annenberg Public Policy Center, P.O. Box 58100, Philadelphia, PA 19102. </em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/trumps-immediate-speculation-on-shootings-bucks-presidential-norms/">Trump&#8217;s Immediate Speculation on Shootings Bucks Presidential Norms</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Americans Don&#8217;t Need &#8216;Dramatically&#8217; More Protein, Despite Officials’ Claims</title>
		<link>https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/americans-dont-need-dramatically-more-protein-despite-officials-claims/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Yandell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 21:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[FactCheck Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SciCheck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.factcheck.org/?p=279928</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Food-Pyramid-720-x-307.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Food-Pyramid-720-x-307.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Food-Pyramid-720-x-307-340x145.png 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />In unveiling new dietary guidelines, federal health officials have claimed they are correcting past guidance that created a “generation of kids low in protein” and that Americans should get "dramatically" more of the nutrient. While some individuals may benefit from more protein, Americans are not generally protein-deficient.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/americans-dont-need-dramatically-more-protein-despite-officials-claims/">Americans Don&#8217;t Need &#8216;Dramatically&#8217; More Protein, Despite Officials’ Claims</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Food-Pyramid-720-x-307.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Food-Pyramid-720-x-307.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Food-Pyramid-720-x-307-340x145.png 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />
<p>In unveiling&nbsp;new dietary guidelines, federal health officials have claimed they are correcting past guidance that&nbsp;created a “generation of kids low in protein”&nbsp;and that Americans should get &#8220;dramatically&#8221; more of the nutrient.&nbsp;While&nbsp;some&nbsp;individuals may&nbsp;benefit from&nbsp;more protein,&nbsp;Americans are&nbsp;not generally protein-deficient.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft"><img decoding="async" data-pin-description="RFK Jr. Misleads on Autism Prevalence, Causes - FactCheck.org" data-pin-title="The Facts Behind Claims on Autism, Tylenol and Folate - FactCheck.org" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/SciCHECKsquare_4-161x145.png" alt=""/></figure></div>


<p>In fact,&nbsp;many&nbsp;Americans, including a majority of children, already meet or come near to meeting the lower end of the higher daily protein goals promoted in the new&nbsp;<a href="https://cdn.realfood.gov/DGA.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">guidelines</a>, which range from 1.2 to 1.6 grams per kilogram of body weight per day. There’s some uncertainty about how much protein people should consume for optimal health. Multiple factors affect protein needs, which may be higher for older adults, as well as for people who are building muscle through exercise or actively losing weight.</p>



<p>Despite this nuance, officials portrayed the 2025-2030 Dietary Guidelines for Americans, released Jan. 7, as righting a clear wrong, while misleadingly stating or implying that Americans in general need to eat significantly more protein. The new guidelines include an inverted food pyramid that prominently features a large steak, and the website promoting the guidelines <a href="https://perma.cc/9D7R-ASDQ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">proclaims</a>, &#8220;We are ending the war on protein.&#8221;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="400" height="267" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Food-Pyramid-400-x-267.png" alt="" class="wp-image-280019" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Food-Pyramid-400-x-267.png 400w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Food-Pyramid-400-x-267-217x145.png 217w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A phone shows the new food pyramid. Photo by Smith Collection/Gado/Getty Images</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>“The old guidelines had about half the protein that you need,” Dr. Marty Makary, the Food and Drug Administration commissioner,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DTTjiHWCWMj/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DTTkin-CcgM/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">during</a> a Jan. 9 <a href="https://transcripts.cnn.com/show/sitroom/date/2026-01-09/segment/04" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">appearance</a> on CNN. “Look at the consequence of the old, corrupt food pyramid: a generation of kids low in protein, struggling with muscle mass, weak, having trouble concentrating, addicted to ultraprocessed foods and refined carbohydrates.”</p>



<p>&#8220;The science was clear enough on proteins that we should dramatically increase our input of proteins,” Department of Health and Human Services Secretary Robert F. Kennedy Jr.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/37zoZLUC9_Y" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a>&nbsp;during a Jan. 21 rally.</p>



<p>Nutrition experts we interviewed objected to the idea that Americans in general need to “dramatically increase” protein intake, or that children are broadly deficient. HHS did not reply to an email asking for more information to support these claims.</p>



<p>&#8220;When you look at most intake surveys, most Americans were getting in the range of intakes that is being recommended, close to 1.2&#8221; grams per kilogram of body weight per day,&nbsp;<a href="https://mira.mcmaster.ca/our-faculty/stuart-phillips/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Stuart Phillips</a>, a professor who studies the effects of nutrition and exercise on skeletal muscle at McMaster University in Canada, told us.</p>



<p>For reference, the recommended range would translate to around 108 to 144 grams of protein per day for a 199-pound man or 94 to 125 grams per day for a 172-pound woman, the <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/fastats/body-measurements.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">average weights</a> for U.S. adults. A 3-ounce <a href="https://www.cspi.org/article/how-much-protein-eggs-chicken-beans-or-other-foods" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">serving</a> of chicken breast has 26 grams of protein; a 3-ounce serving of cooked salmon has 19 grams; half a cup of cooked lentils or white beans has 9 grams; and a cup of milk has 8 grams.</p>



<p>Moreover, “probably less than 5% of the U.S. population eat diets that are consistent with the previous dietary guidelines,” <a href="https://hhs.purdue.edu/directory/wayne-campbell/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wayne Campbell</a>, a Purdue University professor who studies nutrients, foods and dietary patterns, told us. “It is an inappropriate attack on past guidelines to say that the guidelines are the reason why everybody eats a poor diet and is not as healthy as they hopefully would be.”</p>



<p>“There is no evidence of widespread protein deficiency in the U.S. population,” Dr.&nbsp;<a href="https://hsph.harvard.edu/profile/frank-b-hu/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Frank B. Hu</a>, a&nbsp;professor of nutrition and epidemiology at Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health, told us.</p>



<p>Previous editions of the dietary guidelines did not give a particular figure for the amount of protein people should eat, experts said. Hu explained that a different group of experts helps set daily recommendations for specific ranges of protein and other nutrients.</p>



<p>“Who is going to track how many grams per kilogram body weight of protein” they are eating? <a href="https://ucanr.edu/people/wendi-gosliner" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wendi Gosliner</a>, who leads research projects at the University of California’s Nutrition Policy Institute, told us, noting that the guidelines are meant to guide federal food programs and nutrition education by providing advice that is &#8220;digestible&#8221; for the general public.</p>



<p>Raising protein intake recommendations requires data showing &#8220;widespread protein inadequacy&#8221; or that there are benefits to eating more protein beyond the minimum, Hu said. “We don’t have any of those data at this point to substantially increase protein intake recommendations&#8221; for the general population, Hu said. He added that an argument could be made for relatively high protein intake for certain segments of the population, including people on weight loss drugs, older adults and people engaged in physical activity that builds muscles.</p>



<p>Some experts are supportive of the protein recommendations in the new guidelines.</p>



<p>Phillips, who was not involved in the guidelines, said that the new range is “more in line with what I would recommend,” agreeing the evidence is particularly strong for certain subgroups and depends on physical activity level. However, he disagreed with the implication that prior guidelines led to widespread deficiency.</p>



<p>Claims that the old food pyramid “produced a ‘generation of children low in protein’ or broadly impaired muscle mass or cognition are not supported by direct evidence,” Phillips told us. “Childhood health challenges are far more plausibly linked to excess energy intake, poor diet quality, physical inactivity, and high consumption of ultra-processed foods than to insufficient protein per se.”</p>



<p>(To be clear, the new food pyramid does not replace the original 1992 food pyramid people may remember, which was&nbsp;<a href="https://www.politifact.com/article/2025/nov/07/food-pyramid-history-my-plate-healthy-diet/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">replaced</a>&nbsp;by another, less hierarchical pyramid in 2005 and then <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20260101004950/https://www.myplate.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MyPlate</a> in 2011.)</p>



<p>“My takeaway from all of it is that we’ve elevated protein in people’s thinking, it&#8217;s front and center, and we gave people very specific goals,”&nbsp;<a href="https://fshn.illinois.edu/directory/dlayman" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Donald Layman</a>, a protein biochemist and professor emeritus at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, told us. “I think we’ve made an enormous step forward in clarity.” Layman, who is also a food company consultant, owns a fat loss company that sells meal replacement shakes, although he told us he has lost money on this latter endeavor.</p>



<p>Layman and nutritional physiologist&nbsp;<a href="https://nutrition.utexas.edu/directory/heather-leidy" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Heather Leidy</a>&nbsp;of the University of Texas at Austin co-authored&nbsp;<a href="https://cdn.realfood.gov/Scientific%20Report%20Appendices.pdf#page=348" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reviews</a>&nbsp;of the effects of the new recommended protein range on weight management and nutrient adequacy for HHS and the U.S. Department of Agriculture, the agencies that produce the guidelines.</p>



<p>Unusually, Layman, Leidy and&nbsp;<a href="https://cdn.realfood.gov/Scientific%20Report.pdf#page=10" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">seven</a>&nbsp;additional scientists were asked to perform these reviews in under three months,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.statnews.com/2026/01/17/new-food-pyramid-behind-the-scenes-dietary-guideline-development/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according</a>&nbsp;to STAT. A 20-person committee of nutrition researchers had previously spent years identifying research questions, reviewing the literature and formulating recommendations. The scientific advisory committee does not write the guidelines, but their conclusions inform them.&nbsp;The guidelines in the past have been <a href="https://www.dietaryguidelines.gov/sites/default/files/2020-12/Dietary_Guidelines_for_Americans_2020-2025.pdf#page=9" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">credited</a> to a list of HHS and USDA staff, although this year&#8217;s guidance <a href="https://cdn.realfood.gov/DGA.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">document</a> does not name authors.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><strong>Muddled Messages on the Role of the Dietary Guidelines</strong></h2>



<p>Makary has&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.rev.com/transcripts/new-white-house-dietary-guidelines">repeatedly</a>&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.thefp.com/p/why-we-threw-out-the-broken-food">said</a>&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://x.com/RapidResponse47/status/2009257110081589453">that</a>&nbsp;the new Dietary Guidelines for Americans increased recommended daily protein intake by “50% to 100%.”</p>



<p>It’s true that the new recommended intake of 1.2 to 1.6 grams per kilogram of body weight per day is 50% to 100% above the&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.health.harvard.edu/nutrition/what-are-rdas-dris-and-dvs">Recommended Dietary Allowance</a>&nbsp;of 0.8 grams per kilogram per day for adults. (Children have somewhat&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://publications.aap.org/aapbooks/monograph/734/chapter/11477417/Protein">higher</a>&nbsp;RDAs, when measured per kilogram of body weight.) These RDAs were established to set baselines for nutrients to prevent deficiency in the vast majority of Americans.</p>



<p>But to be clear, the Dietary Guidelines for Americans do not set RDAs, Campbell explained, which are instead set via a process&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://ods.od.nih.gov/HealthInformation/nutrientrecommendations.aspx">led</a>&nbsp;by the Food and Nutrition Board of the National Academies of Sciences Engineering, and Medicine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The RDA is “not a recommendation for people to purposefully try to eat that amount of protein,” Campbell said, but rather represents an amount people should not fall below. “If you’re eating 1.0 gram per kilo, 1.2 or 1.4 — or even very few people eat 1.6 — then that’s all within a range &#8230; that the 0.8 would support.”</p>



<p>The RDAs, along with other values,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.health.harvard.edu/nutrition/what-are-rdas-dris-and-dvs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">inform</a>&nbsp;the dietary guidelines. However, Campbell said that the guidelines are meant to recommend which food types to eat, not particular nutrient intakes. Researchers do modeling to ensure what they are recommending “meets or moderately exceeds” the nutrient minimums, he said. He was not involved in the current guidelines but served on the scientific advisory committee for the 2015-2020 guidelines.</p>



<p>Campbell said that the current RDA&nbsp;was&nbsp;based on the best&nbsp;evidence&nbsp;available in the early 2000s, when it was last reviewed, and that there&#8217;s &#8220;inconsistent&#8221; evidence since on whether it should be changed. <a href="https://www.nationalacademies.org/units/HMD-FNB-21-P-406" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ann Yaktine</a>, director of the Food and Nutrition Board, told us that protein is among the nutrients set to be updated, although she said she could not predict a timeline. Until that update is complete, she said, the current RDA “will remain,” adding that RDAs and other nutrient-related values inform the dietary guidelines, &#8220;not the reverse.&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><strong>For Most, No &#8216;Dramatic&#8217; Increase in Protein Needed</strong></h2>



<p>Americans mostly exceed the minimal requirement to prevent protein deficiency and, in many cases, even meet the higher goal set in the new Dietary Guidelines for Americans.</p>



<p>“The consensus has not been that there is a dramatic shortage of protein in this country,” Gosliner said, contrary to Kennedy’s claim that Americans need to “dramatically” increase intake.</p>



<p>Using survey&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ars.usda.gov/northeast-area/beltsville-md-bhnrc/beltsville-human-nutrition-research-center/food-surveys-research-group/docs/wweianhanes-overview/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">data</a>&nbsp;on American diets collected by the U.S. government, researchers have estimated that adults on average get&nbsp;<a href="https://kcklatt.substack.com/p/ambiguous-dgas-and-the-ranchers-pyramid" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">near</a>&nbsp;or even slightly&nbsp;<a href="https://perma.cc/6CRH-6SXT" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">above</a>&nbsp;1.2 grams of protein per kilogram of body weight per day &#8212; the bottom of the range now recommended by the dietary guidelines.</p>



<p>“Because the intake of protein is already pretty high, especially animal protein, in the U.S. population, there is no evidence that further increasing protein intake, especially in a major way, will confer significant health benefit,” Hu said.</p>



<p>However, Layman pointed out that there’s variation in how much protein Americans consume. The people who already consume protein within the new recommended range do not need to increase their intake, he said, but some people &#8220;need to dramatically increase&#8221; protein intake.</p>



<p>A 2018&nbsp;<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0002916522029215?via%3Dihub" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">study</a>&nbsp;on protein intakes between 2001 and 2014&nbsp;<a href="https://ajcn.nutrition.org/action/showFullTableHTML?isHtml=true&amp;tableId=t1&amp;pii=S0002-9165%2822%2902921-5" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shows</a>&nbsp;that nonelderly American adult males on average exceeded 1.2 grams per kilogram, but that the average fell to closer to 1.0 as they aged. Women on average got between approximately 1.0 and 1.15 grams per kilogram per day, with amounts also falling with age.</p>



<p>Phillips also said there was room for improvement in protein consumption. “Many Americans meet the RDA only marginally, consume protein in uneven daily patterns, or obtain it largely from low-quality, ultra-processed sources,” he said. However, he added that most Americans “are not protein deficient in the clinical sense.” He cautioned against framing the new recommendations as being driven by deficiency, rather than a way to optimize certain outcomes.</p>



<p>Makary’s claim that prior guidelines led to “a generation of kids low in protein” also overstates the prevalence of protein deficiency in the U.S.</p>



<p>“It’s not like there’s growth stunting on a large scale in the United States because kids are protein deficient,” Phillips said. “It’s disingenuous at best and flat out wrong at worst.”</p>



<p>The 2018 study <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0002916522029215?via%3Dihub#t3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">found</a> that virtually no children age 8 and under ate less than the RDA — the level meant to prevent deficiency in the vast majority of the population. Protein underconsumption did rise with age for minors, with 11% of teenage boys and 23% of teenage girls not meeting the RDA.</p>



<p>Most age groups of children, both male and female, on average exceeded 1.2 grams of protein per kilogram of body weight per day. The exception was adolescent girls, who consumed around 1.1 grams of protein per kilogram daily.</p>



<p>Layman acknowledged a relative lack of research on children and protein intake but also pointed to data showing that adolescents are at risk of not eating enough protein. He also listed the many poor health outcomes for American children today and argued that past guidance had preceded changes in kids&#8217; diets.</p>



<p>&#8220;We know it&#8217;s not working,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We know that after the original guidelines in 1980 that mothers, thinking they were doing the right thing and avoiding cholesterol and saturated fat, switched from having eggs and bacon and milk at breakfast to having Pop-Tarts and Cap&#8217;n Crunch and orange juice.&#8221;</p>



<p>However, Hu detailed a long list of factors other than protein that have led to childhood obesity and other metabolic conditions. These include generally low-quality diets in an obesity-promoting environment, lack of sufficient sleep, inactivity and excessive social media use. “Those are all important drivers of adverse health incomes in children,” he said. “I don’t think protein inadequacy or protein deficiency is a major driver.”</p>



<p>“I wish I could tell you that I thought that &#8230; we just haven’t been feeding kids enough protein, particularly animal protein, and that’s what&#8217;s causing all of the very sad dietary-related challenges that kids are experiencing,” Gosliner said. “From my perspective, there is no evidence of that being true.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">More Protein May Benefit Certain Groups</h2>



<p>A separate question is whether people are generally healthier if they consume&nbsp;substantially more protein than the RDA&#8217;s minimum requirement.</p>



<p>Campbell said that this is a challenging question to answer rigorously. “It’s very difficult to do controlled feeding studies of sufficient length to actually feed people different quantities of protein for months on end to see what happens to them,” he said.</p>



<p>“Where the science is strongest is in showing that certain groups benefit from protein intakes above the RDA,” Phillips said. “Older adults, people engaged in regular resistance or endurance training, individuals recovering from illness or injury, and those intentionally losing weight all appear to achieve better outcomes at intakes closer to 1.2–1.6 g/kg/day. In these contexts, higher protein supports the maintenance of lean mass, functional capacity, and satiety.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, Hu criticized the new guidelines for setting this intake goal broadly, saying that they “are not designed for specific groups of U.S. adults,” but rather the general population.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In a Jan. 7 opinion&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thefp.com/p/why-we-threw-out-the-broken-food" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">article</a>&nbsp;in the Free Press, Makary and an FDA co-author referred specifically to benefits of higher protein intakes for weight loss. “Eating more protein in line with these recommendations consistently improves weight and body composition without harm,&#8221; they wrote.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Layman and Leidy’s&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://cdn.realfood.gov/Scientific%20Report%20Appendices.pdf#page=348">review</a>, used to justify the new guidelines, concluded there was “moderate to strong” evidence that eating protein within the new recommended range promotes weight management.</p>



<p>However,&nbsp;Gosliner said that the review relied on studies of people engaged in weight loss, which are not necessarily generalizable. “They are extrapolating that to the entire population, which doesn’t make sense,” she said.</p>



<p>Layman countered that 75% of Americans are overweight or obese. “Should they basically be guidelines to keep people fat or to get people to ideal weight?” he said. He said that the weight loss studies included in his review in many cases included a maintenance period where people were not restricting calories.</p>



<p>But just because many Americans could benefit from calorie restriction or strength training does not mean that most adults are engaging in these behaviors, other experts said.</p>



<p>A higher protein diet while people are “purposefully energy restricting their diets to lose weight” may help people maintain lean tissue and muscle, Campbell explained. But protein is “not going to be a magical solution for you to actually permanently keep any weight off.”</p>



<p>“Protein without resistance exercise, during weight loss, does very little,” Phillips&nbsp;<a href="https://theconversation.com/2025-was-the-year-protein-jumped-the-shark-272614" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote</a>&nbsp;in a Jan. 6 article on protein hype published in the Conversation. “Exercise is the major driver that helps lean mass retention. Protein is the supporting material.”</p>



<p>Phillips also pointed out that older adults, who can benefit from higher protein intake, make up an increasing share of the population. Protein is &#8220;important,&#8221; he said, &#8220;but it is not a stand-alone solution to metabolic health, childhood development, or healthy aging.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><strong>Overall Diet Also Matters</strong></h2>



<p>The impact of the new dietary guidelines will depend on how people interpret them, some experts said.</p>



<p>Phillips&nbsp;<a href="https://theconversation.com/2025-was-the-year-protein-jumped-the-shark-272614" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote</a>&nbsp;in his Conversation article that 2025 was the year protein “jumped the shark,” explaining a cultural context where it has been “oversold, overvalued and overhyped.” One concern, he told us, is that people will think they are doing “something good for their health&#8221; simply by increasing their protein intake, even if they are already consuming a relatively high amount.</p>



<p>If people eat “substantially” more protein, it could increase the risk of chronic disease, Hu said, explaining that consuming too much protein — and particularly animal protein — is associated with increased risk of chronic disease. “It depends on what comes together with the protein,” he said. For example, he said, people who consume more animal protein also consume more saturated fat, cholesterol and &#8220;other unhealthy components.&#8221;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="400" height="267" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Protein-400-x-267.png" alt="" class="wp-image-280018" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Protein-400-x-267.png 400w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Protein-400-x-267-217x145.png 217w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">A sign advertises protein cold foam at a Starbucks in October 2025. Photo by Smith Collection/Gado/Getty Images</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>“At the end of the day you are eating foods for multiple compounds and nutrients, not just protein,” Campbell said.</p>



<p>The guidelines themselves <a href="https://cdn.realfood.gov/DGA.pdf#page=3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">encourage</a> eating a “variety” of protein foods from animal and plant sources, but the new <a href="https://cdn.realfood.gov/DGA.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">food pyramid</a> prominently features a large steak in the upper left-hand corner, with nuts and legumes further down.</p>



<p>The original committee <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2026/01/17/new-food-pyramid-behind-the-scenes-dietary-guideline-development/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">tasked</a> under the Biden administration with the scientific review for the dietary guidelines&nbsp;<a href="https://www.dietaryguidelines.gov/sites/default/files/2024-12/Part%20E.%20Chapter%201_Overarching%20Advice_FINAL_508.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">recommended</a>&nbsp;an emphasis on consuming more peas, beans and lentils and less red and processed meat. The new dietary guidelines&nbsp;<a href="https://cdn.realfood.gov/Scientific%20Report.pdf#page=4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rejected</a>&nbsp;this advice, with the exception of recommending&nbsp;<a href="https://cdn.realfood.gov/DGA.pdf#page=3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">against</a>&nbsp;processed meat.</p>



<p>If someone replaced refined carbohydrates and sugar in their diet with plant protein, lean protein and eggs, that would be “reasonable,” Hu said. But people who consume a large quantity of animal protein tend to eat significantly less nutrient-dense plant protein sources, he said.</p>



<p>Further, Hu said, supermarkets are now stocked with numerous highly processed protein products.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The new guidelines discourage eating highly processed foods. But Gosliner reiterated that people often do not follow dietary advice. “There’s no reason to think now that if protein is all the rage and people are saying, ‘Eat more protein,’ that you&#8217;re not going to start seeing ice cream with protein powder and cookies with protein powder.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>When asked about the risk of the new guidance feeding into the current trend for promoting highly processed foods as sources of protein, Layman replied, “I think you need to step back and look at the guidelines. What&#8217;s the opening words? Eat real food.”</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><em>Editor’s note: FactCheck.org does not accept advertising. We rely on grants and individual donations from people like you. Please consider a donation. Credit card donations may be made through <a href="https://giving.aws.cloud.upenn.edu/?fastStart=simpleForm&amp;program=ANS&amp;fund=602014" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our “Donate” page</a>. If you prefer to give by check, send to: FactCheck.org, Annenberg Public Policy Center, P.O. Box 58100, Philadelphia, PA 19102. </em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/americans-dont-need-dramatically-more-protein-despite-officials-claims/">Americans Don&#8217;t Need &#8216;Dramatically&#8217; More Protein, Despite Officials’ Claims</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump&#8217;s Selective Comparison Overstates Trade Deficit Decline</title>
		<link>https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/trumps-selective-comparison-overstates-trade-deficit-decline/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[D'Angelo Gore]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[FactCheck Posts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.factcheck.org/?p=279926</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/shipping_containers_port_oakland_getty.jpg" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/shipping_containers_port_oakland_getty.jpg 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/shipping_containers_port_oakland_getty-340x145.jpg 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />Through President Donald Trump's first full 10 months in office, the cumulative U.S. trade deficit in goods and services was down 3.9% from the same period in 2024. His claim that he has "slashed our trade deficit by 77%" appears to compare the monthly trade deficit in January 2025 to the deficit nine months later in October.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/trumps-selective-comparison-overstates-trade-deficit-decline/">Trump&#8217;s Selective Comparison Overstates Trade Deficit Decline</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/shipping_containers_port_oakland_getty.jpg" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/shipping_containers_port_oakland_getty.jpg 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/shipping_containers_port_oakland_getty-340x145.jpg 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />
<p>Through President Donald Trump&#8217;s first full 10 months in office, the cumulative U.S. trade deficit in goods and services was down 3.9% from the same period in 2024. His claim that he has &#8220;slashed our trade deficit by 77%&#8221; appears to compare the monthly trade deficit in January 2025 to the deficit nine months later in October.</p>



<p>Economic experts told us that Trump&#8217;s method is not the preferable way to measure whether the overall trade imbalance with international trading partners is up or down.</p>



<p>&#8220;[L]ooking at changes from one month to another is not a reliable way to assess whether the trade deficit is rising or falling in any meaningful sense,&#8221; <a href="https://gps.ucsd.edu/faculty-directory/kyle-handley.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kyle Handley</a>, a professor of economics at the University of California, San Diego, wrote in an email to us.</p>



<p>He said &#8220;[m]onthly trade balance figures are extremely volatile&#8221; and &#8220;reflect timing of shipments, energy prices, seasonal adjustment noise, and one-off transactions.&#8221; He suggested instead looking at trade trends over several months or, when possible, a full year.</p>



<p>On multiple occasions, however, Trump <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-remarks-board-of-peace-charter-meeting-davos-january-22-2026/#10" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has claimed</a> to have already reduced the trade deficit by a large amount based on just two months of data.</p>



<p>&#8220;We had the largest trade deficit in world history&#8221; under former President Joe Biden, &#8220;but in one year I&#8217;ve slashed our gaping trade deficit by a staggering 77%,” Trump <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-speech-economy-energy-clive-iowa-january-27-2026/#40" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> in Jan. 27 remarks in Iowa, for example.</p>



<p>In a speech at the World Economic Forum on Jan. 21, Trump made it more clear that he was comparing the trade deficit in one month to another, <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-speech-world-economic-forum-davos-january-21-2026/#20" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">saying</a>, &#8220;In one year, I slashed our monthly trade deficit by a staggering 77% — and all of this with no inflation, something everyone said could not be done.&#8221; The president highlighted the drop in the monthly trade deficit again in a Jan. 30 <a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/donald-j-trump-my-tariffs-have-brought-america-back-2248391b?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=AWEtsqdc_nIzzdm8-XD8ppbgp-f47tmUzU9G1jV9lvFyIC70C5eN1p58k-P64U8CiL4%3D&amp;gaa_ts=6980b6d5&amp;gaa_sig=WHwMdzgdl7C6oCqmlL9rEopkL7hublphiqmDH5_m463hFYnvZpXhAdsCdlDIg-Rt98dDA4GoVH5CGxIaj5jJ-A%3D%3D" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Wall Street Journal op-ed</a>, in which he attributed the “astonishing&#8221; decrease to &#8220;the help of tariffs.&#8221;</p>



<p>He even <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-press-conference-briefing-room-january-20-2026/#54" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">predicted</a> in a Jan. 20 White House press conference: &#8220;Next year we won&#8217;t have a trade deficit.&#8221;</p>



<p>To be clear, the Bureau of Labor Statistics <a href="https://www.bls.gov/charts/consumer-price-index/consumer-price-index-by-category-line-chart.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">says</a> that the annual inflation rate has declined from 3% to 2.7% since Trump has been back in office, but it’s not at 0%. So prices are still increasing, just at a slower pace. His emphasis on the monthly trade deficit could also mislead people hearing or reading his remarks.</p>



<p>&#8220;The monthly trade balance has been unusually volatile this year, so I would be cautious about drawing conclusions from the data so far,&#8221; <a href="https://economics.nd.edu/people/robert-johnson/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Robert Johnson</a>, an international economist and associate economics professor at the University of Notre Dame, told us in an email.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="517" height="355" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/shipping_containers_port_oakland_insert-517x355.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-280008" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/shipping_containers_port_oakland_insert-517x355.jpg 517w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/shipping_containers_port_oakland_insert-211x145.jpg 211w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/shipping_containers_port_oakland_insert-768x528.jpg 768w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/shipping_containers_port_oakland_insert-1536x1055.jpg 1536w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/shipping_containers_port_oakland_insert.jpg 2000w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 517px) 100vw, 517px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Shipping containers sit stacked at the Port of Oakland on Jan. 28. Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>In October, U.S. imports of goods and services exceeded exports by about $29.2 billion, the lowest one-month gap in trade since 2009, <a href="https://www.bea.gov/sites/default/files/2026-01/trad-time-series-1125.xlsx" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to</a> the Bureau of Economic Analysis. The October figure was down roughly 77.3% from the $128.8 billion deficit in trade in January last year. That appears to be how Trump calculated the percentage, although the White House did not confirm that when we asked.</p>



<p>But Johnson said that deficits were &#8220;unusually large&#8221; in early 2025, between roughly $120 billion and $136 billion in January, February and March, because U.S. importers stocked up on goods to build their inventories before various tariffs on imported products that Trump had said he planned to implement went into effect. &#8220;Then, after the tariffs were put in place, imports fell back to normal,&#8221; producing smaller monthly deficits in later months.</p>



<p>&#8220;Whether this is a permanent change, or simply reflecting the drawdown in inventories, is too soon to tell,&#8221; Johnson said.</p>



<p>“If you just take the number from a month and you compare it to a number from another month, then you&#8217;re just introducing a lot of all of the noise that&#8217;s in the monthly data,” <a href="https://www.piie.com/experts/senior-research-staff/monica-de-bolle">Monica de Bolle</a>, a senior fellow at the Peterson Institute for International Economics, told us in an interview.</p>



<p>When the monthly trade deficit in goods and services dipped to a 16-year low in October, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/08/business/economy/us-trade-deficit-tariffs.html">some</a> <a href="https://wellsfargo.bluematrix.com/links2/html/59354de6-c24c-48b8-8013-abec14771989" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">economists</a> <a href="https://kpmg.com/us/en/articles/2026/october-2025-international-trade.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">attributed</a> the decline mostly to an increase in U.S. exports of gold and a decrease in imports of pharmaceuticals. Meanwhile, BEA data <a href="https://www.bea.gov/news/2026/us-international-trade-goods-and-services-november-2025">released</a> on Jan. 29 show that the monthly deficit nearly doubled to $56.8 billion in November, which would be a 55.9% drop from January – and would make the 77% figure outdated.</p>



<p>“Large month-to-month swings are common, even in periods with no underlying structural change in trade policy or economic conditions,” Handley, at UC San Diego, said. “For that reason, economists almost never evaluate claims about the ‘trade deficit’ based on comparisons between two individual months.”</p>



<p>He listed other measurements that better assess whether the trade deficit is rising or falling, such as comparing cumulative deficits within a year or year-to-date totals compared with the same period in prior years.</p>



<p>&#8220;On those measures, the claim that the deficit fell sharply in 2025 does not hold up,&#8221; he said.</p>



<p>As we noted, when totaling the trade deficit in each of Trump&#8217;s first full 10 months in office in 2025, from February to November, the <a href="https://www.bea.gov/sites/default/files/2026-01/trad-time-series-1125.xlsx" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">most recent data</a> available, the gap between imports and exports was $710.7 billion – a 3.9% decline from the same period in 2024. On the other hand, the trade deficit including all months from January to November last year was $839.5 billion – up 4.1% from the same 11 months in 2024. </p>



<p>Trump didn&#8217;t take office until Jan. 20, but to reemphasize Johnson&#8217;s point, there was a large trade deficit in the first quarter of 2025 as importers rushed to acquire goods ahead of Trump&#8217;s proposed tariffs.</p>



<p>Trade data for December, and thus all of 2025, should be published on Feb. 19, <a href="https://www.census.gov/foreign-trade/schedule.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to</a> the Census Bureau&#8217;s release schedule. The largest annual U.S. trade deficit in goods and services on record was about $923.7 billion in 2022, during the Biden administration, <a href="https://www.bea.gov/sites/default/files/2026-01/trad-time-series-1125.xlsx" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to</a> BEA data going back to 1960. (The Census Bureau and BEA jointly provide this data.)</p>



<p>Although Trump may view a trade deficit as something negative, <a href="https://www.cato.org/blog/ignore-politicians-trade-deficits-dont-really-matter" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">many</a> <a href="https://www.dallasfed.org/research/economics/2025/0904" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">economists</a> <a href="https://www.cfr.org/backgrounders/us-trade-deficit-how-much-does-it-matter" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">don&#8217;t</a> see it that way.</p>



<p>“A trade deficit sounds bad, but it is neither good nor bad,” Tarek Alexander Hassan, a professor of economics at Boston University, <a href="https://www.bu.edu/articles/2025/trade-deficit-is-a-sign-of-americas-strength/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">wrote</a> in an April 2025 opinion post. “It doesn’t mean the US is losing money. It simply means foreigners are sending the US more goods than the US is sending them.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><strong>Trade Deficit Not Going Away Soon</strong> </h2>



<p>The experts we consulted also told us that the trade deficit is unlikely to be eliminated “next year,” as Trump claimed.</p>



<p>&#8220;It is still the case that the U.S. is not self-sufficient in everything,&#8221; de Bolle, at PIIE, said. &#8220;It may be able to export a lot, but it still imports way more than it exports.&#8221;</p>



<p>She said on a macroeconomic level, the U.S. consumes more than it saves, and &#8220;that is going to translate into a trade deficit most of the time, not a trade surplus.&#8221;</p>



<p>Handley said to proceed “very cautiously” with predictions that the trade deficit will end due to tariffs, as Trump suggested in his <a href="https://rollcall.com/factbase/trump/transcript/donald-trump-press-conference-briefing-room-january-20-2026/#54">Jan. 20 White House</a> remarks.</p>



<p>“Trade deficits reflect saving and investment balances, exchange rates, and macroeconomic conditions, not just tariffs,” Handley said, adding that tariffs could reduce the exports of U.S. manufacturing firms by increasing the cost of goods imported for production, &#8220;and thus the deficit will not improve.&#8221;</p>



<p>He noted that most of the tariffs that Trump imposed in <a href="https://taxfoundation.org/research/all/federal/trump-tariffs-trade-war/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2018 and 2019</a>, during his first presidential term, applied to goods that American manufacturers imported for production purposes. &#8220;When their inputs got more expensive, their exports slowed down as well,&#8221; he said. &#8220;We are seeing those same dynamics right now.&#8221;</p>



<p>The last time that the U.S. did not have an annual trade deficit in goods and services was 1975. That year, there was a trade surplus of $12.4 billion, according to BEA records.</p>



<p>There is also the issue of whether all of Trump&#8217;s second-term tariffs will continue as implemented.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Supreme Court is <a href="https://www.scotusblog.com/2026/01/when-will-we-get-the-tariffs-ruling/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">expected</a> to rule this year on the legality of some Trump tariff policies. That will determine whether the tariffs remain in place in their current form.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><em>Editor’s note: FactCheck.org does not accept advertising. We rely on grants and individual donations from people like you. Please consider a donation. Credit card donations may be made through <a href="https://giving.aws.cloud.upenn.edu/?fastStart=simpleForm&amp;program=ANS&amp;fund=602014" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our “Donate” page</a>. If you prefer to give by check, send to: FactCheck.org, Annenberg Public Policy Center, P.O. Box 58100, Philadelphia, PA 19102. </em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/02/trumps-selective-comparison-overstates-trade-deficit-decline/">Trump&#8217;s Selective Comparison Overstates Trade Deficit Decline</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump&#8217;s Aspirin Use and Doctors&#8217; Recommendations</title>
		<link>https://www.factcheck.org/2026/01/trumps-aspirin-use-and-doctors-recommendations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jessica McDonald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[FactCheck Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SciCheck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.factcheck.org/?p=279826</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Aspirin-720-x-307.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Aspirin-720-x-307.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Aspirin-720-x-307-340x145.png 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />President Donald Trump has said on multiple occasions in recent months that he takes a “large” dose of aspirin to prevent cardiovascular disease. His comments could perpetuate a common misperception, so we wanted to clarify the current science and what the recommendations are.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/01/trumps-aspirin-use-and-doctors-recommendations/">Trump&#8217;s Aspirin Use and Doctors&#8217; Recommendations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Aspirin-720-x-307.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Aspirin-720-x-307.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Aspirin-720-x-307-340x145.png 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />
<p>President Donald Trump has said on multiple occasions in recent months that he takes a “large” dose of aspirin to prevent cardiovascular disease. His comments could perpetuate a common misperception, so we wanted to clarify the current science and what the recommendations are.</p>



<p>Low-dose aspirin is recommended for people who have already experienced a cardiovascular event, but it generally isn’t recommended for those looking to avoid a first heart attack or stroke — and neither is high-dose aspirin.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft"><img decoding="async" data-pin-description="RFK Jr. Misleads on Autism Prevalence, Causes - FactCheck.org" data-pin-title="The Facts Behind Claims on Autism, Tylenol and Folate - FactCheck.org" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/SciCHECKsquare_4-161x145.png" alt=""/></figure></div>


<p>Trump brought up his aspirin use in a Jan. 22&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8xERuYqAbVs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">press gaggle</a>&nbsp;when he was asked by a reporter about some bruising on his hand. “I would say take aspirin if you like your heart. But don&#8217;t take aspirin if you don&#8217;t want to have a little bruising,” he said. “I take the big aspirin. And when you take the big aspirin, they tell you, you bruise.”</p>



<p>The Wall Street Journal&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.wsj.com/us-news/as-signs-of-aging-emerge-trump-responds-with-defiance-769c5dcd">reported</a>&nbsp;in January that Trump’s physician said the president takes 325 milligrams of aspirin a day for “cardiac prevention.” That’s considered a high dose, compared with a typical low, or “baby,” aspirin dose of 81 milligrams.</p>



<p>“They say aspirin is good for thinning out the blood, and I don’t want thick blood pouring through my heart,” Trump told the outlet in the same story, which drew on an October interview with the president. “I want nice, thin blood pouring through my heart.”</p>



<p>Trump, who is 79 years old, similarly&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/11/us/politics/trump-interview-transcript.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">told</a>&nbsp;the New York Times on Jan. 7 that he takes a “large dose” of aspirin because he wants “nice, thin blood going through my heart,” adding that he has taken aspirin for 30 years and has never had a heart attack or been diagnosed with heart disease of any kind.</p>



<p>Trump has expressed some awareness that his aspirin use deviates from the norm, suggesting on various occasions that his doctors have said that <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/donald-trump-addresses-health-hand-bruise-stroke-mri-greenland.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">he is</a>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.wsj.com/us-news/as-signs-of-aging-emerge-trump-responds-with-defiance-769c5dcd" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">taking</a>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/11/us/politics/trump-interview-transcript.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">too much</a>&nbsp;aspirin. It&#8217;s not clear if he knows that even low-dose aspirin is not typically recommended for people who don&#8217;t have cardiovascular disease. In his remarks, he is primarily speaking about his own case and does not appear to be giving advice to others.</p>



<p>Still, because his remarks could reinforce common misunderstandings about aspirin, we wanted to address the topic.</p>



<p>When we inquired, the White House did not clarify what Trump&#8217;s doctors have recommended, but provided a statement attributed to Trump&#8217;s physician, Dr. Sean Barbabella, that said the president takes 325 milligrams of daily aspirin &#8220;to maintain his exceptional cardiovascular health.&#8221; Barbabella added that Trump&#8217;s &#8220;medical evaluations and laboratory results continue to show excellent metabolic health, and have revealed his cardiovascular health puts him 14 years younger than his age. Overall, the President remains in exceptional health and perfectly suited to execute his duties as Commander in Chief.&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">Balancing Risks and Benefits</h2>



<p>Aspirin is&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ahajournals.org/doi/10.1161/cir.0000000000000678" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">thought to</a>&nbsp;<a href="https://med.stanford.edu/news/insights/2019/07/aspirin-for-prevention-a-look-at-the-potential-benefits-and-risks.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">lower</a>&nbsp;cardiovascular risk by reducing blood clotting. By making <a href="https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/body/22879-platelets" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">platelets</a> &#8212;  the cell fragments that are involved in clotting &#8212; less sticky, clots are less likely to form. But for the same reason, aspirin also increases the risk of potentially dangerous bleeding.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While aspirin used to be more widely recommended, as early as 2014 the Food and Drug Administration <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20190429110422/https://www.fda.gov/consumers/consumer-updates/can-aspirin-day-help-prevent-heart-attack" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">concluded</a> that &#8220;the data do not support the use of aspirin as a preventive medication by people who have not had a heart attack, stroke or cardiovascular problems, a use that is called &#8216;primary prevention.'&#8221;</p>



<p>&#8220;In such people,&#8221; the agency explained on its website, &#8220;the benefit has not been established but risks—such as dangerous bleeding into the brain or stomach—are still present.&#8221; The agency also emphasized that people should consult a doctor before starting any daily aspirin regimen.</p>



<p>In subsequent years, additional studies have shown that for many people without cardiovascular disease, the benefits don’t outweigh the risks.</p>



<p>Since 2019, the American College of Cardiology and American Heart Association have&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.ahajournals.org/doi/10.1161/CIR.0000000000000678">said</a>&nbsp;that aspirin “should be used infrequently in the routine primary prevention of [atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease] because of lack of net benefit.”</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="400" height="267" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Aspirin-400-x-267.png" alt="" class="wp-image-279884" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Aspirin-400-x-267.png 400w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Aspirin-400-x-267-217x145.png 217w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Photo by fizkes / stock.adobe.com.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>“Most people without known cardiovascular disease like a prior heart attack, stroke, or blockages in major arteries, do not need aspirin,” Dr.&nbsp;<a href="https://profiles.utsouthwestern.edu/profile/193161/ann-marie-navar.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ann Marie Navar</a>, a preventive cardiologist at the University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, told us. “This will increase their risk of bleeding problems – not just bruising but bleeding in the stomach or gut.”</p>



<p>Instead, she advised, people should avoid smoking, eat a heart-healthy diet, get regular exercise, and focus on lowering their cholesterol and keeping their blood pressure controlled.</p>



<p>She added that bruising is “common” among aspirin users and that mild bruising “is not concerning.”</p>



<p>The details are a little more nuanced in Trump’s case, as his cardiovascular risk is somewhat elevated, but the president is also taking more aspirin than is recommended. Dr.&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.bumc.bu.edu/camed/profile/donald-lloyd-jones/">Donald Lloyd-Jones</a>, chief of preventive medicine at Boston University, told us that given&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.cnn.com/2018/01/17/health/trump-heart-disease-gupta">past reports</a>&nbsp;that Trump has plaque build-up in his coronary arteries, it “may be reasonable” to take low-dose aspirin for cardiac prevention purposes. But, he said, the high dose “is certainly not needed or indicated.”</p>



<p>In 2018, Trump’s physician revealed that the president completed a&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.heart.org/en/health-topics/heart-attack/diagnosing-a-heart-attack/cac-test">coronary artery calcium test</a>&nbsp;&#8212; a scan evaluating the amount of plaque in his arteries &#8212; with a moderately high score of 133. Although common for a man of his age, a&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://medlineplus.gov/ency/article/007344.htm">score</a>&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.mayoclinic.org/tests-procedures/heart-scan/about/pac-20384686">over 100</a>&nbsp;is suggestive of heart disease. Lloyd-Jones said the score “indicates that he has atherosclerotic coronary heart disease and subclinical cardiovascular disease at a moderately advanced state.”</p>



<p>If Trump is unaware of the changing practices around aspirin, he wouldn’t be alone. Last year, a survey conducted by the Annenberg Public Policy Center, our parent organization, found that&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.asc.upenn.edu/news-events/news/nearly-half-adults-mistakenly-think-benefits-daily-aspirin-outweigh-risks">nearly half</a>&nbsp;of U.S. adults mistakenly believe that the benefits of low-dose aspirin for cardiac prevention outweigh the risks.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">What’s Recommended</h2>



<p>For people without cardiovascular disease, daily aspirin is not explicitly recommended for any population for cardiovascular disease prevention.</p>



<p>According to the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ahajournals.org/doi/10.1161/cir.0000000000000678" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2019 guidelines</a>&nbsp;from the American College of Cardiology and American Heart Association, which are the most recent, low-dose aspirin “might be considered” for people 40 to 70 years old who are at higher cardiovascular risk and do not have an increased risk for bleeding. For anyone above the age of 70 or a person of any age who has a higher risk of bleeding, the groups advise against routine aspirin use.</p>



<p>Similarly, the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force, a federally funded panel of independent national experts in disease prevention,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.uspreventiveservicestaskforce.org/uspstf/recommendation/aspirin-to-prevent-cardiovascular-disease-preventive-medication" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">advised</a>&nbsp;<a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2791399" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in a 2022 update</a>&nbsp;against starting low-dose aspirin for primary prevention of cardiovascular disease in people 60 years or older. For adults 40 to 59 years old at elevated risk only, the group said the decision to use aspirin “should be an individual one,” as the net benefit is “small.”</p>



<p>Both guidelines were influenced by&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2791432">three large placebo-controlled trials</a>&nbsp;that were published in 2018, which collectively involved more than 47,000 patients and helped clarify the current harms and benefits of low-dose aspirin in various groups.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(18)31924-X/abstract" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ARRIVE trial</a>, which included men age 55 and older and women 60 and older at average cardiovascular risk, identified no cardiovascular benefit to low-dose aspirin and a small increased risk of gastrointestinal bleeding.</p>



<p>The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/10.1056/NEJMoa1805819" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ASPREE trial</a>, which enrolled people who did not have cardiovascular disease and were mostly 70 years and older, found low-dose aspirin “resulted in a significantly higher risk of major hemorrhage and did not result in a significantly lower risk of cardiovascular disease than placebo.”</p>



<p>The&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/10.1056/NEJMoa1804988">ASCEND study</a>, which evaluated low-dose aspirin use in people 40 years and older with diabetes but no known cardiovascular disease, did identify a reduction in vascular events, but those were “largely counterbalanced,” according to the authors, by an increase in major bleeding events.</p>



<p>Earlier studies had found aspirin was more effective, Lloyd-Jones told us. As he also detailed in a 2022 <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamacardiology/fullarticle/2791724">editorial</a> in JAMA Cardiology, this is likely because in the past, physicians were not very good at controlling blood pressure, cholesterol or other major cardiovascular risk factors. Now, in an era with statins and blood pressure medications, and less smoking, for example, there is less “room” for aspirin to be needed or to help, he said. And because aspirin has retained the same bleeding risk, it has shifted the risk-benefit calculus.</p>



<p>“For patients without ischemic heart disease, there is very clear evidence from randomized controlled trials that aspirin is not associated with a clear benefit (and may be associated with harm from bleeding),” Dr.&nbsp;<a href="https://medicine.duke.edu/profile/william-schuyler-jones" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">William Schuyler Jones</a>, an interventional cardiologist at Duke University, told us in an email, referring to the <a href="https://www.heart.org/en/health-topics/heart-attack/about-heart-attacks/silent-ischemia-and-ischemic-heart-disease" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">type of heart disease</a> that occurs when arteries are narrowed, usually due to plaque build-up.</p>



<p>Still, Navar said that there is a bit of a gray area &#8212; and that many preventive cardiologists do recommend aspirin for people “with evidence of a lot of cholesterol buildup in their heart arteries,” such as those with “very high” coronary artery calcium scores.</p>



<p>Experts emphasized to us that for all the confusion and discussion about the recommendations for those without cardiovascular disease, for those with disease &#8212; such as after a stroke, heart attack or after a stent &#8212; there remains a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.acc.org/Latest-in-Cardiology/Articles/2022/04/27/20/41/New-USPSTF-Recommendation-on-Aspirin-in-CVD" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">strong recommendation</a>&nbsp;to take low-dose aspirin to prevent another event, or what’s called secondary prevention. Some patients, however, may not take aspirin if they are on other blood thinners or anti-platelet medications, Navar said.</p>



<p>A 2021&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMoa2102137">trial</a>, which Jones led, compared high- and low-dose aspirin in patients with established cardiovascular disease. It did not find that the higher dose was more effective. And while it also didn’t find that the higher dose led to more bleeding, patients often preferred to switch to the low-dose regimen.</p>



<p>Jones said patients with cardiovascular disease should take the low dose.</p>



<p>Other trials and observational studies, Navar said, “have shown higher doses of aspirin do increase bleeding risk.”</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><em>Editor’s note: FactCheck.org does not accept advertising. We rely on grants and individual donations from people like you. Please consider a donation. Credit card donations may be made through <a href="https://giving.aws.cloud.upenn.edu/?fastStart=simpleForm&amp;program=ANS&amp;fund=602014" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our “Donate” page</a>. If you prefer to give by check, send to: FactCheck.org, Annenberg Public Policy Center, P.O. Box 58100, Philadelphia, PA 19102. </em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/01/trumps-aspirin-use-and-doctors-recommendations/">Trump&#8217;s Aspirin Use and Doctors&#8217; Recommendations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>As ICE Arrests Increased, a Higher Portion Had No U.S. Criminal Record</title>
		<link>https://www.factcheck.org/2026/01/as-ice-arrests-increased-a-higher-portion-had-no-u-s-criminal-record/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert Farley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[FactCheck Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured Posts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.factcheck.org/?p=279638</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p><img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Trump-WOTW-720-x-307.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Trump-WOTW-720-x-307.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Trump-WOTW-720-x-307-340x145.png 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />While the Trump administration insists that it is targeting the "worst of the worst" in its immigration enforcement, it has not provided information to substantiate that, and the data that is available suggests the claim has become less accurate over time.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/01/as-ice-arrests-increased-a-higher-portion-had-no-u-s-criminal-record/">As ICE Arrests Increased, a Higher Portion Had No U.S. Criminal Record</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="640" height="273" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Trump-WOTW-720-x-307.png" class="attachment-medium_large size-medium_large wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" decoding="async" loading="lazy" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Trump-WOTW-720-x-307.png 720w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Trump-WOTW-720-x-307-340x145.png 340w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />
<p>While the Trump administration insists that it is targeting the &#8220;worst of the worst&#8221; in its immigration enforcement, it has not provided information to substantiate that, and the data that is available suggests the claim has become less accurate over time.</p>



<p>&#8220;The Trump administration has specifically targeted the worst of the worst,&#8221; Department of Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6J0-YouvMGo" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> in a press conference in July. &#8220;The individuals that we are going after are those that are violent criminals, those that are breaking our laws and those that have final removal orders.&#8221;</p>



<p>While the number of monthly Immigration and Customs Enforcement&nbsp;arrests has risen steadily over the first year of Trump&#8217;s second term,&nbsp;the percentage of those arrested who have no criminal convictions or pending charges has also gone up. </p>



<p>Our analysis of ICE arrest data obtained by the <a href="https://deportationdata.org/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Deportation Data Project</a>&nbsp;found a doubling over time of the percentage without criminal records, meaning neither convictions nor charges. In Trump&#8217;s first three months in office, 21.9% of those arrested had no criminal record. The percentage rose to 34.2% in Trump&#8217;s second three months, and then to 40.5% in the three months ending in mid-October.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In January, nearly 43% of those detained had no convictions or charges, according to publicly available <a href="https://www.ice.gov/detain/detention-management" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ICE data</a>.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, the percentage of those arrested by ICE who have criminal convictions &#8212; not merely pending charges &#8212; fell from 44.7% in Trump&#8217;s first three months to 31.8% in the three months ending in mid-October.</p>



<p>Trump administration officials claim most of those without charges in the U.S. have convictions or pending charges in their home country, but DHS has provided no data to back that up.</p>



<p>Moreover, while the administration has long said it is targeting the &#8220;worst of the worst&#8221; criminals, only a small<strong> </strong>fraction of those detained by ICE have been convicted of the type of violent felony offenses often cited by the administration, according to an analysis of leaked ICE data by the libertarian Cato Institute.</p>



<p>&#8220;I think when you listen to senior leaders in the Trump administration, what they&#8217;re saying is that they&#8217;re arresting what they&#8217;re calling the, quote, worst of the worst. They&#8217;re arresting people that they&#8217;re referring to as murderers and rapists,&#8221; <a href="https://graemeblair.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Graeme Blair</a>, associate professor of political science at UCLA and co-director of the Deportation Data Project, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YuHAGJk_-a4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">told</a> KTLA 5 News in July. &#8220;And I think that that just really doesn&#8217;t tell the story of what they&#8217;re doing.&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">The Definition of &#8216;Criminals&#8217;</h2>



<p>President Donald Trump has repeatedly insisted &#8212; as he did in a <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/115958124569932540" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Truth Social pos</a>t on Jan. 25 &#8212; that immigration enforcement efforts are targeted at the &#8220;Tens of Millions of Illegal Alien Criminals [who] poured into our Country, including Hundreds of Thousands of Convicted Murderers, Rapists, Kidnappers, Drug Dealers, and Terrorists.&#8221;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="400" height="267" src="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Trump-WOTW-400-x-267.png" alt="" class="wp-image-279877" srcset="https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Trump-WOTW-400-x-267.png 400w, https://cdn.factcheck.org/UploadedFiles/Trump-WOTW-400-x-267-217x145.png 217w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">During a briefing at the White House on Jan. 20, Trump holds up a mugshot as an example of the so-called &#8220;worst of the worst&#8221; being arrested by ICE. Photo by Saul Loeb/ AFP via Getty Images.</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>In early December, DHS launched what it calls its &#8220;Worst of the Worst&#8221; <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/wow" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">website</a>. The purpose, DHS Assistant Secretary for Public Affairs Tricia McLaughlin <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/dhs-launches-worst-worst-webpage-targeting-alleged-criminal-illegal-immigrants-nationwide" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a>, was &#8220;so every American can see for themselves the criminal illegal aliens that we are arresting, what crimes they committed, and which communities we removed them from.&#8221; The site is filled with examples of immigrants arrested by ICE during the Trump administration who have convictions for serious violent felonies, according to DHS.</p>



<p>Noem insists the administration&#8217;s enforcement efforts are targeting just such criminals.</p>



<p>&#8220;Every single individual [arrested or detained] has committed a crime, but 70% of them have committed or have charges against them on violent crimes and crimes that they are charged with or have been convicted of that have come from other countries,&#8221; Noem said on <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/face-the-nation-full-transcript-01-18-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CBS&#8217; &#8220;Face the Nation&#8221;</a> on Jan. 18.</p>



<p>&#8220;And let&#8217;s remember the true data, the true data, 70%, approximately, it goes anywhere from 60% to 70%, of people that are arrested are criminals, bottom line,&#8221; White House border czar Tom Homan said on <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/meet-the-press/meet-press-january-11-2026-n1313206" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NBC&#8217;s &#8220;Meet the Press&#8221;</a> on Jan. 11.</p>



<p>Later on that same program, Democratic Sen. Chris Murphy disputed those figures. &#8220;I heard him [Homan] say that they are undertaking targeted enforcement actions against criminals. Just not true. The vast majority of people they are rounding up are peaceful immigrants.&#8221;</p>



<p>DHS&#8217; public data does not provide a breakdown of the types of crimes committed by those with criminal convictions, nor of the types of crimes faced by those with pending charges, that would allow the public to assess Noem&#8217;s claim about the percentage detained who have committed violent crimes. (Similarly, the data can&#8217;t answer whether the &#8220;vast majority&#8221; are &#8220;peaceful,&#8221; as Murphy claimed &#8212; though it is accurate that the vast majority have not been convicted of a crime in the U.S.)</p>



<p>&#8220;We have no way of knowing if the worst of the worst are being targeted,” <a href="https://www.migrationpolicy.org/about/staff/colleen-putzel-kavanaugh" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Colleen Putzel-Kavanaugh</a>, an associate policy analyst at the Migration Policy Institute, told us. “The government is not giving us access to that kind of data.”</p>



<p>The administration&#8217;s 70% claim also relies on including those with pending charges as &#8220;criminals.&#8221;</p>



<p>&#8220;A charge is not a conviction,&#8221; <a href="https://www.brennancenter.org/about/leadership/lauren-brooke-eisen" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Lauren-Brooke Eisen</a>, senior director for justice at the Brennan Center for Justice, told us. &#8220;Just because someone is charged with a crime. &#8230; People are innocent until proven guilty.&#8221;</p>



<p>&#8220;Someone with a pending charge who is not convicted is not usually called a &#8216;criminal&#8217; in our criminal system,&#8221; David Hausman, an assistant professor at the University of California, Berkeley School of Law who directs the Deportation Data Project, told us.</p>



<p>According to DHS data, about 29% of those detained by ICE in January had criminal convictions, down from about 54% last February.</p>



<p>The transition toward arresting a higher percentage of immigrants with no criminal record appears to coincide with the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/policy/department-homeland-security-deportation-disfunction-976a0e9b?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=AWEtsqeZjPD-pSiGvKwvpO5vTo8AkwDIAf8Egzmfj2ZlxIvUHkB3qsaGf7NdtSEz7_k%3D&amp;gaa_ts=697912eb&amp;gaa_sig=6ojxKvYEGByDrSsejU-FMutwf__X7vdyhChdFMWVIkus1otD22J9FELbZkdrYJDS5MA7j1D2tHvp9hlwC4z-5w%3D%3D" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reported pressure</a> from Noem and others in the Trump administration to significantly increase the number of immigration arrests.</p>



<p>&#8220;Under President Trump’s leadership, we are looking to set a goal of a minimum of 3,000 arrests for ICE every day and President Trump is going to keep pushing to get that number up higher each and every single day,” senior White House adviser Stephen Miller <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MJNXsOqFSZs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a> on Fox News on May 29.</p>



<p>While the number of arrests has not reached that goal, the number of those in ICE detention has risen by about 80% since May, according to <a href="https://www.ice.gov/detain/detention-management" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">DHS data</a>. (Those in ICE detention include arrests made over an unknown period of time.)</p>



<p>Much of that growth, records indicate, is being driven by the arrest of people without criminal records, at least not in the U.S.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">Convictions or Pending Charges</h2>



<p>In Trump&#8217;s first year, about 36.5% of those arrested by ICE had prior criminal convictions. Another 29.8% faced pending criminal charges. And about a third had neither a conviction nor a pending charge. That&#8217;s according to our analysis of data gathered by the <a href="https://deportationdata.org/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Deportation Data Project</a>, a joint project of the UC Berkeley Law School and UCLA that obtains individual-level arrest data through Freedom of Information Act requests and lawsuits. Our analysis covers the period between Trump&#8217;s inauguration on Jan. 20, 2025, and Oct. 15, the latest data the project was able to obtain.</p>



<p>Together, those with criminal convictions or pending charges represented 66% of arrests, which the administration has rounded up to 70%. But there&#8217;s more context: the trend over time of higher percentages of arrests of people with neither a conviction nor pending charge.</p>



<p>As we said, in the first three months of Trump&#8217;s presidency, about 22% of those arrested by ICE had no criminal record. By the three months ending in mid-October, that had jumped to approximately 40.5%.</p>



<p>ICE&#8217;s <a href="https://www.ice.gov/detain/detention-management" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">public statistics</a> also show that over time, a higher percentage of those being detained have no criminal convictions or pending charges.</p>



<p>Consider, in February 2025, the first full month of Trump&#8217;s second term, about 14.7% of those detained by ICE had no criminal convictions or pending charges. By September, that percentage had shot up to 34.6%, and in January it was 42.7%.</p>



<div style="position: relative; width: 100%; height: 0px; padding: 99.86% 0px 0px; overflow: hidden; will-change: transform;"><iframe loading="lazy" style="position: absolute; width: 100%; height: 100%; top: 0px; left: 0px; border: medium; padding: 0px; margin: 0px;" src="https://e.infogram.com/_/gnXmmDMW64ZHAqCpqYwV?src=embed&amp;embed_type=responsive_iframe" title="ICE Average Monthly Detention Population" allowfullscreen="" allow="fullscreen"></iframe></div>



<p>The number of immigrants detained by ICE who have no convictions or pending charges has soared, from 3,165 in February 2025 to 25,193 in January of this year.</p>



<p>By comparison, just 869 of those detained by ICE in December 2024 (Biden&#8217;s last full month) had no convictions or pending charges. Then, 64% of those detained by ICE had criminal convictions. In January, 2026, it was roughly 29%, according to ICE data.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">Types of Crimes</h2>



<p><a href="https://www.cato.org/people/david-bier" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">David Bier</a>, the director of immigration studies at the Cato Institute, <a href="https://www.cato.org/blog/5-ice-detainees-have-violent-convictions-73-no-convictions" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">analyzed</a> nonpublic data from ICE leaked to Cato, and he found that among those with criminal convictions detained by ICE, 8% were convicted of violent or property crimes (about 5% were violent criminal convictions).</p>



<p>&#8220;And that includes very minor assaults. I mean, not like rape and murder,&#8221; <a href="https://www.cato.org/multimedia/media-highlights-radio/david-j-bier-discusses-president-trumps-war-immigrants-kpfas" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bier said</a> in a radio interview with KPFA on Jan. 22. &#8220;These are someone had an altercation at a bar or things like that, not serious violent criminals who committed murder and rape.&#8221;</p>



<p>Contrary to administration rhetoric about targeting the worst of the worst, Bier described the arrests under Trump as &#8220;indiscriminate.&#8221;</p>



<p>&#8220;They have removed the prioritization that was in place under the Biden administration to go after those violent criminals that they&#8217;re highlighting,&#8221; Bier said. &#8220;They got rid of that policy and replaced it on Day One with a policy of arresting people who are the most convenient to arrest.&#8221;</p>



<p>Cato&#8217;s findings were corroborated by a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2025/12/04/us/ice-arrests-criminal-records-data.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">New York Times analysis</a> of ICE data obtained through the Deportation Data Project. Between the period of Jan. 20 and Oct. 15, the Times found that nationwide, 37% of those arrested in ICE operations had any past criminal conviction. Just 7% had a violent conviction. Another 30% had pending criminal charges, and 33% had no criminal charges.</p>



<p>The disparity was even wider in cities and states that have been targeted for enhanced immigration enforcement. In the four areas analyzed &#8212; Los Angeles, Washington, D.C., Massachusetts and Illinois, the majority of those swept up by ICE had no criminal record (convictions or pending charges). Details on the operations in Minneapolis were not available yet.</p>



<p>The New York Times analysis noted that while only a fraction of those arrested had been convicted of a violent crime, &#8220;The most common non-violent convictions were for driving under the influence and other traffic offenses.&#8221;  </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">Charges in Home Countries?</h2>



<p>Pushing back against reports of higher percentages of ICE arrests of immigrants without criminal records, administration officials have claimed that those people often have convictions or pending charges in their home countries.</p>



<p>Although DHS did not respond to our queries for this story, DHS&#8217; McLaughlin has <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/cecot-statements-60-minutes-01-18-2026/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a>, “Many of the individuals that are counted as ‘non-criminals’ are actually terrorists, human rights abusers, gangsters and more; they just don’t have a rap sheet in the U.S.&#8221;</p>



<p>But DHS does not provide any public data to corroborate how many of those arrested by ICE fit that description, or what charges they face or have been convicted of in their home countries.</p>



<p>It’s part of the lack of transparency that has been a problem with the Trump administration, said Putzel-Kavanaugh of the Migration Policy Institute, adding that whether the U.S. is able to obtain criminal records from an immigrant&#8217;s home country is highly country specific. Some countries are simply more forthcoming about sharing such data.</p>



<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re not aware of data that DHS holds, and certainly it&#8217;s not been provided in the data that they&#8217;ve shared with us about any kind of foreign criminal connections,&#8221; Blair of the Deportation Data Project <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YuHAGJk_-a4" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">said</a>. &#8220;I think that that&#8217;s, frankly, a lot of bluster.&#8221;</p>



<p><em>Correction, Jan. 28: We corrected the date of a quote by Noem, which was in July, and added the full sentence of her remark.</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><em>Editor’s note:&nbsp;FactCheck.org does not accept advertising. We rely on grants and individual donations from people like you. Please consider a donation. Credit card donations may be made through&nbsp;<a href="https://giving.aws.cloud.upenn.edu/?fastStart=simpleForm&amp;program=ANS&amp;fund=602014" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">our “Donate” page</a>. If you prefer to give by check, send to: FactCheck.org, Annenberg Public Policy Center, P.O. Box 58100, Philadelphia, PA 19102.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2026/01/as-ice-arrests-increased-a-higher-portion-had-no-u-s-criminal-record/">As ICE Arrests Increased, a Higher Portion Had No U.S. Criminal Record</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using Disk: Enhanced 

Served from: www.factcheck.org @ 2026-02-17 13:01:44 by W3 Total Cache
-->
